{
  "BT1-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect activates as soon as you target a Digimon and declare an attack\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate in battles against Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If you attacked an opponent's Digimon, it will activate even if the attack is blocked. However, if you attacked the opposing player, it won't activate if blocked and a battle with the opposing player's Digimon occurs.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate in battles when it is blocked by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if it is being given \uff1cPiercing\uff1e by the effect of an Option card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in the breeding areas?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in the breeding areas?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it doesn't specify \"in the breeding area,\" the effect doesn't check the breeding area. Thus, it can't meet the requirements of this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved in the breeding area during the current turn, does that meet the requirements of \"If you've digivolved this turn\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved during the current turn using the effect of [BT1-078 Jagamon], that meet the requirements of \"If you've digivolved this turn\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon's effect to add Tamer cards to my hand that are not red?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when I have 4 or fewer cards in my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The effect states \"in its name\", so it allows cards that are [Agumon]\u00a0in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add Digimon that are not an exact match to [Agumon] but have [Agumon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"Your recycle bin\" is another word for \"your trash\" -- it's where cards go when they're deleted or trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"your recycle bin\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It lasts until the end of the turn you activated it.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How long does the 2000 DP boost from this card's inherited effect last?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the +2000 DP boost ends.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's inherited effect to boost its DP. Later, this digivolution card is trashed. Does the DP boost go away?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If your opponent doesn't announce a block using \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it doesn't activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when attacking an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it does not specify \"for the turn\" it loses the boost as soon as the inherited effect was lost.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If after activating this effect, the Digimon is hit by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e so that it becomes this card again. Does the Digimon keep the boost if it digivolves into a new Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not unless the full effect of \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to redirect the attack is resolved.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent declares \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends their Digimon but cannot resolve the effect of \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Does Biyomon still give +2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't because the effect states it lasts \"for the turn\".\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e. If this Digimon is then removed from my battle area later in the turn, does the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e effect also go away?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon's effect to target itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves, does it retain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When your memory drops to 2 or less, it loses , preventing you from performing the second check.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 3 memory, and use this card's effect to gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and attack my opponent. During the check, [ST2-13 Hammer Spark] is flipped over, and its -2 memory security effect reduces my memory to 1"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3. End of Turn Procedures begin, causing you to lose 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on the opponent's side.\n",
      "question": "Q: I pass turn after using this card's effect to give myself additional memory. How much memory does my opponent have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If your opponent doesn't announce a block using \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it doesn't activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when attacking an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has used an Option card or other effect to give one of their Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect to delete that Digimon? "
    }
  ],
  "BT1-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the security effect didn't activate, the card goes to the trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card performs a security check, flipping over an Option card with a security effect. What happens to the Option card if its effect didn't activate? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. (From Card_Rulings:BT1-021)\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give itself \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e. If it digivolves, does it retain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, after all effects and battles resolve, it becomes your turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, a Digimon with this digivolution card is deleted, and this card's inherited effect moves the memory gauge to 1 on my side. Is it passed to my turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. It only becomes your turn after both the attack and all effects finish resolving.\n",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon with this digivolution card is deleted after blocking an opponent's Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. As a result, I gain 1 memory, moving the memory gauge to 1 on my side. Does my opponent's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It ends as soon as your opponent no longer has any Digimon with no digivolution cards. \n",
      "question": "Q: During my turn, all of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards are deleted. What happens to this card's inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.  \n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If your Digimon has this card's inherited effect attacks, Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and no digivolution cards cannot redirect the attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards\" work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, after all effects and battles resolve, it becomes your turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is deleted during my opponent's turn. Its effect moves the memory gauge to 1 on my side. Is it now my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If you don't trash cards in your hand during effect processing at the time you declare your attack, you can't unsuspend this card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect after I attack with it and resolve all battles and checks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect is voluntary.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this card's effect when I attack with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you don't have 3 or more cards in hand, you can't trash cards in your hand or unsuspend this card with its effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect when I have 2 cards or less in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3. End of Turn Procedures begin, causing you to lose 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on the opponent's side.\n",
      "question": "Q: I pass turn after using this card's effect to give myself additional memory. How much memory does my opponent have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you only gain 1 memory, regardless of how many Digimon your opponent has with no digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to gain 1 memory for each Digimon my opponent has with no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's Japanese name (\u30ed\u30fc\u30c0\u30fc\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) has \"Leomon\" (\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Leomon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards, nothing happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards? "
    }
  ],
  "BT1-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digi-Egg cards aren't Digimon cards, so they can't be played with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digi-Egg in its digivolution cards to my battle area? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a separate Digimon, and enters play unsuspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: I suspend this card as I declare its attack. If I use its effect to play a Digimon card from its digivolution cards, does that Digimon enter play suspended? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a separate Digimon, and doesn't receive any effects that currently apply to the original Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card from its digivolution cards, does that Digimon carry over any effects currently applied to this Digimon? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, does that effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is triggered and activates before 6ther already triggered effects. See more in Effect Resolution\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, when does that effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card. Can it attack this turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has a level 4 or lower Digimon card in its digivolution cards, do I have to activate this card's effect to play it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT1-056 Petermon]'s effect to play this Digimon. Can it attack this turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when I have 4 or fewer cards in my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if multiple Digimon are deleted at the same time, you can only draw 1 card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Two of my opponent's Digimon are deleted simultaneously. Can I draw 2 cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the deletion of Digimon using ShineGreymon's skill is treated as a single instance of deletion by the game. Previously, ShineGreymon's [When Digivolving] effect was treated as multiple instances occurring at separate timings, but this was changed as of December 18, 2020.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT2-041 ShineGreymon]'s [When Digivolving] effect to delete 2 or more of my opponent's Digimon simultaneously. Does this mean I can draw 2 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use an effect to play a Digimon while this Digimon is suspended. Can I trigger \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, moving a Digimon between areas is different from playing it, so you can't draw a card.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my breeding phase, I move a level 3 Digimon from my breeding area to my battle area. Can I draw a card off this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs. After resolving all other effects. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon, then use this Digimon's effect to reduce the opponent's Digimon to 0 DP. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [When Attacking] effects are resolved before blocks are declared, so you can't activate this Digimon's effect after your opponent declares a block.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon to attack, and my opponent uses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block the attack. Can I use this Digimon's effect to reduce the blocking Digimon's DP to 0 and delete it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect has already activated, so the -2000 DP will persist until the end of the turn.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After I use this Digimon's effect to give an opponent's Digimon -2000 DP, my memory drops to 2 or less. Does my opponent's Digimon revert to its original DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"Your recycle bin\" is another word for \"your trash\" -- it's where cards go when they're deleted or trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"your recycle bin\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You can only play 1 copy from either your hand or trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's effect to play a [Tinkermon], can I play 1 each from my hand and trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card. Can it attack this turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3. End of Turn Procedures begin, causing you to lose 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on the opponent's side.\n",
      "question": "Q: I pass turn after using this card's effect to give myself additional memory. How much memory does my opponent have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Because the effect grants +1000 DP for every 3 security cards you have, no DP bonus is granted when you have 2 or fewer security cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 or fewer security cards left. What happens to this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Choose as many Digimon as you can. The only time you can choose 1 Digimon is when your opponent only has 1 Digimon in play.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to only choose 1 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give 1 Digimon -6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It only grants \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, no matter how many security cards you have.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 6 security cards. Does this card's effect give this Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: [When Attacking] happens before \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. So you cannot negate the block, but you can prevent it from suspending itself to block. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent declares a block with one of their Digimon. Can I use this card's inherited effect to suspend that Digimon, negating the block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to add a level 4 Digimon card that isn't green to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have 2 or less memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to add a level 5+ Digimon card that isn't green to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3. End of Turn Procedures begin, causing you to lose 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on the opponent's side.\n",
      "question": "Q: I pass turn after using this card's effect to give myself additional memory. How much memory does my opponent have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you only gain 1 memory, no matter how many suspended Digimon your opponent has.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 4 suspended Digimon. Does this card's inherited effect gain me 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't activate during battles with Security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate during battles with my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates when your opponent's Digimon is attacked and deleted, even if it wasn't the target of attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate during battles where my opponent blocks the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the card text says \"you can,\" so you can choose not to digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal a green level 6 Digimon card with this card's effect, do I have to digivolve into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 2 or more green level 6 Digimon cards with this card's effect. Can I choose which card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: I reveal a level 6 Digimon card that isn't green with this card's effect. Can I digivolve into that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when there are 2 or fewer cards in my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot as [When Attacking] effects trigger before you digivolve into this card.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon to digivolve into a Level 6 Digimon with a [When Attacking] effect, can I use the [When Attacking]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot as Jagamon's effect was lost after digivolving it cannot be activated even though it was triggered. But, you can use Jagamon's effect first and then use [BT5-089 Izzy Izumi & Mimi Tachikawa] even if you digivolve into a level 6 with Jagamon's effect first. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If Jagamon attacks, and [BT5-089 Izzy Izumi & Mimi Tachikawa] is used first and digivolves it. Can I still use Jagamon's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it becomes your opponent's turn after the attack ends.\n",
      "question": "Q: I lose 3 memory from this card's effect, causing the memory gauge to move to 1 or greater on my opponent's side. Does it become my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [End of Attack] effect when I attack with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate it. The effect of [End of Attack] effect can be resolved even if no battle occurs. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My [BT1-081 HerculesKabuterimon] attacks a Digimon and the attack target gets deleted by a card effect before the battle occurs. Does the [End of Attack] still activate even if no battle occurred?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that controls this card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Digimon to suspend with this card's skill?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon that has the effect to suspend 1 of their Digimon on attack, and this card was suspended. Can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Rosemon's effect triggers at the [Reaction] step. (See more in Attack Resolution.)\n",
      "question": "Q: I play [ST3-16 Seven Heavens] to give -10000 DP to the opponent's rested Rosemon. Then my [ST3-11 Seraphimon] attacks player. Both Seraphimon and Rosemon skills trigger at the same time [When Attacking] Seraphimon -4000 DP to Rosemon, killing it. Can Rosemon still rest an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Rosemon's effect triggers at the [Reaction]/[Counter] timing. (See more in Attack Resolution and Attack Resolution/Old.)\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a level 7 Digimon that has [BT3-064 TiaLudomon] in its digivolution cards and uses its effect to \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e my [BT1-082 Rosemon]. Can I still use Rosemon's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] effect activates at the [Counter] timing, and blocking with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e can only be done during the block timing. (See more in Attack Resolution.)\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and is unsuspended when my opponent attacks with a Digimon. Can I suspend this Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e before activating this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and is currently unsuspended when my opponent attacks with a Digimon. If I suspend this Digimon to block the opponent's Digimon, can I activate this card's effect to suspend the \uff1cBlocker\uff1e? (See more in Attack Resolution/Old.)"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can digivolve into this card from a red or blue level 6 Digimon by paying its digivolve cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: How can I digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The chosen Digimon and all Digimon with the same name as that Digimon are deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to choose one of my opponent's Digimon. Is that Digimon deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Just [Greymon]. Only Digimon with names that completely match the specified name are deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: I choose [Greymon] with this card's [When Digivolving] effect while my opponent has a [Greymon]/[MetalGreymon], and [WarGreymon] in play. Are all of them deleted, or just [Greymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The card numbers may be different, but the names match. All of your opponent's [MetalGreymon] cards are deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [ST1-09 MetalGreymon], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], and [BT1-114 MetalGreymon] in play in their battle area. I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to choose [ST1-09 MetalGreymon]. Are all of my opponent's [MetalGreymon] cards deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I attack with this Digimon when it has a level 6 Digimon card in its digivolution cards, do I always have to activate this card's When Attacking effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You have to unsuspend it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to return one of its level 6 digivolution cards to my hand. Can I choose not to unsuspend this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I resolve their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Each card's effect activates individually: \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e gets applied twice, giving your Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have two copies of this card in my battle area, does my Digimon with 4 or more digivolution cards gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e during my turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your Digimon loses \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, and the second check isn't performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, which I use to attack my opponent. The card revealed from the first check has a security effect that reduces my Digimon's digivolution cards to 3 or fewer. Does it still have \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I resolve their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Unless otherwise specified, cards don't lose effects when suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate if it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT3-040 Shakkoumon]'s effect allows it to be played as a Blue Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play [BT3-040 Shakkoumon] does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I resolve their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It allows you to look at all of the cards in your security stack without revealing them to your opponent. You then pick one of those cards, reveal it, and add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's On Play effect says \"Look at your security stack.\" What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Shuffle your deck without triggering \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card from my security stack to my hand that isn't yellow?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even though your security is the same after the effect, it was reduced during the effect. So the \"when your security is reduced\" effect gets triggered.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card from my security stack, and then \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e? Do effects that have \"when your security is reduced\" activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Like Main effects on Option cards, you can activate these effects at any time during your main phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: What timing does [Main] occur at?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's Main effect if I have a level 5 or higher green Digimon in my Breeding Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I resolve their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Like Main effects on Option cards, you can activate these effects at any time during your main phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: What timing does [Main] occur at?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's Main effect if I have a level 5 or higher green Digimon in my Breeding Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Unless otherwise specified, cards don't lose their effects when suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate if it is suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Hatching a Digimon does not count as playing them, so it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my breeding phase, I hatch a level 2 Digimon from my Digi-Egg deck. I then digivolve that Digimon into a level 3 Digimon during my main phase. If I use this card's effect to move that Digimon to my battle area, can I attack with it immediately?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: While it is possible, this can only be done if you have a Level 2 Digimon in your Breeding Area. If you have a Digimon that can be moved out from the Breeding Area it must be moved out. If you have no Digimon in your Breeding Area and cards in your Digi-Egg deck, you must hatch.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to suspend this tamer with its [Main] effect and not use its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When you pass the turn the memory counter is set to 3 and \"end of turn\" effects will now resolve giving your opponent 2 additional memory and moving the memory counter to 5. (See more in End of Turn Procedures)\n",
      "question": "Q: I pass turn after using [BT1-090 Gravity Crush]. How much memory does my opponent have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You have to both draw 2 cards and give a Digimon +2000 DP if possible. However, if one effect cannot be done (you do not have Digimon, or you have no cards in deck) you can still use the other one.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to only trigger \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e or give one of my Digimon +2000 DP? Do I have to do both?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You have to give the Digimon both +2000 DP and \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e if possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to give one of my Digimon only +2000 DP or \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e? Do I have to do both?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has used an Option card or other effect to give one of their Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give one of my unsuspended Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Even if this card's effect is used, nothing happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I use this card's effect on a Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect when my opponent's Digimon has no digivolution cards. If that Digimon later gains digivolution cards, can it attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It has no effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens when I use this card while I have 1 or fewer cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you would draw 1. Cards turned over by the security check are not included in the number of security cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 4 security cards. My opponent attacks me and I flip [BT1-102 Blade of the True] as the security check. Do I draw 2 cards with the [Security] effect because it is still in the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my Digimon digivolves after I use this card, does that Digimon still receive this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. (See more in Effect Resolution#Global Effects)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After activating this card's effect, I use [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect to move a Digimon from my breeding area to my battle area. Does this card's effect also apply to that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs. After resolving all other [When Attacking] and [Reaction]/[Counter] timing effects, the attack ends. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon with a Digimon that's gained the [When Attacking] effect from this card. The [When Attacking] effect reduces my opponent's Digimon to 0 DP, deleting it. What happens next?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [When Attacking] effects are resolved before blocks are declared, so you can't activate this Digimon's effect after your opponent declares a block. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then attack with one of my Digimon, which is blocked by an opponent's Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to delete the blocking Digimon by reducing its DP to zero?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. However, Digimon played that turn without \uff1cRush\uff1e cannot attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then play a Digimon. Does it receive this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use 2 copies of this card. When I attack with a Digimon, can I activate its [When Attacking] effect twice in a single attack, giving an opponent's Digimon -4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still use BanchoStingmon's effect if the attack target's DP decreases before BanchoStingmon's effect activates as long as it was 12000 DP when it was targeted for the attack.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have activated [BT1-104 Golden Ripper] and attack with [BT3-058 BanchoStingmon]. If I attack with this card and use [BT1-104 Golden Ripper]'s effect to decrease the attack of the attack target from 12000 DP to 10000 DP before I use its effect, can I use this card's effect to give it 7000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The DP value printed on a card is its original DP. This card's effect temporarily allows you to treat the DP value printed on an opponent's Digimon as if it were 3000.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"original DP\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when a Digimon's DP becomes 0, it's deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to change the original DP of an opponent's Digimon to 3000. I then use [ST3-11 Seraphimon]'s effect to give an opponent's Digimon 4000 DP. If the opponent's Digimon drops to 0 DP, is it deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, effects that increase or decrease DP work as normal, raising the Digimon's DP to 6000.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect has set a Digimon's original DP to 3000. If [ST1-13 Shadow Wing] is used to give that Digimon +3000 DP, is its DP now 6000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, its original DP becomes 3000. 3000 DP and 1000 DP (from the effect) add up to 4000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect on a Digimon that's already getting +1000 DP from an effect, does its DP become 3000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Even after digivolving, the Digimon's DP is treated as 3000 until the end of the turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon while this card's effect is active. What happens to the Digimon's DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect that was used last takes precedence.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I set a Digimon's original DP with this card, and then use another card to set its original DP again. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect prevents the reduction of DP. But it does not prevent its original DP from being set to another number.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can [BT1-105 Blast Fire] to decrease the DP of a Digimon with \"DP cannot be reduced\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Level 2 Digimon has no DP and so its DP can't be changed and it will still be trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's effect to set my opponent's Digimon's DP to 3000 and it gets \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e and becomes a Level 2 Digimon with no DP. Does this card's effect set the Level 2 Digimon's DP to 3000 and stop it from being trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they continue by checking the card that was added to your security stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. My opponent attacks me with a Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, and flips over this card during the security check. Its \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e activates, adding a card to my empty security stack. Does my opponent continue the security check?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolution costs can't be reduced to less than zero. You can digivolve the card for free, but you can't gain memory with effects that reduce digivolution costs.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a level 6 Digimon with a digivolution cost of 3, and use this card's effect to reduce that cost by 4, to -1. Can I digivolve into that Digimon by gaining a memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Since the card doesn't specify breeding areas, the effect doesn't apply to Digimon there.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does activating this card's effect also reduce the digivolution cost of cards in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: During the turn I used this card, I digivolve a green Level 5 Digimon into a Level 6 Digimon using another card's effect, can I reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As long as you're digivolving from a green Digimon, the effect applies.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: During the same turn I used this card, I digivolve a green Digimon into a non-green Digimon. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if your opponent's Digimon has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it can't be suspended with this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses an Option card or other effect to give one of their Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's security effect to suspend that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can either suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon, regardless of DP, or 2 of your opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less. You can't mix and match. \n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend both 1 of my opponent's Digimon, and 2 of my opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect allows you to pick 1 Digimon and suspend it, regardless of DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less, and no other Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect has no limit to the number of times it can be used. As long as you keep deleting your opponent's Digimon, you can keep using the effect to unsuspend your Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. Can I unsuspend it over and over again every time I use it to delete an opponent's Digimon in battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn't activate in battles with Security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. If it deletes an opponent's Security Digimon in battle, can I unsuspend my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if your Digimon deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives, you can unsuspend it, even if the opposing Digimon had \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. I attack with it, and my opponent blocks it. If my Digimon deletes the opponent's blocking Digimon and survives, can I unsuspend my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can only unsuspend the Digimon with this effect if it deletes the Digimon it's currently attacking by battle. Other Digimon and effects don't count.\n",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. I attack an opponent's Digimon with it, and an effect causes one of my opponent's other Digimon to be deleted during the battle. Do I still get to unsuspend my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-113": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on one of my opponent's Digimon, which they then digivolve. Can it now attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's security effect only affects Digimon. Your opponent's Tamers unsuspend as normal. \n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's security effect also prevent my opponent's suspended Tamers from unsuspending during their unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-114": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have less than 5 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-115": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. This card's [When Attacking] effect doesn't depend upon the color of your Tamers.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Attacking] effect activate when I have a Tamer that isn't blue in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter how many blue Tamers you have in play, the effect only grants +1000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 blue Tamers in play. During my turn, does this card's inherited effect grant +2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot because it was already used. [Once Per Turn] effects are per card.\n",
      "question": "Q: After unsuspending itself with its [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect, I digivolve into a new Digimon and attack with it. The security check reveals a card that \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e it back into [BT1-115 Veedramon]. Can I use the [Once Per Turn] effect of Veedramon again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can use the [Once Per Turn] effect of the new [BT1-115 Veedramon] again. [Once Per Turn] effects are per card.\n",
      "question": "Q: After unsuspending itself with its [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect, it got \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e into a level 3. I evolve it back into [BT1-115 Veedramon]. Can I use its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will a 2 color red card meet the requirements for this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this effect also activate when your own Digimon are suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this effect also activate when this card is trashed by your own effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the tamer card also need [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the effect only reveals 1 card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait do I add it to my hand even without having a 2nd card to add?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If both a Digimon card and tamer card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait are revealed with this effect, must I add both of them to hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I choose not to move all digivolution cards from under this Digimon to under a tamer, will this Digimon still be deleted at the [End of Attack]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, because there is no action being taken if you have no digivolution cards the effect cannot be activated if you have no digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Even without digivolution cards, can I activate the [End of Attack] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the tamer being unsuspended and the tamer being given the digivolution cards be different tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, no matter how many tamers are suspended at the same time you will only get 2000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: When multiple tamers are suspended at the same time, can I get more than 2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, provided memory is on the opponent's side.\n",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-013 BetelGammamon] is in the digivolution cards, does the [All Turns] effect let me attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if this card is added to Kimeramon's digivolution cards with its [When Digivolving] effect it will gain BetelGammamon's \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, but the time to trigger that effect has passed.\n",
      "question": "Q: if BT8-013 BetelGammamon digivolves into [BT8-084 Kimeramon], and Kimeramon places this card into its digivolution cards with its [When Digivolving] effect, does this card's [All Turns] effect allow Kimeramon to attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If there are multiple cards with [Gammamon]\u00a0in their names does the [All Turns] effect give me access to all of their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, inherited effects are not targeted by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [All Turns] effect give me access to inherited effects as well?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Due to this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect. You will have two of [BT8-008 Gammamon]'s \"[Your Turn] [Once Per Turn] When you play a red Tamer, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.\" As such, you will draw 2 cards in total.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon in my battle area, this Digimon has [BT8-008 Gammamon] and another copy of this card in its digivolution cards. If I play a Red Tamer, how many cards do I draw?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: If Jesmon is in the digivolution cards and I control a Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name, does the when digivolving effect give me 4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, however the rule that \"A Digimon cannot attack the turn it was played\" cannot be ignored.\n",
      "question": "Q:  Will the benefits of the [When Digivolving] effect be gained by Digimon newly entering the battle area after the fact?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: The [On Play] effect says: \"Reveal the top 4 cards of your deck. Add 2 cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait among them to your hand.\" and it says: \"you may return 1 [MetalGreymon] from your trash to your hand\", if I have a [Kiriha Aonuma] in play, can I choose which of these actions to perform?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the bonus card you draw for digivolution results in your hand having 7 cards, this effect will not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: For the [When Digivolving] effect is the condition of having 6 or less cards in my hand checked after I draw for digivolution?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the [On Play] effect target opponent's Digimon that have no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I target a Digimon with less/equal digivolution cards than/to this Digimon with the [On Play] effect and later on that Digimon's digivolution cards surpass this Digimon's digivolution cards is it then able to attack and block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if both a level 3 and level 4 are present, please choose to either play both of them or neither of them, you cannot play just one of them.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have both a Level 3 and level 4 Digimon card in this Digimon's digivolution cards, may I choose to play just one of them with the [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I target a level 5 or lower Digimon with the [On Play] effect and later on that Digimon becomes level 6 or higher, does it still have \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the effect only reveals either an option with [Plug-In]\u00a0in its name or a yellow tamer but not both, do I add that card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If both a Plug-in option and yellow tamer are revealed with this effect, must I add both of them to hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, how much you pay to use the option card does not matter, however, a card like [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] modifies its own cost while the card is in you hand, if such a card is used while its cost in you hand is 1 or less this effect will not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the option card is used without paying its cost or if its cost is reduced to below 2 will the inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must use an option card from your hand, or with an effect that says to \"use\" an option, in order to activate the inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I activate the \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect of an option card in my battle area can I activate the inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use an option card that has no target for its effect can I activate the inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect applies no matter which of your Digimon is attacking.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in the digivolution cards of a Digimon with [Shoutmon]\u00a0in its name, and a different Digimon of mine attacks the opponent, will the security Digimon still be reduced by 2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 security when I attack do I apply both parts of the [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It cannot be added to your security stack, so after the option's effect hasresolved, it will be sent to the trash.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent used [BT9-103 Kongou], what happens to the option I use with the[When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be placed in the Battle Area, this card's effect is to place it on top of your security when the option card would be placed in your trash, but if the option card is in your Battle Area at the resolution of the option's effect then it would never be placed in your trash, so it can't be placed in your security either.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With the [When Digivolving] effect if I use an option that says \"Then, place this card in your Battle Area\", what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already been activated. [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] is placed into security after this card is placed in security. So, [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] is the top card.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: With the [When Digivolving] effect of this card I play [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!]. The [Main] effect of [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] chooses to place this card into the security. Will the [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] still be placed into security now that this card is no longer in the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it affects Digimon with either condition.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [Opponent's Turn] effect affect Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e and Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack -X\uff1e\u00a0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e will always apply from the moment digivolution is complete, so activating the [When Digivolving] effect is impossible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has this Digimon, and I digivolve into a Digimon with a [When Digivolving] effect and \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e can I activate the [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers both to \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -X\uff1e .\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e the Digimon will still be treated as having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e .\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e does that mean they cancel each other out and the Digimon will be treated as not having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e\u00a0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes it will fully resolve, however as it will gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e during the effect, it will immediately be affected by this card's effect from that moment onwards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent controls this Digimon and my MetalGreymon digivolves into [BT9-015 MetalGreymon (X Antibody)] will its [When Digivolving] effect fully resolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues because it didn't have \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e when it declared the attack, and the attack on this Digimon won't be canceled.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent attacks this Digimon with a Digimon that doesn't have \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e. It activates a [When Attacking] that gives it \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e afterwards. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon only gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e while meeting certain conditions, such as \"While you have a Tamer in play\", will it be affected by this cards effect while those conditions are not being met?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the [When Attacking] has already activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect stops the opponent from activating [When Attacking] effects, if the Digimon did not have \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e and activated a [When Attacking] effect that also applies \"at the end of turn\", does the \"at the end of turn\" still activate if it gains \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I also add cards to my hand with the [Ancient Plant]/[Carnivorous Plant]\u00a0trait with this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the effect only reveals either a card with [Vegetation]/[Plant]/[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits but not both, do I add that card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If both a card with [Vegetation]/[Plant]/[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits are revealed with this effect, must I add both of them to hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not. The Digimon was suspended by \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e before it was digivolved. So its inherited effect was not active when it was suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is digivolved into a Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e. Does this card's inherited effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Fairy\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b), does it include traits other than [Fairy] (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the opponent attacks while this Digimon itself is suspended, can I change the attack target to this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect is a [Reaction]/[Counter] timing effect, so GrandisKuwagamon's [When Digivolving] effect will always be activated first, and you'll be able to activate this card's effect afterwards.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon attacks and activates a [When Attacking] effect to digivolve it into [BT9-055 GrandisKuwagamon], with the [When Digivolving] effect they change the attack target to one of my suspended Digimon, after that is it possible to change the attack target again to a different suspended Digimon with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend this Digimon itself to activate the [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is the attack declaration that causes your Digimon to be suspended, not \uff1cBlitz\uff1e directly, so the inherited effect cannot activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon attacks and suspends with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, can I activate the inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Fairy\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b), does it include traits other than [Fairy] (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, if this Digimon and my Digimon with [Vegetation]/[Plant]/[Fairy]\u00a0in their traits are deleted at the same time, does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect allow them to activate the [On Deletion] effect being granted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Fairy\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b), does it include traits other than [Fairy] (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to utilize the [When Digivolving] effect to suspend this Digimon itself, so that I gain 2 memory, in order to immediately unsuspend this Digimon and give it \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 suspended Digimon do I get 4000 DP and \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon itself is suspended, do I count it for the [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Fairy\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b), does it include traits other than [Fairy] (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Place them at the bottom of your deck in any order, Please see the official site for details.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the cards that I don't add to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the effect only reveals 1 card that I can add to my hand, do I add it to my hand even without having a 2nd card to add?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the effect reveals 2 cards that can be added to hand, must I add both of them to hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent does not have a target for this card's \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on 1 of your opponent's Digimon, is it still possible to place this card into the digivolution cards of one of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I'm unable to add any of the revealed cards to my hand, am I still able to delete one of my opponent's Digimon with a Play Cost of 4 or less when performing DigiXros with 2 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I am unable to play a Digimon with the [All Turns] effect, is it still possible to add a card from this Digimon's digivolution cards to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your Digimon's  DP is returned to its original value, and on top of that their  DP is increased by 2000 more because of the other part of this card's [When Digivolving] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If because of this card's [When Digivolving] effect my Digimon's DP cannot be reduced, but one of my Digimon already had its  DP reduced earlier, what happens to that Digimon's  DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If neither player controls a tamer to delete with the \"Then\" part of the [When Digivolving] effect, does this Digimon still unsuspend?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: With the \"Then\" part of the [When Digivolving] effect, if only I control a tamer, do I have to delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect is a [Reaction]/[Counter] timing effect, so all of your opponent's [When Attacking] effects will have to activate first, and you'll be able to activate this card's effect afterwards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a level 4 or lower Digimon attacks, can I delete it with this card's effect before it has a chance to activate any [When Attacking] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must have exactly 3 to activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if I have 4 or more digivolution cards, can I activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in the deck, when revealed by [BT5-009 Shoutmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Only if it has 3 digivolution cards, but the check will ignore the [On Play].\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has [BT5-014 OmniShoutmon], does this Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it was after the Digimon was deleted that the trash increased to 10 cards, so the timing does not work.\n",
      "question": "Q: There are 9 cards in my trash, if the Digimon that this card was in the digivolution cards of was deleted in battle and that put the trash to 10 cards, will the inherited effect of \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the effect only reveals either a Digimon card with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0trait or a [Yuu Amano] but not both, do I add that card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If both a Digimon card with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0trait and [Yuu Amano] are revealed with this effect, must I add both of them to hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Bagra Army\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u30d0\u30b0\u30e9\u8ecd), does it include traits other than [Bagra Army] (\u30d0\u30b0\u30e9\u8ecd)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when an opponent triggers 2 effects at the same time that will \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, this effect can activate in response to either of those effect activations, but not both at once, in either case \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e will only add 1 card to their hand, so they will only trash 1 card when this effect is activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: In regards to the [Opponent's Turn] effect, if my opponent attacks with a Digimon and activates 2 [When Attacking] effects that each \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, can I cause them to trash 2 cards in their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they added 2 cards to their hand with their effect, so this effect will cause them to trash 2 cards, in regards to the example given they will end up trashing 4 cards total, 2 from their own effect and 2 from yours.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: In regards to the [Opponent's Turn] effect, when the opponent activates an effect like \"\uff1cDraw 2\uff1e then trash 2\" resulting in a net change of 0 to their hand size, can I activate this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will only trash 1 card.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses a card with \"..\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, ..., \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e\". Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect trash 1 or 2 cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose which draw it triggered against.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses a card with \"..\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, ..., \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e for each of your X\". Can I choose whether my opponent trashes 1 or X cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As the opponent increased their hand by 1 twice, rather than 2 at the same time. They will trash 1.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates [EX4-014 Gaossmon]. Do they trash 1 or 2 cards when I activate this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: When activating this card's effect to digivolve into a Digimon card from the trash, can this card itself be the card I select to digivolve into?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: There are 9 cards in my trash, if this Digimon being deleted puts the trash to10 cards, will the [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: In regards to the [Opponent's Turn] effect, can I also activate this effect in response to my opponents effects that trash my digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, trash as many digivolution cards as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has only 1 digivolution card, when one of my other Digimon with 2 digivolution cards would be affected by an effect such as \"Trash 2 digivolution cards\", can the [Opponent's Turn] effect be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do, trash the total number of digivolution cards that would have been trashed from each of the Digimon that you replaced with this Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a \"trash the bottom digivolution card\" is applied on 2 of my Digimon. Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] so that it trashes only this card's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Just 1, the amount of cards that could be trashed by the effect does not matter, only the amount that would have been trashed as a result of that specific activation.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my other Digimon with only 1 digivolution card would be affected by \"Trash 2 digivolution cards\", I decide to active this Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] effect, how many of this Digimon's digivolution cards do I need to trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do while this Digimon has no digivolution cards, digivolution cards will not be trashed. If there are effects that activate when digivolution cards are trashed, such as \"By trashing a digivolution card,\" (e.g. Costs) the effect will not proceed because digivolution cards were not trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: A \"trash digivolution cards\" effect targets one of my Digimon when this Digimon has 0 digivolution cards. Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. If you can trash the number of digivolution cards specified by the effect from this Digimon, your Digimon with 0 digivolution cards can indeed activate such an effect,\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible for one of my Digimon with 0 digivolution cards to activate an effect that reads \"By trashing X of this Digimon's digivolution cards\" by way of activating this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect and trashing those cards from this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you trash 1 digivolution card for each of your Digimon, you do not have to trash your other Digimon's digivolution cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates a \"Trash the bottom digivolution card of all of your opponent's Digimon\" effect. Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to trash just this 1 Digimon's digivolution cards without trashing my other Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you change the target of the effect and trash 2 from the bottom of this Digimon.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent activates [BT5-088 Sora Takenouchi & Joe Kido], and I choose to activate this card's effect in response. Do I get to choose which of my digivolution cards are trashed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It would trash 1 digivolution card (as much as possible) after redirecting the effect.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has [BT9-109 X Antibody] and my opponent activates [BT5-088 Sora Takenouchi & Joe Kido] and I choose to activate this card's effect in response. How many cards does this Digimon trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It would trash 2 digivolution cards (as much as possible) after redirecting the effect.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my other Digimon has [BT9-109 X Antibody] and my opponent activates [BT5-088 Sora Takenouchi & Joe Kido] targeting that Digimon, and I choose to activate this card's effect in resposne. How many cards does this Digimon trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated the effect chooses which card is trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: When the opponent's security are revealed with this card's effect, who gets to choose which card is trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally when you DigiXros the requirements can only be placed from your hand or battle area, but with this card's effect you can also place requirements from under your tamers as well.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the [Your Turn] effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place requirements from under my other tamers as well? Not just thistamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a tamer in the digivolution cards of a Digimon, can I also place requirements from under that tamer as well?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only targets 1 Digimon. The effect of this card will not trigger when 2 Digimon are played at the same time.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-097 Tidal Wave] to play 2 Digimon with [DigiXros] requirements and I suspend 1 of this card, can I place cards underneath both Digimon for their [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only activate this card's effect when playing exactly 1 Digimon and when that Digimon has [DigiXros] requirements.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 1 Digimon with [DigiXros] requirements and 1 Digimon without [DigiXros] requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally when you DigiXros the requirements can only be placed from your hand or battle area, but with this card's effect you can also place requirements from under your tamers as well.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the [Your Turn] effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place requirements from under my other tamers as well? Not just thistamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a tamer in the digivolution cards of a Digimon, can I also place requirements from under that tamer as well?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only targets 1 Digimon. The effect of this card will not trigger when 2 Digimon are played at the same time.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-097 Tidal Wave] to play 2 Digimon with [DigiXros] requirements and I suspend 1 of this card, can I place cards underneath both Digimon for their [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only activate this card's effect when playing exactly 1 Digimon and when that Digimon has [DigiXros] requirements.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 1 Digimon with [DigiXros] requirements and 1 Digimon without [DigiXros] requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a tamer in the digivolution cards of a Digimon, can I play a [Dorulumon] from under that tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a tamer in the digivolution cards of a Digimon, can I play a [Ballistamon] from under that tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Place them at the bottom of your deck in any order, Please see the official site for detail.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the cards that I don't add to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cards placed by this card will be placed first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my DigiXros Digimon would be played, is it possible to separately place cards into its digivolution cards by both its own DigiXros and this tamer's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cards will return to where they were previously before placing them as digivolution cards.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT8-071 Psychemon] and I attempt to play [BT10-084 Tacimon] while I only have 2 memory. What happens to the digivolution cards placed underneath by this card when Tactimon returns to the hand."
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not as the Digimon card was not in play at the time of placing digivolution cards underneath.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT11-088 Bagramon] in play and I activate this card to place digivolution cards underneath a Digimon. Will the [Opponent's Turn] effect of Bagramon activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's security effect let me play a [Taiki Kudo] revealed from the top of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If among the revealed cards there is no Digimon card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait, may I still play a revealed [Taiki Kudo]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if both a Digimon with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait and [Taiki Kudo] are revealed, please choose to either perform both of those actions or perform neither of them, you cannot perform just one of them.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both a Digimon with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait and [Taiki Kudo], may I choose to just add a Digimon with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait to my hand and not play a revealed Taiki Kudo? Or vice versa?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Kiriha Aonuma] is among the cards revealed by this card's effect, can it be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add 1 card if only 1 card is revealed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect add fewer than 2 cards to my hand if it reveals fewer than 2 cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait trait among the 6 revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. For this card's effect you reveal cards, add 2 cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait trait among them to your hand, then play 1 [Kiriha Aonuma] among them. Therefore, if there are 2 or fewer cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait trait including [Kiriha Aonuma] among the revealed cards, you can't play [Kiriha Aonuma] because you would have to add it to your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there aren't 2 other Digimon cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait trait among the six revealed cards, can I still play [Kiriha Aonuma] from among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you perform any of this effect you must perform as much of it as possible, so if both cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait trait and a [Kiriha Aonuma] are among the 3 cards revealed, you must perform both \"add [...] to your hand\" and \"play 1 [Kiriha Aonuma],\" or you must choose to perform neither.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 6 cards. If both cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait trait and a [Kiriha Aonuma] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only activate the effect that adds the cards to my hand and not play [Kiriha Aonuma], or the other way around?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I don't play a [Pulsemon] from my hand, do I still place this card into the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 security do I apply both parts of the effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, by the time the security effect is activated this card will no longer be counted as part of the security stack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 security when my opponent performs a security check, and this is the revealed card, for this effect do I count as having 3 security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the Digimon suspended by this effect, and the Digimon returned to deck by this effect, be different Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" part of this card's effect still applies whether the target of the option is now a Tamer or a Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this option on a Digimon which is later de-digivolved into a Tamer, will my opponent be able to delete that Tamer with an effect on their turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, a card being revealed from the top of the deck does not count as being in the deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is revealed from the top of the deck and trashed from among those revealed cards, do I add this card to my hand with its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Because [Jesmon GX]'s [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] effects cannot be activated due to your opponent's [BT10-042 Venusmon], even this card can't activate those effects in these circumstances.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a [Jesmon GX] that has \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e in play, while my opponent has a [BT10-042 Venusmon] in play. If I use this card and target my [Jesmon GX], can this card's effect activate [Jesmon GX]'s [When Digivolving] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, using this option does not \"place\" a card in the Battle Area, so [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] does not gain any memory when this card is used.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does using this option trigger [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6]'s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when this card is used, it is only sent to trash after the effect is finished activating, so it is sent to trash after [BT13-090 LordKnightmon]'s effect activates\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT10-110 Seiken Meppa], targeting [BT10-112 Jesmon GX] to activate its [When Digivolving] effect. I place [BT13-090 LordKnightmon] with the effect of [BT10-112 Jesmon GX] and activate [BT13-090 LordKnightmon]\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect. Am I able to add the same [BT10-110 Seiken Meppa] card that I used back to hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means this Digimon may be treated as if it were 1 of the listed requirements for that DigiXros, for example if the listed requirements are [Shoutmon X4] +[Beelzemon], this Digimon may be treated as [Shoutmon X4]/[Beelzemon] for that DigiXros.\n",
      "question": "Q: \"When you would DigiXros this turn, this Digimon may replace 1 of the DigiXros requirements.\" What does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only lets you treat it as 1 requirement for the DigiXros.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this is the first card I place into the digivolution cards when digixrossing, can I continue treating it as other additional requirements and meet all of them with just 1 card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't work.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name and the opponent's Digimon are deleted at the same time, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if cards in hand are trashed by my opponent's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can add a red tamer card to your hand even if it doesn't have [Vaccine]\u00a0trait. Only red Digimon cards cannot be added to your hand unless they have [Vaccine]\u00a0trait.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that the red tamer card among the cards revealed from the deck cannot be added to the hand unless it has the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait."
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a red Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait or a red tamer card, add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect be added to the hand unless there are both a red Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait and a red tamer card among the 3 cards revealed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of this card is \"add one card to your hand\", so you need to add it to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that if there are both a red Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait a red tamer card among the three cards that are revealed, add only one of them to your hand, and add one to your hand. is it possible to put the back under the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't work.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon that has this card as an digivolution cards and my red tamer disappear at the same time, will the gain 1 memory effect be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack has been changed by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it will work.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon that has this card as its digivolution cards attacks the opponent and the opponent blocks with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect \"The name of this card/Digimon are also treated as [Shoutmon] and [Starmons].\u201d, can this card be selected as the target of effects that target only [Shoutmon]/[Starmons]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack has been changed by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it will work.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon that has this card as its digivolution cards attacks the opponent and the opponent blocks with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible. In that case, add as many cards as possible to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect add cards to my hand even if there is only one card that has the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait or [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait among the revealed cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot. This effect is triggered \"when the opponent's security is reduced\", so even if you check multiple copies of your opponent's security, you can choose whether to trigger it at the first check. And since it's a [Once Per Turn] effect, if it activates when the security is reduced on the first check, it won't activate on the next check.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] effect activate twice when I check 2 opponent's security cards with my Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Bird]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:BirdCategory:Ancient BirdCategory:Bird DragonCategory:Giant BirdCategory:Holy BirdCategory:Ancient BirdkinCategory:AvianCategory:BirdkinCategory:Mini BirdCategory:Mysterious Bird\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Bird]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u9ce5), does it include traits other than [Bird] (\u9ce5)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Beast]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient Mythical BeastCategory:Beast DragonCategory:Beast KnightCategory:BeastCategory:Holy BeastCategory:Mythical BeastCategory:Rare AnimalCategory:Four SovereignsCategory:Ancient AnimalCategory:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:BeastkinCategory:Dark AnimalCategory:Mysterious BeastCategory:Sea Beast\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Beast]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u7363), does it include traits other than [Beast] (\u7363)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon card that is played with this card's [On Deletion] effect is \"a red Digimon card with a 3000 DP or less that includes a [Avian]/[Bird]/[Beast]/[Animal]/[Sovereign]\u00a0in one of its traits.\" For example, it means that the upper limit of \"3000 DP or less\" will be +2000. For example, if you have one red tamer, you can make a Digimon card with a 5000 DP or less, and if you have two tamers, a Digimon card with a 7000 DP or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card mean, \"For each red tamer you have, add 2000 to the maximum DP of the card you can play by this effect.\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot. It is valid only for the [On Deletion] effect that this card itself.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect of \"add 2000 to the maximum DP of the card you can play by this effect for each of my red tamers\" also apply to other effects that play Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack has been changed by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it will work.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks the opponent and the opponent blocks with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, will this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect \"The name of this card/Digimon are also treated as as [OmniShoutmon] and [ZeigGreymon].\u201d, can this card be selected as the target of effects that target only as [OmniShoutmon]/[ZeigGreymon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a Digimon card with [Gaogamon]\u00a0in its name or a blue tamer card, add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect not add a card to my hand unless there are both a Digimon card with [Gaogamon]\u00a0in its name and a blue tamer card among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \u201cAdd to your hand\u201d, you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that if there are both a Digimon card with [Gaogamon]\u00a0in its name and a blue tamer card among the revealed cards, only one of them can be added to the hand and the other can be trashed. Must I add one to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have either a Digimon card with [Veedramon]\u00a0in its name or a blue tamer card, add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect not add a card to my hand unless there are both a Digimon card with [Veedramon]\u00a0in its name and a blue tamer card among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \u201cAdd to your hand\u201d, you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that if there are both a Digimon card with [Veedramon]\u00a0in its name and a blue tamer card among the three cards that are revealed, add only one of them to your hand and add one to the bottom of your deck. Must I add one to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is considered to be activating a Tamer's card effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's effect to activate an [On Play] effect, does that count as activating a Digimon's card effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect \"The name of this card/Digimon are also treated as as [MetalGreymon] and [Cyberdramon].\u201d, can this card be selected as the target of effects that target only as [MetalGreymon ]/[Cyberdramon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since the card was not revealed by a security check, its [Security] effect can't be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Security] effect of the card added to the hand with this card's \"your opponent adds the top card of their security stack to their hand\" effect be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Burst Digivolution is a mechanic, not an effect, so it doesn't count as \"When an effect adds cards to your opponent's hand\".\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent returns a Tamer to their hand by Burst Digivolving, does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon cannot attack the player, so it will attack the opponent's Digimon. If there is no opponent Digimon to attack, such as when there is no opponent\u2019s suspended Digimon, it will not attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon gains an effect that forces it to attack, what will happen?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't work.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card and my purple Digimon or tamer are deleted at the same time and there are no purple cards left in the battle area, will this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] without deleting itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Each Digimon activates its inherited effect once, and only the Digimon that activates it later remains in the Battle Area. An interrupting \"when you would\" effect will trigger and activate only once during a series of effects derived from one effect activation, even if it is not a [Once Per Turn] effect. After the original effect has been activated, it can be triggered and activated again.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: You and your opponent have 1 Digimon with [Sukamon]\u00a0in its name that has this card as a digivolution card. When that Digimon is deleted, what will happen if both of us use the inherited effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your level 6 Digimon is selected as the target of \"By deleting 1 of your Digimon\". Then, if this card's inherited effect attempts to delete the [EX1-073 Machinedramon].However, if [EX1-073 Machinedramon] activates its effect in response, it will not be deleted by the effect of.Because it no longer gets deleted, this card's inherited effect cannot prevent the deletion, the level 6 Digimon gets deleted by the effect of [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame].<br. />As such, because your Digimon was deleted, it can delete an opponent's unsuspended Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the deleted Digimon.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a level 6 Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card, and my opponent has [EX1-073 Machinedramon] whose name is treated as [Sukamon]. What happens if I use [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame] to delete both Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] without deleting itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Each Digimon activates its inherited effect once, and only the Digimon that activates it later remains in the Battle Area. An interrupting \"when you would\" effect will trigger and activate only once during a series of effects derived from one effect activation, even if it is not a [Once Per Turn] effect. After the original effect has been activated, it can be triggered and activated again.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: You and your opponent have 1 Digimon with [Sukamon]\u00a0in its name that has this card as a digivolution card. When that Digimon is deleted, what will happen if both of us use the inherited effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your level 6 Digimon is selected as the target of \"By deleting 1 of your Digimon\". Then, if this card's inherited effect attempts to delete the [EX1-073 Machinedramon].However, if [EX1-073 Machinedramon] activates its effect in response, it will not be deleted by the effect of.Because it no longer gets deleted, this card's inherited effect cannot prevent the deletion, the level 6 Digimon gets deleted by the effect of [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame].<br. />As such, because your Digimon was deleted, it can delete an opponent's unsuspended Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the deleted Digimon.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a level 6 Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card, and my opponent has [EX1-073 Machinedramon] whose name is treated as [Sukamon]. What happens if I use [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame] to delete both Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You may look at all of the contents of your security stack only by yourself without revealing it to your opponent. After that, choose one card to add to your hand, reveal only that card to your opponent, and add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"search your security stack\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] without deleting itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Each Digimon activates its inherited effect once, and only the Digimon that activates it later remains in the Battle Area. An interrupting \"when you would\" effect will trigger and activate only once during a series of effects derived from one effect activation, even if it is not a [Once Per Turn] effect. After the original effect has been activated, it can be triggered and activated again.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: You and your opponent have 1 Digimon with [Sukamon]\u00a0in its name that has this card as a digivolution card. When that Digimon is deleted, what will happen if both of us use the inherited effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The original name will be changed to [Sukamon] and the colour will be changed to White, but the effect of \"treat as XXX\" will not be lost, so at the same time as being treated as [Sukamon] and White, the name and colour due to those pre-existing effects will not be changed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects against opponent Digimon that already have effects such as \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as XXX or \"The colour of this Digimon is also treated as XXX.\", what will happen to the opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: [ST12-13 Sistermon Ciel], [BT6-084 Sistermon Ciel], and [BT7-083 Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)] are also treated as [Sistermon Noir]/[Sistermon Noir (Awakened)] respectively, but these are special game rules and not effects, so if this card's [On Play] or [When Digivolving] effects would target them, their names will be changed to [Sukamon]. They will no longer be treated as [Sistermon Ciel]/[Sistermon Noir].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects are activated on the opponent's [ST12-13 Sistermon Ciel], [BT6-084 Sistermon Ciel], or [BT7-083 Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)], what will happen to that opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your level 6 Digimon is selected as the target of \"By deleting 1 of your Digimon\". Then, if this card's inherited effect attempts to delete the [EX1-073 Machinedramon].However, if [EX1-073 Machinedramon] activates its effect in response, it will not be deleted by the effect of.Because it no longer gets deleted, this card's inherited effect cannot prevent the deletion, the level 6 Digimon gets deleted by the effect of [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame].<br. />As such, because your Digimon was deleted, it can delete an opponent's unsuspended Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the deleted Digimon.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a level 6 Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card, and my opponent has [EX1-073 Machinedramon] whose name is treated as [Sukamon]. What happens if I use [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame] to delete both Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will keep the DP reduction, and if after applying the previous DP reduction to the new DP value (3000), its DP is 0 then it will be deleted.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the Digimon that becomes a [Sukamon] with this effect, if its DP had already been reduced before?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Tamer will be treated as [Sukamon] and a White Tamer card, but it will not have DP.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if the Digimon affect by this card's effect becomes a Tamer due to \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon will be treated as a White Level 2 Digimon named [Sukamon], but it will not have DP, so it will be sent to the trash (not deleted) since a Digimon without DP cannot exist in the battle area.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if the Digimon affected by this card's effect becomes a Level 2 Digimon without DP due to \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digimon becomes a white Digimon with 3000 DP and an original name of [Sukamon], and is also treated as the name (or as containing the name) specified by the <Rule> text.\n[5]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is activated on a Digimon that has \"<Rule> Name: also treated as X\" or \"<Rule> Name: also treated as containing X\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose freely as long as the total play cost is 7 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: From the cards revealed by this card's effect, can I deliberately select fewer targets so that the total play cost is less than 7?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible. This effect triggers every time security is checked and flipped.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect, when an opponent's Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e checks 2 of your security, can 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon gain -4000 DP twice?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No,it cannot. This card is treated as including [Leomon]\u00a0in its name. but it is not considered as [Leomon].\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Leomon].\u201d, can this card be selected as the target of an effect that targets only [Leomon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect will suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon for each green or black tamer card you have, but only 1 Digimon can be suspended during the unsuspend phase. The target can be not only the Digimon that was suspended by this card's effect, but also the Digimon that was originally already suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that when you have 2 green or black tamer cards, you can suspend 2 of your opponent's Digimon and prevent those 2 of your opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during your opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose freely as long as the total play cost is 10 or less.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: From the cards revealed by this card's effect, can I deliberately select fewer targets so that the total play cost is less than 10?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. A 2-color Tamer still counts as 1 Tamer.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to reveal 2 cards from the top of my deck when I have a green and black 2-color Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 2-3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible for this card's [When Digivolving] effect to trash 3 cards from the hand even when the opponent has only 2 or less Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. 2-colour tamers count as one tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 1 green/black tamer, can I reduce the digivolution cost paid by this card's effect by 2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Vemmon] can be placed in the digivolution cards even if those cards are not among the revealed cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If there is no [Snatchmon]/[Destromon]/[Galactimon]/[Fusionize] among the cards revealed by this card's effect, can [Vemmon] be placed in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a card with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name or [X Antibody]\u00a0in its name or a black tamer card, add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect not add a card to my hand unless there is a card with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name or [X Antibody]\u00a0in its name and a black tamer card among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \u201cAdd to your hand\u201d, you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that if there are both a card with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name or [X Antibody]\u00a0in its name and a black tamer card among the revealed cards, add only one of them to your hand and add one to your deck. Must I add one to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect \"The name of this card/digimon is also treated as [Numemon].\u201d, can it be selected as the target of an effect that targets [Numemon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 4-5 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"when a Digimon becomes unsuspended\" inherited effect work when an opponent's Digimon becomes unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect \"The name of this card/digimon is also treated as [DarkKnightmon] and [Tuwarmon].\u201d, can it be selected as the target of an effect that targets [DarkKnightmon]/[Tuwarmon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if there is no [Analogman] among the revealed cards, if there is a card with with the [Cyborg]\u00a0trait or [Machine]\u00a0trait, add it to your hand or place it in the digivolution cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there is no [Analogman] among the cards revealed by this card's effect, you can add a card with the [Cyborg]\u00a0trait or [Machine]\u00a0trait to your hand, or place it in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I don't have [Machinedramon] in my hand, is it possible to return my [Analogman] to the bottom of the deck with this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card was deleted during an attack and the attack hasn't ended yet, you cannot declare an attack in the middle of an attack.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If [BT9-102 Attack of the Heavy Mobile Digimon!] has been used this turn. After this card attacks, it gets deleted in a battle or by a [Security] effect, if its [On Deletion] plays a [Machinedramon], can it declare an attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. If your Digimon does not have the highest DP when you declare an attack, the conditions for this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect will not be fulfilled.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: The opponent's Digimon, which is not the Digimon with the highest DP, attacks, and the [When Attacking] effect increases the DP, making it the Digimon with the highest DP. In that case, can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to change the attack target to this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect \"when a Digimon becomes unsuspended\" also activate when the opponent's Digimon becomes unsuspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the attacker declared an attack when it was the Digimon with the highest DP.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent attacks with their Digimon with the highest DP and then an effect reduces its DP. Can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon card with [DigiXros] requirements is played by an effect and this card is placed in the digivolution cards by a [DigiXros], does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot. If the DP becomes 0 when it is played and deleted, the [On Play] effect cannot be activated. Also, if it is deleted by other effects or rules, the condition of \"by deleting this Digimon\" will not be fulfilled.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is played, the already activated DP- effect reduced the DP to 0 and deleted it. In that case, can the effect be activated even if the condition of \"By deleting this Digimon\" of the [On Play] effect is met?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon and my [Yuu Amano] are deleted at the same time, won't my [Yuu Amano] be deleted by this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If you trash [Mirei Mikagura] or a card with the [Angel]\u00a0trait, [Archangel]\u00a0trait, or [Fallen Angel]\u00a0trait from your hand, the [When Digivolving] effect of this card becomes Is it possible to return it from the trash to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes it is.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is the effect of this card is that you nay play a blue level 3 Digimon card from the digivolution cards of your purple Digimon, or you may play a purple level 3 Digimon card from the digivolution cards of your blue Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't work. When the effect of [EX3-023 Plesiomon] plays a level 4 Digimon cardfrom the digivolution cards of a Digimon, this card has not yet become a digivolution card, so the inherited effect will not be triggered.\n",
      "question": "Q: With the [When Digivolving] effect of [EX3-023 Plesiomon], I play a level 4 Digimon card from the digivolution cards of a Digimon, and placed this card from my hand in the digivolution cards of [EX3-023 Plesiomon]. In this case, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. First, put 1 or 2 cards with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits from your trash into your hand, then place 1 or 2 cards with [Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits under your tamer. You cannot put the target card under the tamer without adding it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, is it possible to place a card with [Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits from your trash into the digivolution cards of one of your tamers without adding it to your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Bagra Army\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Bagra Army]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u30d0\u30b0\u30e9\u8ecd), does it include traits other than [Bagra Army] (\u30d0\u30b0\u30e9\u8ecd)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the opponent has 2 or more Digimon, does this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effect to check all cards in the opponent's hand and trash 1 card from it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when a Digimon is placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards, any digivolution cards it had are trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effect \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon under 1 of your opponent's other Digimon as its bottom digivolution card.\", mean that the digivolution cards of your opponent's chosen Digimon card are also placed in the digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not as the Digimon card was not in play at the time of placing digivolution cards underneath.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has activates a \"when you would play\" effect to place digivolution cards underneath a Digimon that hasn't been played yet. Does the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The token will be removed from the game.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card chooses a Token to be placed underneath another Digimon as a digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Nothing will happen, as a Token cannot have digivolution cards. So the Digimon will remain in play.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card chooses to place a Digimon underneath a Token as a digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the Digimon is unaffected by card effects, it will not be placed as a digivolution card. As such, both Digimon will remain in the battle area.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I choose a Digimon with \"unaffected by card effects\" to be placed as a digivolution card underneath another Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the other Digimon is unaffected by card effects, it it cannot gain digivolution cards by effects. As such, both Digimon will remain in the battle area.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I choose a Digimon to be placed as a digivolution card underneath another Digimon with \"unaffected by card effects\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Bird]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:BirdCategory:Ancient BirdCategory:Bird DragonCategory:Giant BirdCategory:Holy BirdCategory:Ancient BirdkinCategory:AvianCategory:BirdkinCategory:Mini BirdCategory:Mysterious Bird\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Bird]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u9ce5), does it include traits other than [Bird] (\u9ce5)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Beast]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient Mythical BeastCategory:Beast DragonCategory:Beast KnightCategory:BeastCategory:Holy BeastCategory:Mythical BeastCategory:Rare AnimalCategory:Four SovereignsCategory:Ancient AnimalCategory:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:BeastkinCategory:Dark AnimalCategory:Mysterious BeastCategory:Sea Beast\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Beast]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u7363), does it include traits other than [Beast] (\u7363)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not work if the turns change before your main phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate when my turn begins, or if memory is moved to the opponent's side due to some effect during my turn, my unsuspend phase, or my breeding phase, and the turn ends?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not work if the turns change before your main phase.\n",
      "question": "Q:  Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate when my turn begins, or if memory is moved to the opponent's side due to some effect during my turn, my unsuspend phase, or my breeding phase, and the turn ends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible as long as the opponent has declared that they will attack the player when declaring the attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon attacks a player, and then changed the target of the attack to a Digimon with the effect of \uff1cRaid\uff1e. In that case, is it possible to change the attack target again with this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your Digimon is not affected by [Security] effects of your opponent's option cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon is affected by this card's effect of \"isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\", will it also be immune to the [Security] effects of the opponent's option cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [EX1-068 Ice Wall!] is still in effect, and this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's option cards\" no longer applies, so your Digimon gains \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\".\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon is under the effect of this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's option cards\", my opponent uses [EX1-068 Ice Wall!]. When it becomes my next turn and this card's effect wears off, does my Digimon have a \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since your Digimon will no longer be affected by the effect of the Option Card, the \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect will be lost.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent used [EX1-068 Ice Wall!] and my Digimon gained \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\", but I activate this card's effect so that my Digimon \"isn't affected by your opponent's option cards\". In that case, what happens to the \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon will have its DP reduced as this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's option cards\" no longer applies. So your Digimon will lose 8000 DP.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, if my opponent uses [BT11-100 Megalo Spark] and chooses a Digimon that received this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's option cards\" on my turn. What happens when their turn ends?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: With this effect, if your Digimon has digivolved into [Angewomon], you can play [LadyDevimon] from your hand without paying the cost, and if your Digimon has digivolved [LadyDevimon], you can play [Angewomon] from your hand without paying the cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] effect play [Angewomon] from your hand when you digivolve your Digimon into [Angewomon]? Or  when your Digimon digivolves into [LadyDevimon], is it possible to play [LadyDevimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not work if the turns change before your main phase.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate when my turn begins, or if memory is moved to the opponent's side due to some effect during my turn, my unsuspend phase, or my breeding phase, and the turn ends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally when you DigiXros the requirements can only be placed from your hand or battle area, but with this card's effect you can also place requirements from under your tamers as well.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the [Your Turn] effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place requirements from under my other tamers as well? Not just thistamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a tamer in the digivolution cards of a Digimon, can I also place requirements from under that tamer as well?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only targets 1 Digimon. The effect of this card will not trigger when 2 Digimon are played at the same time.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-097 Tidal Wave] to play 2 Digimon with [DigiXros] requirements and I suspend 1 of this card, can I place cards underneath both Digimon for their [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only activate this card's effect when playing exactly 1 Digimon and when that Digimon has [DigiXros] requirements.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 1 Digimon with [DigiXros] requirements and 1 Digimon without [DigiXros] requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you now have a Digimon with [Seadramon]\u00a0in its name, so the effect can activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If you don't have any Digimon with [Seadramon]\u00a0in its name, and you use this card's effect to play a Digimon card with [Seadramon]\u00a0in its name from the digivolution cards of your blue Digimon, will the effect \u201creturn 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to the bottom of its owner's deck.\u201d activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. It's an effect that says \"suspend 2 of your opponent's Digimon\", so you must suspend 2 Digimon if there are 2 valid targets.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, when 2 or more of my opponent's Digimon are suspended, is it possible to intentionally cause only 1 to become suspended, or not to suspend a Digimon at all?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Insect]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:InsectoidCategory:Ancient Insectoid\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Insect]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u6606\u866b\u578b), does it include traits other than [Insect] (\u6606\u866b\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect allow your Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon that is unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: For the effect of this card, if I don't have [Destromon]/[Galactimon] in my trash, can I still place 1 [Vemmon] from my trash in my Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I deliberately choose this card's effect so that the total play cost of the targeted cards are less than the play cost of one of my Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card's effect cannot force a Digimon to attack if it cannot attack normally.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect allow a suspened Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name attack a player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: With this card's effect, when I attack with my Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name, does that Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card's effect can only allows your Digimon to attack a player.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s effect allow my Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name to attack an opponent\u2019s suspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when a Digimon is placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards, any digivolution cards it had are trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card, \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon under 1 of your opponent's other Digimon as its bottom digivolution card.\", mean that the digivolution cards of your opponent's chosen Digimon card are also placed in the digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The token will be removed from the game.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card chooses a Token to be placed underneath another Digimon as a digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Nothing will happen, as a Token cannot have digivolution cards. So the Digimon will remain in play.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card chooses to place a Digimon underneath a Token as a digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the Digimon is unaffected by card effects, it will not be placed as a digivolution card. As such, both Digimon will remain in the battle area.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I choose a Digimon with \"unaffected by card effects\" to be placed as a digivolution card underneath another Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the other Digimon is unaffected by card effects, it it cannot gain digivolution cards by effects. As such, both Digimon will remain in the battle area.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I choose a Digimon to be placed as a digivolution card underneath another Digimon with \"unaffected by card effects\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e is not considered an effect where a Digimon would leave the battle area.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect and place 4 [Vemmon] at the bottom of their owners' decks to prevent it from leaving the battle area when this Digimon is affected by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When this Digimon would leave the battle area\" refers to one of the following statuses: \"placed in trash due to deletion,\" \"returned to hand/deck,\" \"placed in security stack,\" \"moved to an area other than the battle area,\" or \"placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards.\"\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"When this Digimon would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate it when this Digimon is affected by effect that moves it to one of those areas.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect and place 4 [Vemmon] at the bottom of their owners' decks to prevent it from leaving the battle area when this Digimon is returned to my deck or placed in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate if it becomes your opponent's turn before your main phase\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect if an effect at the start of my turn or during my unsuspend phase or breeding phase causes the memory counter to move to my opponent's side and it becomes my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"When this Digimon would leave the battle area\" does not trigger for DNA Digivolution.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I have Galacticmon and a red level 6 Digimon in my battle area and I declare that I'm going to DNA Digivolve them into [ST13-06 RagnaLoardmon], can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect to prevent the digivolution?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon with [Veedramon]\u00a0in its name without a [When Digivolving] effect suspends, can I suspend this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with [Veedramon]\u00a0in its name in its name attacks and becomes suspended. If I activate the effect of [BT9-109 X Antibody] to digivolve into a Digimon with a [When Digivolving] effect. Does this card's effect activate the new Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has \"Your opponent's [When Digivolving] effects cannot activate\". Can this card perform the [When Digivolving] effect of the Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Am I able to activate a \"[When Digivolving] [Once Per Turn]\" effect using this card's [Your Turn] effect, if it was already activated this turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect refers to deletion effect that states \"Delete Digimon with X DP or less\" and \"Select opponent\u2019s Digimon with the total of X or less\". This effect enables the player to increase the limit by 1000 DP. However, this effect does not apply to effects that don't mention a DP number, such as \"Delete the Digimon that has lower DP than this Digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: What does the effect \"Add +1000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It only affects the maximum DP, so [BT3-098 Plasma Stake] will still delete only Digimon with 13000 DP or more.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect increase the minimum DP deletion of [BT3-098 Plasma Stake] from 13000 DP to 14000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can evolve into [ChaosGallantmon]/[Gallantmon (X Antibody)], but it cannot digivolve into [BT5-081 ChaosGallantmon] nor [EX2-073 Gallantmon Crimson Mode] because it does not meet the digivolution requirements for [BT5-081 ChaosGallantmon] nor [EX2-073 Gallantmon Crimson Mode] as it is not a Purple Level 5 Digimon nor is it a Red Level 6 Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect allow it to digiolve into [ChaosGallantmon]/[Gallantmon (X Antibody)]/[Gallantmon Crimson Mode] if no Digimon was deleted by its effect."
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card's inherited [End of Attack] effect is deleted in battle during the battle that this Digimon attacked, will [End of Attack] activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name or Digimon card with [Free]\u00a0trait and 1 card [Davis Motomiya]\u00a0in its name, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name or Digimon card with [Free]\u00a0trait and 1 card [Davis Motomiya]\u00a0in its name, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's a tamer card with [Davis Motomiya]\u00a0in its name, so you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-088 Davis Motomiya & Ken Ichijoji] is among the 3 cards revealed by this effect, can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from a LV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from a LV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [All Turns] effect activate when the opponent's Digimon activates \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They are trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to place one of my other blue Digimon under this Digimon's digivolution cards, what happens to that Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [BT9-109 X Antibody] is also trashed because it is not being trashed by an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When you place one of your other blue Digimon under this Digimon's digivolution cards with the effect of this card and that Digimon has [BT9-109 X Antibody], what happens to X Antibody?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cBlocker\uff1e while it has 2 or more colors of evolution sources.\n",
      "question": "Q: While this Digimon has 3 or more colors in its digivolution cards, does it gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e from this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 [Greymon]\u00a0in its name and 1 card [Davis Motomiya]\u00a0in its name, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name and 1 card [Davis Motomiya]\u00a0in its name, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon with either \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e and/or \uff1cSecurity Attack -X\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e the Digimon will still be treated as having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e .\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e does that mean they cancel each other out and the Digimon will be treated as not having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon with either \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e and/or \uff1cSecurity Attack -X\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e the Digimon will still be treated as having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e .\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e does that mean they cancel each other out and the Digimon will be treated as not having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamers cannot attack, so [BT4-092 Marcus Damon] who is in the battle area as a Tamer cannot attack.[Marcus Damon] such as [BT12-092 Marcus Damon], while it is treated as a Digimon by its effect, can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my [BT4-092 Marcus Damon] who has +3000 DP and \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from this card's [Your Turn] effect attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, effects that target Digimon cannot target [Marcus Damon] while they are not treated as Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When an effect that targets a Digimon with a DP of 3000 or less activates, will this card's [Your Turn] effect to give +3000 DP to [Marcus Damon] allow it to become a target of that effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it is not an effect with a duration such as \"for the turn\", the effect will be lost unless the name of the Digimon after digivolving is also [Marcus Damon].\n",
      "question": "Q: My [Marcus Damon] has digivolved into a Digimon with the effect of a card that treats my Tamer as a Lv.3 Digimon and digivolving into it. In that case, what happens to the +3000 DP and \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e that [Marcus Damon] obtained from this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamers do not have DP, so they are not treated as 3000 DP Tamers.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will [Marcus Damon], whose has +3000 DP due to this card's [Your Turn] effect, be treated as a 3000 DP Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon with either \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e and/or \uff1cSecurity Attack -X\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e the Digimon will still be treated as having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e .\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e does that mean they cancel each other out and the Digimon will be treated as not having \uff1cSecurity Attack\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name or Digimon card with [Free]\u00a0trait and 1 card [Ken Ichijoji]\u00a0in its name, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name or Digimon card with [Free]\u00a0trait and 1 card [Ken Ichijoji]\u00a0in its name, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's a tamer card with [Ken Ichijoji]\u00a0in its name, so you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-088 Ken Ichijoji & Ken Ichijoji] is among the 3 cards revealed by this effect, can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. The effect of this card's [On Play] is \"Reveal up to 3 Tamer cards from your hand and place all revealed cards on the bottom of your deck in any order\". If you reveal, you must also place it at the bottom of your deck. If you reveal 3 tamer cards from your hand, be sure to place them on the bottom of your deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to reveal 3 Tamer cards from my hand and not return them to the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If there is no target to attack, the effect will not be able to declare an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to this card's [When Digivolving] effect if the opponent has no Digimon that it can attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If there is no target to attack, the effect will finish without declaring an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to this card's [When Digivolving] effect if the opponent has no Digimon that it can attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Total up the number of suspended Digimon and suspended Tamers of each player, and gain 1 memory for every 2 of them. For example, if you have 1 suspended Digimon and 1 suspended Tamer, and your opponent has 2 suspended Digimon, the total will be 4, so you gain 2 memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do you count the \"gain 1 memory for every 2 suspended Digimon and Tamer\" for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect \"All other Digimon and Tamers don't unsuspend\" causes them both to be unable to unsuspend.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this Digimon, or when both my opponent and I have 1 of this Digimon each. Will this card's [All Turns] effect prevent this Digimon from unsuspending during the unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be unsuspended. DNA Digivolving comes into play unsuspended because it treats it as a new Digimon. This card's effect does not affect it because, it does not become unsuspended from a suspended Digimon.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in the battle area, and my opponent performs DNA Digivolution with two suspended Digimon. Will that Digimon be unsuspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that is correct.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, does that mean that the Digimon cannot be unsuspended by the \uff1cReboot\uff1e and effects that unsuspend the Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 [Greymon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name or Digimon card with [Free]\u00a0trait and 1 card [Tai Kamiya]\u00a0in its name, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card with [Greymon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name or Digimon card with [Free]\u00a0trait and 1 card [Tai Kamiya]\u00a0in its name, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's a tamer card with [Tai Kamiya]\u00a0in its name, so you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If [BT5-093 Tai Kamiya & Matt Ishida] is among the 3 cards revealed by this effect, can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from a LV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. However, in that case, the effect finishes without attacking due to the \"cannot attack\" effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect target an opponent's Digimon that has an effect that \"cannot attack\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the start of your opponent's main phase, the effect given by this card's effect will be triggered at the same time, and your opponent will decide which one to activate first. After the first effect has been activated, the second Digimon that was waiting to activate will activate its effect before the [Reaction]/[Counter] timing, but the first Digimon is already attacking, so it cannot attack. effect ends. As a result, only the opponent's Digimon that activated its effect first will attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect twice and give 2 of my opponent's Digimon the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon.\" effect, what will happen\u00a0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon that are unaffected by opponent's effects can also be selected as targets for effects, so when the opponent's Digimon becomes your opponent's turn, the effect of \"This Digimon is unaffected by opponent's effects\" is lost and it receives the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect. As a result, it will attack at the start of the main phase.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated against an opponent's Digimon that has the effect \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon is unaffected by opponent's effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Black Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Black-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from a LV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Black Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Black-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the target of the attack has been changed by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, so it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks the opponent and the opponent blocks with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, will this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [All Turns] effect activate when my Digimon other than this Digimon or my opponent's Digimon attacks and the target of the attack is changed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the target of the attack has been changed by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, so it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks the opponent and the opponent blocks with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, will this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [All Turns] effect activate when my Digimon other than this Digimon or my opponent's Digimon attacks and the target of the attack is changed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be played.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card revealed a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or higher that can reduce its play cost to 6 or lower due to some effect, Can that card be played with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has [EX3-013 Chaosdramon] as a digivolution source and is targeted for deletion by an effect. When this Digimon would be deleted, can I activate this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect to trash the top card of my opponent's security and then activate [EX3-013 Chaosdramon]\u2019s [All Turns] effect to trash two level 5 cards from its digivolution sources to avoid being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Since this card's \"This Digimon gains all effects of [Machinedramon] and [Chaosdramon] cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards\" effect is [All Turns], it activates the instant digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effect is gained and triggered.\n",
      "question": "Q: [EX3-013 Chaosdramon] digivolves into this card. This card gains all effects of [Chaosdramon] cards in its digivolution sources, so does [EX3-013 Chaosdramon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon will always gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e instead, and \"trash the top 2 cards from your deck\" cannot be performed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if it has a [Wizardmon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. Can I trash 2 card from the top of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 2-3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Count your Tamers with different colors. In the case of a 2-color Tamer card, if it has a color that does not overlap, it counts as one tamer of that color. For example, if you have one red Tamer, one blue-yellow Tamer, and one red-yellow Tamer, you can count them as one red Tamer, one blue Tamer, and one yellow Tamer, for a total of three.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do you count the condition of this card's [When Digivolving] effect \"for each Tamer with a different color \"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still attack while suspneded.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [End of Your Turn] effect attack even if this Digimon is suspended while there are 4 or more evolution sources?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Digimon that are \"unaffected by the opponent's Digimon's effects\" can be selected as the destination of the Digimon to be placed in the evolution source, but in that case they will not be affected and cannot be placed.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I place an opponent's Digimon into the evolution sources of another Digimon that currently has \"This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent's Digimon effects\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the effect has already been activated, even if the [Sparrowmon] leaves the digivolution cards, the effect will continue until the end of the opponent's next turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, all of my Digimon gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and the effect of not returning to the hand or deck. If [Sparrowmon] is no longer in this card's digivolution cards, what will happen to the effect(s) that my Digimon got?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if the current DP of the Digimon is not 10000 or higher when the effect is activated, you will not gain 2 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as its digivolution card attacked the player while it had 10000 DP and checked security. If the [Security] effect of the flipped card reduces the DP to 9000 or less, can the memory +2 effect of this card's digivolution card effect be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's \"When this Digimon checks your opponent's security stack\" condition is triggered when this Digimon attacks your opponent or activates \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and performs a security check. \"When your opponent's security is reduced\" is triggered not only by security checks, but also when the number of security cards is reduced by other means, such as \"Trash your opponent's security\" effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: How is this card's \"When this Digimon checks your opponent's security stack\" trigger condition different from \"When your opponent's security is reduced\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's inherited effect activates after the [Security] effect but before the battle with the Security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack the player with a Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card. The Digimon gets deleted in a battle with a Security Digimon. In this case, can I gain 2 memory off this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. you can. In that case, the cards will still be in the digivolution cards of [Guilmon].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [Main] effect to place this card, 1 [Growlmon], and 1 [WarGrowlmon] as digivolution cards for [Guilmon], can I choose not to digivolve into a [Gallantmon] in your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate another card's effect to digivolve one of my Digimon, can I digivolve my [Guilmon] into a [Gallantmon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will still activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Your Turn] effect, will it activate even if the attacking Digimon is not \"Blue and Green\" but \"Green and Blue\" instead?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. That Digimon is not a \"2-color Digimon\" even if it has blue and green in its colours.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [Your Turn] effect work even if I attack with a Digimon that has 3 or more colors, including blue and green?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Tamer will be able to attack just like a Digimon and will also be subject to effects that target a Digimon. It can also be destroyed in battle with a Digimon or Security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does it mean that this Tamer's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect causes it to also be treated as a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is also being treated as a Digimon due to its [Start of Your Main Phase] effect and has its DP reduced to 0 by an opponent's effect, is it deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will trigger. If this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect has been activated, this card is treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, so when it becomes suspended, it will trigger the \"When this Tamer becomes suspended\" effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is also being treated as a Digimon due to its [Start of Your Main Phase] effect and is suspended, does that trigger this card's [Your Turn] \"When this Tamer becomes suspended\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not. This card's effect only treats this card as a Digimon (not a Digimon card), and, once it is placed as a digivolution source for another Digimon, the effect no longer applies and it is treated only as a Tamer card.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is also being treated as a Digimon due to its [Start of Your Main Phase] effect and is placed as a digivolution source for another Digimon by an effect that says \"Place a Digimon as a digivolution source for another Digimon\", is this card treated as a Digimon card in the digivolution sources?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 Digimon card with \uff1cSave\uff1e in its card text and 1 card with [Hunter]\u00a0trait, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card with Digimon card with \uff1cSave\uff1e in its card text and 1 card with [Hunter]\u00a0trait, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can not. A Digimon that is unable to attack cannot declare an attack by this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Main] effect attack with my suspended Digimon or a Digimon played that turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: When attacking with this card's [Main] effect, does that Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can not. A Digimon that is unable to attack cannot be attacked by this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Main] effect declare an attack with my Digimon that was played that turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: When attacking with this card's [Main] effect, does that Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They are trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I place 1 of my blue Digimon as the bottom digivolution card of 1 of my other Digimon with this card's effect, what happens to the digivolution cards that the placed Digimon had?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: [BT9-109 X-Antibody] is also trashed since it is trashed by game rules and not by an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I place 1 of my blue Digimon as the bottom digivolution card of 1 of my other Digimon with this card's effect, what happens if the placed Digimon had [BT9-109 X-Antibody] as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a dual-color yellow and red Tamer in play, does it count twice for this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: 3 of your opponent's Digimon get -4000 DP. This card's effect only targets 3 of your opponent's Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have two yellow or red Tamers in play, does this card's [Main] effect cause 6 of my opponent's Digimon to get -2000 DP or 3 of my opponent's Digimon to get -4000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you would win the game.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has 1 security, my Digimon attacks the player directly, and an opponent's Digimon that has been given the [On Deletion] effect of this card's [Main] effect is deleted by a [When Attacking] effect, do I win the game since the security card is trashed before the attack happens?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not unsuspend. This card's effect is \"All of your opponent's cards don't unsuspend during their next unsuspend phase\", so Digimon played or moved into the Battle Area after this card's [Main] effect is activated are also affected by it.\n",
      "question": "Q: After I activate this card's [Main] effect, my opponent plays a suspended Digimon by an effect. Does that Digimon become unsuspended during their next unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, the effect ends without performing an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Main] effect, can I choose an opponent's digimon that has an effect that makes it unable to attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the beginning of the opponent's Main Phase, both of the effects given by this card trigger at the same time, and the opponent chooses which to activate first. After activating [When Attacking] (and such) effects, both Digimon's pending effects must be activated before the [Reaction]/[Counter] timing, but an attack cannot be declared while in the middle of an attack, so the effect ends. As a result, only the Digimon whose effect is activated first declares an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card twice, giving two of my opponent's Digimon the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon.\" effect, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When it becomes the opponent's turn, the opponent's Digimon loses the benefit of \"This Digimon is not affected by your opponent's effects\", so the effect given by this card causes it to attack at the beginning of the Main Phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I target an opponent's Digimon with \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon is not affected by your opponent's effects\" for this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can activate if one of your Digimon digivolves into [Beelzemon (X Antibody)] while this card is in the trash. [Trash] indicates that this card can be used while it's in the trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does the timing of [Trash] [Your Turn] mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, activating an effect from the trash is different from using an option card, so there's no need to meet color requirements and you do not pay a memory cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I were to activate this card's [Trash] effect, does it have a color requirement or memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, activating an effect from the trash is different from using an option card, so they would not trigger.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Trash] effect, do \"When you use an option card\" effects trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that, as long as the cards with a [Xros Heart]/[Blue Flare]\u00a0trait have different card numbers, there is no upper limit to the cards you can use for a DigiXros.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's DigiXros requirements say \"\u221e Digimon cards with a [Xros Heart]/[Blue Flare]\u00a0trait & different card numbers,\" what does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If there are 0 cards, it is not considered a DigiXros.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: The number of cards in the DigiXros condition for this card is \"\u221e cards\", but is it considered DigiXrosed if there are 0 cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. With this effect, you can place only your [Shoutmon] in the battle area as the evolution source.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I would play this card, is it possible to place a [Shoutmon] card in the hand, breeding area, or trash as a digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cards are sent to the trash.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a [Shoutmon] card is placed in this card's digivolution cards by the effect of \"When this Digimon would be played\", what happens to the card in the digivolution cards of the [Shoutmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [BT9-109 X Antibody] is also discarded because it is not discarded by an effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When [Shoutmon] is placed in this Digimon's evolution source with the effect of this card, that Digimon also has [BT9-109 X Antibody] in its digivolution cards, what happens to the X Antibody card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. [DigiXros] can be performed after all \"when... would play\" effects have finished activating. Therefore, you would [DigiXros] after using this card's effect to place [Shoutmon] in its digivolution cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When you place a [Shoutmon] card as a digivolution card this card's effect, can you place another card as a digivolution card first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a [Shoutmon] card is placed in this card's digivolution cards by its effect, the digivolution cards of [Shoutmon] are in the trash. Is it possible to place the digivolution cards of [Shoutmon] as digivolution cards under this card with [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an [Shoutmon] is placed in this card's digivolution cards with the \"When this card would be played\" effect, is it possible to place a card with the same card number as that [Shoutmon] for [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If a card has [Xros Heart]/[Blue Flare]\u00a0trait and a different card number it means you can DigiXros without any upper limit.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [DigiXros] condition of \"\u221e Digimon cards that have [Xros Heart]/[Blue Flare]\u00a0trait mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, 0 cards are not counted as performing [DigiXros].\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: The number of this card's [DigiXros] is \u221e, but is it considered DigiXros if it's 0?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the opponent has no suspended Digimon, and a Digimon attacks with this card as a digivolution card, and the opponent's Digimon suspends and blocks with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Does this card's inherited effect take effect at the time of the battle with the opponent's blocking Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You cannot delete your opponent's Digimon, but you can trash a card from your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can you trash a card from your hand for this card's inherited [On Deletion] even if there are no level 3 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will not be able to digivolve including them.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"Your Digimon can't digivolve.\" also prevent effects that digivolve from Tamers and DNA Digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Once per turn, the play cost is reduced by 4, and then the play cost is reduced by -1 for each of this Digimon's digivolution card. For example, if this Digimon has 1 digivolution card and a Digimon card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait is played, the play cost will be reduced by 5.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait is played, what does \"and reduce the play cost by 1 for each of this Digimon's digivolution cards.\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is mandatory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [Start of Your Main Phase], must you place the card that is revealed from the top of your Digi-Egg Deck and all of your Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait as a digivolution card for this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who activated this effect will choose the order. In addition, the order of digivolutiuon cards already underneath it will not be changed, and the cards placed by this effect will be placed as digivolution cards underneath the existing digivolution cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If you place multiple cards on the digivolution cards at the same time for this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, what order are they placed underneath?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's an inherited effect of [Breeding], so it works in the Breeding Area. Also, if you move the Digimon to the battle area, the effect of [Breeding] will not be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's inherited effect activate while the Digimon that has this card as its digivolution card is in the breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will not be able to reduce the play cost. Since the effect of [BT8-071 Psychemon] is not an effect that targets Digimon, it cannot be blocked even if this card is in the breeding area.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the opponent has [BT8-071 Psychemon], does this card's [Your Turn] effect still reduce the play cost of Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, using and activating [BT10-110 Seiken Meppa]'s [Main] effect does not cause a card to be \"placed\" in the Battle Area, so this card's inherited effect does not trigger.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does using [BT10-110 Seiken Meppa] trigger this card's inherited effect to gain memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: [Marcus Damon] will become a Digimon with 3000 DP, but it will still have \uff1cRush\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's effect and choose my [Marcus Damon] that is already treated as a Digimon with 12000 DP and \uff1cRush\uff1e by the effect of [BT13-020 ShineGreymon: Burst Mode], what will happen?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be deleted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] that is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect, is reduced to 0 DP will it be deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since both effects trigger at the same time, the player can choose which effect activates first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name is played, does the [On Play] effect or this card's [Your Turn] effect activates first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For card's [On Play] effect, can I return my own [Kristy Damon] to my hand even if I don't have a [Garudamon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Only you will check the cards in your security without revealing it to the opponent. If there is a card that can be played by this effect you can play it.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving], what does \"search your security\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Shuffle the security without performing \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if there is no red or yellow Tamer in my security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot because your Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name was played before this card became a digivolution card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve into [SaviorHuckmon], can I gain 1 memory from this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since both effects trigger at the same time, the player can choose which effect activates first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name is played, does the [On Play] effect or this card's [Your Turn] effect activates first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [All Turns] effect, when your red or yellow [Marcus Damon] is deleted, can the deleted card be placed from the trash at the top of my security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since both effects trigger at the same time, the player can choose which effect activates first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name is played, does the [On Play] effect or this card's [Your Turn] effect activates first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be deleted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] that is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect, is reduced to 0 DP will it be deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's \"[On Play] [When Digivolving]\" effect, can it play [Omnimon (X Antibody)]/[Gankoomon (X Antibody)] from the digivolution cards of a Digimon in the Breeding Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect and then its DP is reduced to 0 by an effect, is it deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You can only return your own Tamer to the hand for Burst Digivolve.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return an opponent's Tamer to its owner's hand for this card's Burst Digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Marcus Damon] played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect is only treated as a Digimon after it has entered the Battle Area, so Crimson Blaze wouldn't prevent it.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Would [BT8-097 Crimson Blaze]'s \"can't play Digimon by effects\" effect prevent playing a [Marcus Damon] when activating this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Marcus Damon] played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect is only treated as a Digimon after it has entered the Battle Area, so [BT13-102 Keenan Crier]'s effect is not triggered.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Would [BT13-102 Keenan Crier]'s \"When a Digimon is played by an effect\" effect trigger when activating this card's [When Digivolving] effect to play a [Marcus Damon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: In addition to \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, effects such as \"change the target of the attack to this Digimon\" will prevent you from changing the target of your attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's \"this Digimon's attack target can't be switched\" effect differ from the \"This Digimon cannot be blocked\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, if you have a total of 2 Digimon with [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait and a blue Tamer. Can I trash the digivolution cards of different Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect still work when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since these effects are triggered at the same time, you can choose which effect is activated first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is played, in what order does this card's \"[On Play] [When Digivolving]\" effect and [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You can only return your own Tamer to the hand for Burst Digivolve.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return an opponent's Tamer to its owner's hand for this card's Burst Digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this card's effect. The player chooses the cards in their opponent's hand until there are only 8 left and the order they are returned to the deck before returning them to the bottom of the deck.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the cards in my opponent's hand to return to the deck with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Without revealing any cards, the owner of this card chooses cards to remove from their opponent's hand. Then, without revealing any cards, the owner of this card chooses how to order the removed cards and they are placed at the bottom of the deck. Throughout the resolution of this effect, the owner of [BT13-033 MirageGaogamon: Burst Mode] is never allowed to look at any of the removed cards, but the owner of the removed cards is allowed to look at the removed cards at any point before they are returned to the bottom of the deck.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When I activate this card's [When Attacking] effect, what happens to the cards removed from my opponent's hand? Are they revealed to me before going back into the deck? To my opponent? Who decides what order they go into the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"When this Digimon would leave the battle area\" does not trigger for DNA Digivolution.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attempt to DNA digivolve this Digimon and another Digimon, can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect to prevent the digivolution?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect\nmean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you have to reveal a card from your hand. If each player's security total is 6 or less, use the subsequent effects as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are no yellow cards in your hand or if you don't want to increase security, is it possible for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to not reveal a card from hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Because it is a card containing yellow, it is placed above security. You cannot return it to your hand. \n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal a two-color yellow card from my hand with this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, will that card either be placed in security or returned to your hand. Will it be? "
    }
  ],
  "BT13-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When there is only one Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e in my opponent's Battle Area, the Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks, and the opponent's Digimon blocks. If the opponent's Digimon becomes suspended as a result, will this card's inherited effect give it +1000 DP during the battle?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, can I choose to suspend a Digimon and then choose a different Digimon to be unable to unsuspend until the end of the opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, it will not be suspended by this effect, but can still be unable to unsuspend until the end of the opponent's turn.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [On Play] effect of this card, \"until the end of your opponent's turn, 1 of your opponent's Digimon doesn't unsuspend\" target an opponent's Digimon that is unsuspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [On Play] effect to select a Digimon that will be unable to unsuspend until the end of the opponent's turn, can I target it even if it is not a Digimon with 7000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Both effects trigger at the same time, and you can activate them in either order. However, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e does not perform the security checks until all other effects have resolved. So the top card of security will always be trashed first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect trash the top card of security first, or does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e perform a security check if the Digimon deletes an opponent's Digimon in battle and survives?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Since this effect is a [Once Per Turn] effect, it cannot be activated at a different timing on the turn that was already activated (e.g. [When Digivolving].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] [Main] effect activate during the main phase of the same turn as when it digivolved into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] [Main] effect play [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait, does [BT13-007 Yggdrasil_7D6] and this card's reduce the play cost in total?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will. In addition, this effect targets \"all of your Digimon with [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait and all of your green Digimon\", so even Digimon played before this effect is activated they will gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [All Turns] effect, when a Digimon with [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait or green Digimon is played. Does it gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect suspend an opponent's Digmon or Tamer even if this Digimon is unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card's [End of Your Turn] effect mandatory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if your opponent's there is only 1 suspended Digimon and 1 suspended Tamer, they can be counted as 2.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Attacking] effect \"For each 2 of your opponent's suspended Digimon or Tamers\". Does that mean for every \"2 of your opponent's suspended Digimon\" or \"2 of your opponent's suspended Tamers\". If not, how does it work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. It can only return your cards to the hand with \"Burst Digivolve\".\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's Burst Digivolution return the opponent's Tamer to hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card does include itself in the trash.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect include this card among the cards with [Chessmon]\u00a0in its name in the trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] without deleting itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Each Digimon activates its inherited effect once, and only the Digimon that activates it later remains in the Battle Area. An interrupting \"when you would\" effect will trigger and activate only once during a series of effects derived from one effect activation, even if it is not a [Once Per Turn] effect. After the original effect has been activated, it can be triggered and activated again.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: You and your opponent have 1 Digimon with [Sukamon]\u00a0in its name that has this card as a digivolution card. When that Digimon is deleted, what will happen if both of us use the inherited effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your level 6 Digimon is selected as the target of \"By deleting 1 of your Digimon\". Then, if this card's inherited effect attempts to delete the [EX1-073 Machinedramon].However, if [EX1-073 Machinedramon] activates its effect in response, it will not be deleted by the effect of.Because it no longer gets deleted, this card's inherited effect cannot prevent the deletion, the level 6 Digimon gets deleted by the effect of [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame].<br. />As such, because your Digimon was deleted, it can delete an opponent's unsuspended Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the deleted Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a level 6 Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card, and my opponent has [EX1-073 Machinedramon] whose name is treated as [Sukamon]. What happens if I use [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame] to delete both Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] without deleting itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Each Digimon activates its inherited effect once, and only the Digimon that activates it later remains in the Battle Area. An interrupting \"when you would\" effect will trigger and activate only once during a series of effects derived from one effect activation, even if it is not a [Once Per Turn] effect. After the original effect has been activated, it can be triggered and activated again.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: You and your opponent have 1 Digimon with [Sukamon]\u00a0in its name that has this card as a digivolution card. When that Digimon is deleted, what will happen if both of us use the inherited effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your level 6 Digimon is selected as the target of \"By deleting 1 of your Digimon\". Then, if this card's inherited effect attempts to delete the [EX1-073 Machinedramon].However, if [EX1-073 Machinedramon] activates its effect in response, it will not be deleted by the effect of.Because it no longer gets deleted, this card's inherited effect cannot prevent the deletion, the level 6 Digimon gets deleted by the effect of [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame].<br. />As such, because your Digimon was deleted, it can delete an opponent's unsuspended Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the deleted Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a level 6 Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card, and my opponent has [EX1-073 Machinedramon] whose name is treated as [Sukamon]. What happens if I use [BT8-107 Pandemonium Flame] to delete both Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This card's [All Turns] effect is triggered when your Digimon with [Chessmon]\u00a0in its name is deleted, so if its deletion was prevented, it will not triggered.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this suspended Digimon would be deleted, can I activate this Digimon with this card's [All Turns] effect if the deletion was prevented such as by \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, if during the next turn the opponent digivolves from a Digimon with a play cost of 9 or less into a Digimon with an appearance cost of 10 or more. Can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the attack has already been declared, the attack continues.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: While this opponent's card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is active, if the opponent declares an attack with a Digimon with a play cost of 9 or less, and then uses a [When Attacking] to become a Digimon with a play cost of 10 or higher. What happens to the attack in this case?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [All Turns] effect trigger if an opponent's Digimon with [Etemon]/[Sukamon]\u00a0in its name is deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be blocked. \uff1cBlocker\uff1e does not affect this Digimon, so it is not affected by \"cannot be affected by opponent's Digimon\" effects.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is unaffected by the opponent's Digimon's effects due to this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving], if I attack with this Digimon can it be blocked by the opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose not to choose a Digimon to attack. In that case, an attack will not occur.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect not choose an opponent's Digimon to attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can select an opponent's Digimon that has the effect of \"cannot attack\" or an opponent's suspended Digimon, but in that case the target cannot attack, so no attack will occur.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I select my opponent's Digimon with the effect of \"Cannot attack\" or my opponent's suspended Digimon as targets for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, and have them attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since they are triggered at the same time, the [End of Your Turn] effect of the opponent, who is the turn player, is activated first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Will the opponent's Digimon attack with this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, or will the opponent's [End of Your Turn] effect be activated first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. After the opponent's Digimon declares an attack due to the effect of this first Digimon, and after the activating effects triggered by that effect, it becomes the second Digimon's turn to activate, but at that point an attack is still ongoing, so a new attack cannot be declared, and the effect fails. \n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 of this Digimon, can this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect make 2 of my opponent's Digimon attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The opponent will choose.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Who chooses the card to be trashed from the opponent's hand with this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's not a battle, it was deleted by the effect of \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the Digimon that has this card as its digivolution is deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's possible because it's not an digivolving.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: It says that this card cannot digivolve, but is it possible to use a card's effect to make it a digivolution card for other Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect return itself from the trash to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are only 2 cards with \"Gizmon\" in their name, including this card, in the trash, this card's [On Deletion] effect return those cards to the bottom of the deck and removes [Gizmon: AT] from the trash. Can that prevent it from being played?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The opponent will choose.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Who chooses the card to be trashed from the opponent's hand with this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's not a battle, it was deleted by the effect of \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the Digimon that has this card as its digivolution is deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's possible because it's not an digivolving.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: It says that this card cannot digivolve, but is it possible to use a card's effect to make it a digivolution card for other Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect return itself from the trash to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are only 2 cards with \"Gizmon\" in their name, including this card, in the trash, this card's [On Deletion] effect return those cards to the bottom of the deck and removes [Gizmon: XT] from the trash. Can that prevent it from being played?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's not a battle, it was deleted by the effect of \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the Digimon that has this card as its digivolution is deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, put 2 cards in your hand that meet the conditions of [Lucemon]\u00a0in its name or [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait. You can also add 1 [Lucemon]\u00a0in its name and 1 [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait. But you must add as much as you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect reveals 2 cards with [Lucemon]\u00a0in its name or 2 cards with [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait from among the revealed cards. Can I choose to add less cards to hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it is triggered at the same time as the opponent's [End of Your Turn] effect, it will be after the opponent's (the turn player's) [End of Your Turn] effect has activated and effects derived from those activations.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: At what time does [Ravemon] get played at the end of the opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. At the end of your turn, [BT13-092 Ravemon: Burst Mode] is still on top, so this card's [End of Your Turn] effect did not trigger.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If after Burst Digivolving from this card into [BT13-092 Ravemon: Burst Mode]. At the end of my turn, after the [BT13-092 Ravemon: Burst Mode] from Burst Digivolution is trashed can I activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You can search your opponent's hand with this card's [When Digivolving] effect until you trash a cards from your opponent's hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I check which card was added from the top of their security to their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they will not. Since it is \"the opponent's Digimon with the same name as the returned card\", if you return [Greymon] to the deck, only the opponent's Digimon with the name [Greymon] will be deleted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Attacking] effect returns [Greymon] from the opponent's trash to the bottom of the deck, will the opponent's [MetalGreymon]/[WarGreymon] be deleted as well?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Attacking] effect returns a card with \"This card/Digimon is also treated as \u25cb\u25cb\" from the opponent's trash to the bottom of the deck. Is it possible to delete both  Digimon with the same name as that Digimon as well as Digimon with the name \"\u25cb\u25cb\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it was not checked, so the [Security] effect does not activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the card added to the hand with this card's [When Digivolving] effect has a [Security] effect, will that effect be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't have to put the cards in your hand as a digivolution card as they are private information.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If you have a Digimon card with [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait in your hand. Is it mandatory to place the digivolution card of your [BT13-007 Yggdrasil_7D6] in the breeding area with this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For the [All Turns] effect of this card, if there are no opponent Digimon and I have [Agumon]/[Greymon]. Is it possible to gain 1 memory without reducing an opponent's Digimon's DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I played a blue Digimon and its DP became 0 due to an opponent's effect instantly. Will this Tamer's [All Turns] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It must come from your hand\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: For the digimon card placed by this card's [All Turns] effect, does it come from my hand or from the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, draw a card from your deck whenever possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent activates the [Your Turn] effect of this Tamer, do I have to draw 1 card from my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not considered to have been trashed from security.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is revealed from security by the effect of [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)] and trashed, will this card's \"When this card is trashed from your security stack by an effect\" be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the order of the colors doesn't matter, so you can use either yellow/black or black/yellow. \n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Turns] effect be activated even when a yellow-black Digimon is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I made a Black/Yellow Digimon appear, the opponent's effects reduced the DP to 0 instantly and deleted it. In that case, will this Tamer's [All Turns] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who activated the effect of this card. It will be performed if the opponent player does not trash 1 Tamer or Option card from their hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player will gain 1 memory and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate whether it was my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon that was played by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, DigiXros itself is not an effect nor did it cause the Digimon to be played, so even if it was played as an action in the main phase, it will not activate. It can be activated if the Digimon that performed DigiXros was played due to an effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect be activated if a Digimon is played and performed DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who used this card gains memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player gains memory with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect of this card is activated before the security check.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the opponent's Digimon attacks the player and this card is trashed from security by the [When Attacking] effect, does the security check by the attack or this card's \"When this card is discarded from security by effect\" activate first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the total number of security cards for both you and your opponent. For example, if you have 3 security cards and your opponent has 2 security cards, each player's security total is 5 cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What dooes \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" for this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if the number of security checks becomes 0, a security check will not be performed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the opponent's Digimon attacks the player and this card is trashed from security by the [When Attacking] effect. If this card's [Main] effect gives \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e to all of the opponent's Digimon, and the security attack value of the attacking Digimon becomes 0, is a security check performed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"When this card is discarded from Security by an effect\" is not a [Security] effect, so it will activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is trashed from Security by an effect while the opponent is activating the effect \"The opponent's [Security] effects do not activate\", does this card's [Main] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not considered to have been trashed from security.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is revealed from security by the effect of [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)] and trashed, will this card's \"When this card is trashed from your security stack by an effect\" be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if there is no digivolution card it cannot be returned to the hand by this card's effect, and the effect of unsuspending all of your Digimon will not be performed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return my [Leopardmon: Leopard Mode] that does not have a digivolution card to my hand, and unsuspend my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, in that case, since Lv.2 Digimon does not have DP it will be trashed by Rules Processing after the effect has finished activating.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return my [Leopardmon: Leopard Mode] that only has a level 2 Digi-Egg cards as a digivolution card to my hand and unsuspend all my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will not be affected by the [Security] effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon receives the effect \"This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" due to this card, is it also unaffected by the [Security] effects of the opponent's option cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. The \"When this Digimon is suspended, delete all of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost less than or equal to this Digimon\" obtained from this card becomes the effect of a Digimon and is not considered an option card effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For the effect of \"When this Digimon is suspended, delete all of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost less than or equal to this Digimon\". Can the effect of \"This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" prevent it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution conditions cannot be ignored, so only Digimon that meet the digivolution conditions or special digivolution conditions of the [Belphemon: Sleep Mode] in the trash can be digivolve into it.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Main] effect, can I digivolve any of my Digimon into [Belphemon: Sleep Mode] from the trash without paying the cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means that you add up the number of cards in your trash and the opponent's trash, and every 5 cards for that total number. For example, if your trash is 12 and your opponent's trash is 8, the total cards is 20, so the play is reduced by 8.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"Every 5 cards in each player's trash\" means every 5 cards in either your trash and then every 5 cards in your opponent's trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"Destroy 1 opponent's Digimon with a DP of 6000 or less\" becomes `Destroy 1 of the opponent's Digimon with a DP of 7000 or less\", but \"Destroy 1 of the opponent's Digimon with a DP of 13000 or more.\" has a minimum DP of 13000 and is not the upper limit it will remain as \"1 opponent's Digimon with DP of 13000 or higher\".\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's \"[On Play] [When Digivolving] [When Attacking]\" effect is activated while \"Add 1000 to the maximum DP you can choose with DP-based delete effects.\" is active. Will it increase the DP deletion of \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with the 13000 DP or more\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it refers to the Digimon being played having different names from each other but all with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait among them. For example, if the target Digimon has the following digivolution cards [Omnimon]/[Alphamon]/[Alphamon]/[Gallantmon]/[Gallantmon (X Antibody)]. It will leave only one [Alphamon] as a digivolution card. In addition, since the [Omnimon] that activated this effect was not the digivolution card, it is possible to play it with this effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, does it mean that Digimon cards other than the name [Omnimon] and with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait can be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You should either play as much as possible or play none at all.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to play Digimon, can I select only specific cards from among the digivolution cards to be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cards are also trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon appears with this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, it says \"Trash 1 of your Digimon in the breeding area.\" What happens to the digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Digimon in the Breeding Area cannot be targeted by this effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect digivolve Digimon in the Breeding Area into Digimon cards that have the [Dark Animal]/[SoC]\u00a0trait that have been trashed from the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect cannot ignore digivolution conditions, so you can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon card with the [Dark Animal]/[SoC]\u00a0trait is trashed from the hand, can this card's inherited effect cause a digivolution into that card regardless of digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you still have to pay the digivolution cost.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect cause a digivolution without paying the digivolution cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so you can only digivolve into cards that meet digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's effect digivolves into [Greymon] in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of digivolution conditions?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's effect active, if a Digimon is played other than by an effect, can effects reduce that Digimon's play cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect lasts until the end of the turn, so during that time, the evolution cost will be reduced by 1 each time you evolve meeting the conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, if I evolve into a Digimon that meets the conditions and then evolve into a Digimon that meets the conditions again in the same turn, will the second evolution cost be reduced by 1?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This inherited effect does not allow to attack if they're in a state that doesn't allow attacking.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's inherited effect, can a Digimon with this card in its digivolution sources attack even if the Digimon is suspended?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. After \"end of turn\" was reached the first time, the once per turn restriction is still in effect because the turn didn't change. And even if you evolve, the [Once Per Turn] limit will not be reset. Therefore, a second attack from this inherited effect is not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: At the end of my turn, after attacking with this card's inherited effect, my memory became 0 or more due to some effect, and my turn continues. After that, if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution source evolves and becomes unsuspended again at the end of my turn, can it attack again with this inherited effect?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they cannot. At the end of your turn, both instances of this card's inherited effects are triggered at the same time. Determine the activation order, and attack with the first Digimon with this card in its sources. After any [When Attacking] or \"When one of your Digimon attacks\" effects triggered by the attack declaration are activated, before the Reaction/Counter timing starts, you must activate any pending triggered effects, including this card's inherited effect on the other Digimon. But since the first Digimon is still attacking, a new attack declaration can't be made, so the second one will fail to activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are 2 Digimon with this card in digivolution sources, can each of them attack with this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. If your opponent has this Digimon, \"while the memory is 1 or more on the opponent's side\" refers to the time when the memory is 1 or more on your side.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has this Digimon and the memory is 1 or more on my side, does this card's [All Turns] effect mean that I can't play Digimon cards with 6000 DP or less?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it cannot be played.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent a Digimon card with a DP of 6000 or less from being played, even if it's an effect that would play it?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they cannot be played.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent tokens that are treated as Digimon with a DP of 6000 or less from being played?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be played.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [All Turns] effect, even if it was originally a Digimon card with a DP of 6000 or less, if the DP becomes greater than 6000 when it's played in the Battle Area due to some effect, can that card be played?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. If the memory is 1 or more on your side when you would declare the playing of the Digimon, it cannot be played.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has this Digimon and the memory is 1 or more on my side, can I play a Digimon card with DP of 6000 or less if paying the play cost would cause memory to no longer be 1 or more on my side?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The declaration itself of playing such a Digimon is not allowed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has this Digimon and the memory is 1 or more on my side, is it possible for me to pay the Play Cost of a Digimon card with DP of 6000 or less even though the Digimon won't be played?\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A special card that is treated as a Digimon or a Tamer that appears due to an effect. With this card's effect, you can play tokens that are treated as Digimon with the names \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" and \"Umon the Blue Thunder\". For detailed rules regarding tokens, please check the rule manual.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What is a \"token\"?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they're not. The \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" and \"Umon the Blue Thunder\" tokens played by this card's effect do not have a play cost or level, so they cannot be targeted by effects that require them.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Are the \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" and \"Umon the Blue Thunder\" tokens played by this card's effect subject to effects that target \"Digimon with a play cost of X or lower\" or \"Digimon with a level of X or higher/lower\"?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that is possible. If you have either \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" or \"Umon the Blue Thunder\", delete that token and activate \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [All Turns] effect, when you only have either \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" or \"Umon the Blue Thunder\", can you delete that 1 token and activate \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only works once. No matter how many \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" or \"Umon the Blue Thunder\" are deleted simultaneously with this effect, the \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e will only occur once.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e twice if I delete 2 of my \"Amon the Crimson Flame\" or \"Umon the Blue Thunder\"?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When leaving the battle area\" means \"placed in the trash due to deletion\", \"returned to the hand/deck\", \"placed in security\", \"moved to an area other than the battle area\", or \"placed in digivolution sources of another Digimon or underneath a Tamer\".\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does \"when leaving the battle area\" on this card mean?\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate \"This Digimon cannot be blocked\" even if the evolution source of the opponent's Digimon cannot be trashed?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Since this card's inherited effect is a \"When this Digimon would be deleted\" effect, it's activated by interrupting the deletion. Therefore, before the [On Deletion] effect is triggered, the [Gomamon] card with the [On Deletion] effect moves out of digivolution sources, so the [On Deletion] effect doesn't trigger.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card and another [Gomamon] with an [On Deletion] inherited effect are in the evolution sources of the same Digimon. When that Digimon is deleted, can I activate this card's inherited effect to play that other [Gomamon] from evolution sources, and then activate that card's inherited [On Deletion] effect?\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 4-5 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30c1\u30d3\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Vee\" (\u30d6\u30a4) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Vee]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does this card's inherited effect activate during my unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect doesn't refer to [Tsumemon], but to the name of the Digimon on top with this card as its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: What counts as \"another Digimon in play with the same name as this Digimon\"? Does this only count if I have another Digimon in play named [Tsumemon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect was activated before your opponent blocked it. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect was activated before your opponent blocked it. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect was activated before your opponent blocked it. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. They weren't flipped over in a security check, so they don't activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to trash my opponent's Security Cards. Do the [Security] effects on those cards activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 1 or more cards in their security stack. I attack my opponent with this Digimon and its [When Attacking] effect trashes the rest of their security cards, leaving them with zero cards in their security stack. If the attack isn't blocked and my attack is successful when they have zero cards in their security stack, do I win the game?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, play costs can't be reduced to less than zero. You can play the card for free, but you can't gain memory with effects that reduce play costs.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 5 or more Digimon with no digivolution cards in play, meaning this card's effect reduces its cost by 5, to -1. Can I play it by gaining a memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to unsuspend this card if it digivolves while suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If this Digimon attacks, Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and no digivolution cards cannot redirect the attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards\" work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If this Digimon attacks, Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and no digivolution cards cannot redirect the attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards\" work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't use this Digimon's effect to suspend your blue Tamers. The effect only allows you to unsuspend this Digimon when another effect suspends one of your blue Tamers.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon's effect to suspend one of my blue Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is unsuspended during my main phase, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's \"gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if both Digimon are deleted simultaneously, the effects trigger one at a time. When the first Salamon's effect resolves, you add 1 cards to your security stack, bringing the total up to 4. This means the \"3 cards or less\" condition for the second Salamon's effect no longer applies. The second Salamon's effect doesn't activate, and your security stack remains at 4 cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 3 cards in my security stack when 2 copies of this Digimon are deleted at the same time. Do the [On Deletion] effects on both cards activate, bringing my security stack up to 5 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs. After resolving all other When Attacking effects, the attack ends.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon, then use this Digimon's inherited effect to reduce the opponent's Digimon to 0 DP and delete it. What happens to the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to as it has \"you may\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this card's [When Attacking] effect every time I attack with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, does that [On Play] effect activate when the Digimon enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. During checks, it will fight your opponent's attacking Digimon as a Security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card face down on top of my security stack because of its effect, does it become a security card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player chooses which effect to use first between [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] and [BT2-040 Ophanimon]. If Ophanimon is used first Back for Revenge cannot be used. If Back for Revenge is used for then Ophanimon can no longer be used.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] on [BT2-040 Ophanimon] and it gets deleted with [BT2-109 Heat Viper]. What happens?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the [When Digivolving] effect activates separately for each yellow Tamer you suspend, and you get to choose the target for each effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to suspend 2 or more yellow Tamers. Can I choose 2 or more of my opponent's Digimon and give all of them -4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they're treated as activating at the same timing. Previously, multiple activations of ShineGreymon's [When Digivolving] effect were treated as occurring at separate timings, but this was changed as of December 18, 2020.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect two or more times. Are they treated as activating at separate timings?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You resolve all of ShineGreymon's effects first and activate any new pending effects after these effects have resolved. In this case, [BT2-083 Millenniummon] will only be deleted after all 8 of ShineGreymon's effects have finished resolving.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card suspends 8 Tamers. During the first 4 instances, this effect kills [BT2-083 Millenniummon]. Would I be able to use the remaining 4 effects to destroy the revived [BT2-083 Millenniummon]? Or would [BT2-083 Millenniummon] revive after ShineGreymon's effects finish resolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even though the Digimon has less than 4000 DP, you can continue to give it -4000 DP even though its DP is already 0. All Digimon that have 0 DP or less at the end of a ShineGreymon's effect will be moved to the trash at the same time.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Yellow Tamers and my opponent has 2 [ST1-03 Agumon]. Can I use both -4000 DP effects on the same Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Use the effects consecutively one after the time to reduce DP. There is no period for effects to trigger between multiple effects having been activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"activate the following effect\" mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If either a level 5 Digimon card or a green Tamer card are present in the 3 cards you reveal, you get to add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal with this card's effect don't contain both a level 5 Digimon card and a green Tamer card, do I still get to add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's inherited effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, does that [On Play] effect activate when the Digimon enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The Digimon suspended by this effect -- along with all of your opponent's other suspended Digimon -- remain suspended during their unsuspend phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [On Play] effect to suspend an opponent's Digimon. Is that Digimon the only one that doesn't unsuspend during my opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It only prevents suspended Digimon from unsuspending. Any unsuspended Digimon remain that way.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect cause my opponent's unsuspended Digimon to suspend themselves during their next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn't affect Tamers. They unsuspend as normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect prevent my opponent's suspended Tamers from unsuspending during their next unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it remains unsuspended during the battle\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to attack an opponent's unsuspended Digimon. Does the opponent's Digimon suspend itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this is because the effect of [BT2-051 RustTyrannomon] is activated before \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e because the RustTyrannomon's owner is the turn player.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks and deletes a Digimon with \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e. Can this Digimon use its effect to suspend another Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect doesn't refer to [Keramon], but to the name of the Digimon on top with this card as its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: What counts as \"another Digimon with the same name as this Digimon\"? Does this only count if I have another Digimon in play named [Keramon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect doesn't refer to [Kurisarimon], but to the name of the Digimon on top with this card as its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: What counts as \"another Digimon with the same name as this Digimon\"? Does this only count if I have another Digimon in play named [Kurisarimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate from breeding areas.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is in my breeding area when I digivolve it into a [Diaboromon] from my hand. Does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect only allows you to gain 1 memory per turn, no matter how many Digimon are deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If 2 or more of my other Digimon are deleted at the same time, can I gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you may choose not to use it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete a Digimon in my breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete a Digimon in my breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the effect of [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon] and [When Attacking] would be resolved at the same time, the opponent's effect will be resolved first, and then VenomMyotismon's effect will be resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]'s effect is \"[Opponent's Turn] When the opponent's Digimon suspends\". The opponent's Digimon is rested to attack. Which comes first [When Attacking] or the [Opponent's Turn] effect of VenomMyotismon to increase memory by 1? Is it the same timing as [When Attacking]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is triggered as soon as the opponent declares an attack suspending the Digimon. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: Is [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]'s [Opponent's Turn] effect considered a [Reaction] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The effect of this card was not triggered when the attack was declared (which caused the Digimon to suspend), so it cannot be activated. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks and activates an effect that \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e on my Level 7 Digimon that becomes a [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]. Can I use VenomMyotismon's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Even though the effect of [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon] was triggered, the Digimon has lost the [Opponent's Turn] effect of VenomMyotismon so it cannot be activated. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks and activates an effect that \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e on my [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]. Can I use VenomMyotismon's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens are special cards that some effects put into play to represent Digimon or Tamers. This card's effect, for example, plays a token that's treated as a Digimon named [Diaboromon]. For a more detailed explanation of how tokens work, check the official rule manual.\n",
      "question": "Q: What's a token? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect by deleting a [Diaboromon] token when this Digimon is about to be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. this card's [All Turns] effect only takes effect when this Digimon is about to be deleted. You can't use it when a [Diaboromon] token is deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when one of my [Diaboromon] tokens is about to be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The token is considered a Digimon with the specified name, and is deleted. \n",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon and a [Diaboromon] token in play in my battle area when my opponent uses [BT1-084 Omnimon]'s [When Digivolving] effect to choose [Diaboromon]. Are this Digimon and my [Diaboromon] token both deleted due to having the same name? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when this Digimon is about to be deleted in a battle with an opponent's Security Digimon? "
    }
  ],
  "BT2-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [On Deletion] effect only returns this card to play. Any cards that were in its digivolution cards go to the trash. \n",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card from my trash using its [On Deletion] effect, do the cards it had as digivolution cards return to my Battle Area as well? "
    }
  ],
  "BT2-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Tamer's effect is triggered once you declare your attack against another player, and is activated before your opponent uses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. The +2000 DP bonus remains for the turn even if the target of attack changes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with a Digimon, and suspend this Tamer. If my opponent uses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block the attack, what happens to the +2000 DP bonus from this Tamer's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. \"Trash all of the digivolution cards of those Digimon\" is an explanation of what happens to the digivolution cards of the Digimon when it returns to their hand. It doesn't count as trashing digivolution for the purposes of this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: You use an effect that reads \"Return 1 of your opponent's Digimon to their hand. Trash all of the digivolution cards of that Digimon\" to return an opponent's Digimon to their hand. When your opponent's digivolution cards are trashed as a result, can you activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot activate the effect of [BT2-085 Joe Kido].\n",
      "question": "Q: I use \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e while I have this Tamer in play. Can I use the effect of [BT2-085 Joe Kido]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent trashes a digivolution card with one of their effects like [BT5-111 Omnimon X] or \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving Digimon in your breeding area doesn't activate the effect that reduces digivolution cost by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon in my breeding area into a Digimon card with [Tyrannomon]\u00a0in its name. Can I use this Tamer's effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 1? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, each copy of this Tamer may be be suspended to reduce the digivolution cost by 1 each. However, you cannot reduce the cost to less than 0.  (From Card Rulings:ST1-12/Card Rulings:ST2-12/Card Rulings:ST3-12, and Card Rulings:BT1-109)\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have two [BT2-088 Taiga]. Can I use its second effect to reduce the digivolution cost of a Digimon by 2 if I rest both Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as trashing 1 of your opponent's digivolution cards is not a requirement, you get +2000 DP when using this card even when your opponent has no digivoltion cards. From Card Rulings:BT1-090\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when my opponent has no digivolution cards to still get the +2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cards get trashed at the same time the Digimon is returned to the hand. So it gets returned to hand before unsuspending a Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When do the digivolution cards get trashed in the effect of [BT2-096 The Ray of Victory]? Does it get trashed before or after unsuspending a Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect can only be activated against 1 of your opponent's Digimon. You can't use a single copy of this card to reduce the DP of multiple Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 or more cards in hand when I use this effect, can I give 2 or more different Digimon -1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Hoewver, it cannot be taken from your trash by BeeleStarmon's [On Play] effect even if you have 2 Tamers.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my hand, and I have exactly 2 Yellow Tamers. Can I play this card with [BT6-112 BeelStarmon]'s [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be demonstrated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers and a [EX2-003 Viximon] in my Digimon's digivolution cards, will that card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete a Digimon in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can play this card without using its effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Option and not use its effect because it has \"you may\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] was not triggered because it was deleted first.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I delete [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] with [BT2-109 Heat Viper]. Can I use that MaloMyotismon's effect to gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't use this card's effect to digivolve from an [Impmon] in your breeding area.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 10 or more cards in my trash. Can I digivolve an [Impmon] in my breeding area into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my [Impmon] into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers strictly to your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP they control. The effect doesn't check the DP of your Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Attacking] effect refers to \"your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP.\" Does this strictly refer to my opponent's Digimon with the highest DP, or does it refer to when I attack an opponent's Digimon with the highest DP out of all Digimon in play, including my own?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If your opponent has multiple Digimon tied for highest DP, attacking any of them allows you to unsuspend this Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has multiple Digimon tied for highest DP. If I attack any one of them, does this card's [When Attacking] effect let me unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect only lets you unsuspend this Digimon when attacking your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP, regardless of whether it's suspended or not.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon with the highest DP is unsuspended. If I attack their suspended Digimon with the highest DP, can I unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon was already unsuspended before the opponent could use \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Attacking] effect attacks the Digimon with the highest DP, but my opponent uses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, does this Digimon still unsuspend?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Unless the target of the attack is the opponent's Digimon with the highest DP at the time the attack is declared, this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect does not trigger at all, so it won't be pending activation. This card's condition is treated as \"when you attack your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP\".\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent's Digimon that does not have the highest DP. While this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect is pending activation, another effect causes the target of the attack to become the opponent's Digimon with the highest DP. Does the [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, its play cost has been reduced so you can play this card.\n",
      "question": "Q: I am at 0 memory but my opponent has a Digimon with 10,000 DP or more, can I play this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30c1\u30d3\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Vee\" (\u30d6\u30a4) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Vee]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect activates as soon as you target a Digimon and declare an attack\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate in battles against Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If you attacked an opponent's Digimon, it will activate even if the attack is blocked. However, if you attacked the opposing player, it won't activate if blocked and a battle with the opposing player's Digimon occurs.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate in battles when it is blocked by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect did not fulfill its trigger condition. See more in Effect Resolution\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card attacks a player and then one of my effects redirects it to an opponent's Digimon. Does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you only get to add one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either [RagnaLoardmon] or cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may add them both to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include 2 [RagnaLoardmon] cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I add both of those cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect allows you to add both cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a [RagnaLoardmon] card and a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, do I only get to add 1 to my hand and have to return the rest to the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If [RagnaLoardmon] has the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, you can choose to add it for the [Legend Arms] so that there are no [RagnaLoardmon] cards you can add to hand. However, otherwise you must add as much as you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a [RagnaLoardmon] card and a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, can I choose to add 1 of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since this Digimon is treated as both red and yellow during your turn, it can digivolve into a Digimon with a digivolution requirement of \"Yellow, Level 5.\"\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon Digivolve into a Digimon which has a Digivolution requirement of \"Yellow, Level 5?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [Your Turn] effects are not activate in the breeding area, so the card isn't treated as a yellow card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a yellow Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a yellow Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The DP value printed on a card is its original DP. This card's [When Digivolving] effect causes a target Digimon's DP, regardless of what's written on the card, to be temporarily treated as having 1000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"Original DP\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent's Digimon's DP will be overwritten as 1000, and if a -1000 DP effect is being applied to it, its DP becomes 0, causing the Digimon to be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving] effect is used on an opponent's Digimon whose DP has been reduced by 1000 by an effect, what happens to that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect that was used last takes precedence.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I set a Digimon's original DP with this card, and then use another card to set its original DP again. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect prevents the reduction of DP. But it does not prevent its original DP from being set to another number.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be used to set the DP of a Digimon with \"DP cannot be reduced\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Level 2 Digimon has no DP and so its DP can't be changed and it will still be trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's effect to set my opponent's Digimon's DP to 3000 and it gets \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e and becomes a Level 2 Digimon with no DP. Does this card's effect set the Level 2 Digimon's DP to 3000 and stop it from being trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose whether or not to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect if I have either [Durandamon]/[BryweLudramon] in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The relevant card is placed directly under this card, or at the very top of this card's digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, how are either the [Durandamon]/[BryweLudramon] cards in your hand placed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the memory counter moves to 1 or greater on your opponent's side temporarily, if by resolving that effect, the memory counter moves back to 0 or greater on your side, your turn may continue.\n",
      "question": "Q: Paying this Digimon's digivolution cost resulted in the memory counter being placed at 1 or above on my opponent's side. However, the [When Digivolving] effect allowed me to gain 3 memory, putting the memory counter at 0 or above on my side. When this happens, does the turn end?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect is compulsory like [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode]. So, it was already used when the attack was declared and cannot put [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode] to active as the effect was already used on the 1st attack. [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode]'s effect is also compulsory, so both [BT3-027 Paildramon] and [BT3-111 Imperialdrmaon: Dragon Mode]'s effects cannot be used on the second attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve this card into [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode] and attack with it deleting an opponent's in battle and surviving. I unsuspend it with its own effect. When I attack again, can I use this card's effect to unsuspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to  use it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this  card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's  [When Digivolving] effect on a Level 4 Digimon card that's part of this  card's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because the effect is continuous, the moment the Digimon becomes Level 5 or above, the effect no longer applies to the Digimon, and it will lose \uff1cJamming\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [Your Turn] effect result in my Level 4 Digimon with \uff1cJamming\uff1e losing \uff1cJamming\uff1e when Digivolving to Level 5 or above?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't activate this effect when digivolving a card in your breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving this card onto a [Paildramon]/[Dinobeemon] in my breeding area, can I reduce the digivolution cost by 2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It's placed at the top of the security stack, face down.\n",
      "question": "Q: After checking the top security card using this card's effect, if that card cannot be added to my hand, what happens to that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I check my top security card using this card's effect and add it to my hand, do I have to reveal it to my opponent?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e if you add a security card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 cards left in my security stack, can I still \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e as a result of this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the latter half of the effect, \"Look at the top card of your security stack. You may add that card to your hand to trigger-\" can still be activated even if you have 0 cards in your deck and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e cannot be resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 cards left in my deck, can I still look at one of my security cards and add it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since this Digimon is treated as both yellow and blue during your turn, it can digivolve into a Digimon with a requirement of \"Blue, Level 5.\"\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon digivolve into a Digimon with a digivolution condition of \"Blue, Level 5\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [Your Turn] effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a yellow card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a blue Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a blue Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the moment your Digimon gains a digivolution card, it no longer counts as a \"Digimon with no digivolution cards,\" and loses \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I digivolve one of my Digimon that currently has no digivolution cards, does its \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e immediately disappear?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT3-040 Shakkoumon]'s effect allows it to be played as a Blue Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play [BT3-040 Shakkoumon] while I have [BT1-086 Matt Ishida] does its effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when moving a card from your trash to your security stack, you must show the card to your opponent so they can confirm it's a yellow Digimon card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's effect to place a yellow Digimon card from your trash on your security stack, do I need to show that card to my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you end up with 4 or more security cards, the Digimon will have -6000 DP for the duration of the turn in which the effect was activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give my opponent's Digimon 6000 DP. Later in the turn, I end up with 4 cards in my security stack. Does the -6000 DP effect go away?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can still lose memory. The stated effects above are also mandatory.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play when I activate the effect on a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still lose memory from effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in play and use the effect of a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. Does my opponent still gain memory from my card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Terriermon's effect is no longer active when MaloMyotismon's effect resolves.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have [BT3-046 Terriermon] in play and my opponent has [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]. My opponent plays [BT2-077 Kimeramon] and deletes 1 of their Digimon and Terriermon. Does my opponent gain memory with [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, that Tamer's inherited effect is treated as a Digimon's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with [BT7-087 Koji Minamoto] in its digivolution cards. Does my opponent gain memory from that Tamer's effect when I have this card in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: The cards I reveal with this effect include only a level 5 or level 6 Digimon, not both. Can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Its [Your Turn] effect is only active when this card is in play in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to suspend an opponent's Digimon for its own \uff1cDigisorption -3\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this Digimon, can I suspend 2 of my opponent's Digimon when I digivolve into 1 Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I do not have any unsuspended Digimon, can I still suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon for \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Using this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I prevent my opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during my opponent's next unsuspend phase by applying this effect to it while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you still get BanchoStingmon's effect. \uff1cBlocker\uff1e happens after all [When Attacking] effects and BanchoStingmon's effect keeps the changes for the turn. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent blocks [BT3-058 BanchoStingmon]. Do I still get its effect off?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. This effect behaves the same way as an effect that reads \"When this Digimon attacks one of your opponent's Digimon with 12000 DP or more\". As such, the requirement for 12000 DP or more is checked at the time the attack is declared and determines whether or not the effect triggers. After the effect has triggered, this requirement does not impact the effect's activation.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent's Digimon with 12000 DP or more with this Digimon, then one of my effects reduces that Digimon's DP to be under 12000. Does this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still use BanchoStingmon's effect if the attack target's DP decreases before BanchoStingmon's effect activates as long as it was 12000 DP when it was targeted for the attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have activated [BT1-104 Golden Ripper] and attack with [BT3-058 BanchoStingmon]. If I attack with this card and use [BT1-104 Golden Ripper]'s effect to decrease the attack of the attack target from 12000 DP to 10000 DP before I use its effect, can I use this card's effect to give it 7000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect did not fulfill its trigger condition.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card attacks a Digimon with less than 12000 DP and then one of my effects increases it to 12000 DP or more afterwards. Can I use this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can still lose memory. The stated effects above are also mandatory.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play when I activate the effect on a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still lose memory from effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in play and use the effect of a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. Does my opponent still gain memory from my card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Chuumon's effect is no longer active when MaloMyotismon's effect resolves.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have [BT3-061 Chuumon] in play and my opponent has [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]. My opponent plays [BT2-077 Kimeramon] and deletes 1 of their Digimon and Chuumon. Does my opponent gain memory with [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, that Tamer's inherited effect is treated as a Digimon's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with [BT7-087 Koji Minamoto] in its digivolution cards. Does my opponent gain memory from that Tamer's effect when I have this card in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you only get to add one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either [RagnaLoardmon] or cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may add them both to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include 2 [RagnaLoardmon] cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I add both of those cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect allows you to add both cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a [RagnaLoardmon] card and a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, do I only get to add 1 to my hand and have to return the rest to the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If [RagnaLoardmon] has the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, you can choose to add it for the [Legend Arms] so that there are no [RagnaLoardmon] cards you can add to hand. However, otherwise you must add as much as you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a [RagnaLoardmon] card and a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, can I choose to add 1 of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: In response to this Digimon attack, an opponent\u2019s Digimon cannot redirect this Digimon's attack when activating the \uff1cBlocker\uff1e effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card reads, \u2018This Digimon is unblockable.\u2019 What exactly does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon can still be suspended but the attack will not be redirected.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent still suspend their Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Card text that specifically specify \"delete,\" such as \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon,\" can't be used to delete your cards with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. They can still be deleted by losing a battle or being reduced to 0 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" on this card's [All Turns] effect refer to, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can still lose memory. The stated effects above are also mandatory.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play when I activate the effect on a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still lose memory from effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in play and use the effect of a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. Does my opponent still gain memory from my card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Gazimon's effect is no longer active when MaloMyotismon's effect resolves.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have [BT3-077 Gazimon] in play and my opponent has [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]. My opponent plays [BT2-077 Kimeramon] and deletes 1 of their Digimon and Gazimon. Does my opponent gain memory with [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, that Tamer's inherited effect is treated as a Digimon's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with [BT7-087 Koji Minamoto] in its digivolution cards. Does my opponent gain memory from that Tamer's effect when I have this card in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it. This Digimon is not deleted if you do not pay 3 memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attacking Digimon was deleted, so the attack ends. However, your opponent's \"when your opponent's Digimon attacks\" effects and effects that activate at the [Counter] timing will activate before the attack ends.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. When this Digimon is deleted after this, what happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. After this Digimon is deleted, its other [When Attacking] effects can't be activated. You can, however, activate other [When Attacking] effects prior to activating this card's [When Attacking] effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but can I still activate any [When Attacking] inherited effects on this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] is in play when this card is deleted, so you gain 1 memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but do I gain a memory from [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] 's \"[All Turns] When another Digimon is deleted, gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you do not have to delete this card. (See more in Optional and Mandatory Effects\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, if I don't play a [MaloMyotismon] do I still have to delete it because it is separated by a \"Then,\" clause?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it. This Digimon is not deleted if you do not pay 3 memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attacking Digimon was deleted, so the attack ends. However, your opponent's \"when your opponent's Digimon attacks\" effects and effects that activate at the [Counter] timing will activate before the attack ends.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. When this Digimon is deleted after this, what happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. After this Digimon is deleted, its other [When Attacking] effects can't be activated. You can, however, activate other [When Attacking] effects prior to activating this card's [When Attacking] effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but can I still activate any [When Attacking] inherited effects on this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] is in play when this card is deleted, so you gain 1 memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but do I gain a memory from [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] 's \"[All Turns] When another Digimon is deleted, gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you do not have to delete this card. (See more in Optional and Mandatory Effects\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, if I don't play a [MaloMyotismon] do I still have to delete it because it is separated by a \"Then,\" clause?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It happens after resolving the Option card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's inherited effect to delete an opponent's level 3 Digimon. Does this happen before or after resolving the Option card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the opponent's Digimon is level 3 at the time the LadyDevimon's efffect resolves, you can delete it with this card's inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e, like [BT2-105 Spider Shooter], to reduce an opponent's level 4 or greater Digimon to level 3. Can I then use this card's inherited effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I don't have a level 4 or lower purple or yellow Digimon card in my trash, do both players still trash the top card of their security stack from this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do the [Security] effects on cards trashed by this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, just because there are no security cards to trash doesn't mean you win the game.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect when my opponent has an empty security stack, do I win the game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If one of the players have cards in their Security stack, that player would still trash a card from that Security stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: If one or both players have empty security stacks, can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to play a level 4 or lower purple or yellow Digimon card from my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The card's Japanese text specifes \"you may\" (\u3067\u304d\u308b). This effect is similar to other effects that allow you to choose whether or not to play a Digimon, such as those written as \"you may pay <...> without paying its energy cost.\"\n",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [When Digivolving] effect to trash cards from both players' security stacks, can I choose not to play a purple or yellow Digimon card with a level of 4 or less from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You gain the memory after  resolving the Option card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain +2 memory from  this card's [Your Turn] effect before or after resolving the Option card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though Lilithmon's effect was triggered its effect cannot be activated unless Lilithmon is in the battle area. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: I activate [BT2-109 Heat Viper] to destroy Lilithmon and my opponent's Digimon. Does Lilithmon's effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect was not active when the Option card was used.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon in play, and use [EX2-070 Digivolution Plug-In S] to digivolve a Digimon into this card. Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both you and your opponent's Digimon were deleted, so you gain two memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon in play when one of my other Digimon attacks, deletes an opponent's Digimon, and is deleted in return. Do I gain two memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Security Digimon aren't considered to be Digimon, so you don't gain any memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 1 memory from this Digimon's effect when a Security Digimon is deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the +1 memory effect activates twice, earning you two memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 of this Digimon in play when one of my other Digimon is deleted. Do I gain two memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects activate simultaneously, so the turn player gains a memory first, followed by the non-turn player gaining a memory, returning the memory gauge to its original position.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent and I both have this Digimon in play. If another Digimon is deleted, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon need to be in the Battle Area to activate their effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks an opponent's Digimon and both Digimon end up being deleted, can I gain a memory off this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If your opponent deletes a Digimon with [BT2-013 Growlmon] first and then \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on the level 7 Digimon. MaloMyotismon's effect does not trigger because it did not see the effect. If your opponent uses [BT3-064 TiaLudomon] first then MaloMyotismon's effect triggers and activates. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a level 7 Digimon with [BT3-064 TiaLudomon] and [BT2-013 Growlmon] against my level 7 Digimon that has [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] underneath it. What happens?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you only get to add one card to your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either a blue or green Digimon card, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may add them both to your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include 2 multi-coloured Blue-Green Digimon cards, can I add both of those cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to add the Blue-Green Digimon as a Blue Digimon so that there are no other Green Digimon to add.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a Blue-Green Digimon card and a single-coloured Blue Digimon card, can I choose to add just 1 of them to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to add the Blue-Green Digimon as a Green Digimon so that there are no other Blue Digimon to add.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a Blue-Green Digimon card and a single-coloured Green Digimon card, can I choose to add just 1 of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Security Digimon aren't considered to be Digimon, so this Tamer's effect doesn't activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: My green or blue Digimon deletes an opponent's Security Digimon in battle and survives. Can I suspend this Tamer to gain a memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter how many Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e you have, you only gain 1 memory from this Tamer's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e in play, do I gain memory for each one?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After you resolve the Option card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When do I gain a memory from this card's effect? Before I resolve an Option card, or after?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, activating a [Security] effect is not the same as using an Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect trigger when I activate a [Security] effect of an Option?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card only prevents the [Security] effects on Option cards from being activated. [Security] effects on Digimon and Tamer cards activate as normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent the [Security] effects on checked Digimon and Tamer security cards from activating?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent my Digimon from being deleted when it loses a battle against my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only prevents Digimon from being deleted as a result of battle. [When Attacking] effects, other card effects, and being reduced to 0 DP will still delete Digimon as normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent me from deleting an opponent's Digimon using a [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you don't have a green Digimon in play when you resolve the card's effect, you can't resolve the part of the effect that requires you to have a green Digimon in play.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I play a green Digimon. Can I suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, while you can play this card from your hand if you have a Blue Digimon in your Breeding Area. The effect of the card does not check the Breeding Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Green Digimon in my Breeding Area. Can I use this card's effect to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent chooses. If they decide not to trash any security cards, the player who used this card receives the benefits of the \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When using this card, does my opponent get to decide whether or not they trash one of their security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Your opponent doesn't have a security card to trash, which means you get the \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e effect automatically.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if my opponent's security stack is empty?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. They weren't flipped over in a security check, so they don't activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's to trash my opponent's Security Cards. Do the [Security] effects on those cards activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve from a Digimon that was suspended by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect only applies when digivolving a Digimon that's already green.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the same turn I used this card, I digivolve a nongreen Digimon into a green Digimon. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As long as you're digivolving from a green Digimon, the effect applies.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the same turn I used this card, I digivolve a green Digimon into a non-green Digimon. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: During the turn I used this card, I activate an effect that involves digivolving for a cost. Can I use this card's effect to suspend a Digimon and reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Since the card doesn't specify breeding areas, the effect doesn't apply to Digimon there.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does activating this card's effect also reduce the digivolution cost of cards in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve on top of a tamer using the effect of [BT6-049 Arbormon], can I use this card's effect to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. (Note: This is a rule change implemented on 2023/07/24. Prior to that, the answer was \"no\".)\n[5]",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend the tamer digivolving for the effect of [BT6-049 Arbormon] to reduce the memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you don't have a blue Digimon in play when you resolve the card's effect, you can't resolve the part of the effect that returns your opponent's suspended Digimon to their hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card, then play a blue Digimon later in the turn, can I return an opponent's suspended Digimon to its owner's hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, while you can play this card from your hand if you have a Green Digimon in your Breeding Area. The effect of the card does not check the Breeding Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Blue Digimon in my Breeding Area. Can I use this card's effect to return 1 of my opponent's suspended Digimon to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates this card's security effect. Can I attack my opponent's security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's security effect affects all of your opponent's Digimon, including Digimon that enter the Battle Area after the effect is activated. (See more in Effect Resolution#Global Effects)\n",
      "question": "Q: After my opponent activates this card's security effect, they use [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa] to move a Digimon from their breeding area to their battle area. Can that Digimon attack me immediately?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not return to the bottom of the deck because [BT3-105 Breath of the Gods] prevent it from happening.\n",
      "question": "Q: I activate [BT5-109 Mega Digimon Fusion!] and [BT3-105 Breath of the Gods] on a Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e then digivolve the Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e into a level 7 Digimon, does the level 7 Digimon return to the bottom of the deck at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect prevents the reduction of DP. But it does not prevent its original DP from being set to another number.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can [BT1-105 Blast Fire] to set the DP of the Digimon targeted with this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if the Digimon has both \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and \uff1cReboot\uff1e, the card's effect can only be used once to grant \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card give \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e to a Digimon with both \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and \uff1cReboot\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon that loses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e also loses \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, as it is no longer affected by this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e to one of my Digimon, but if it digivolves into a Digimon without \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e, what happens to the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it gives \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e to new Digimon that get \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e during the turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon without either \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e. If I digivolve into a Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e, does it gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e causes it to become a Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less, you can delete it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card on one of  my opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 5 or more, and \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e causes it to become a Digimon with a play cost of 4. Can I use this card's effect to delete that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do, you delete the Digimon even though didn't \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to delete an opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less that doesn't have any digivolution cards, or on an opponent's level 3 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Its digivolution cards don't return to play, and remain in the trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon affected by this card was deleted. What happens to its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It loses all effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon affected by this card comes back into play after being deleted, does it retain any effects that were on it prior to deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon affected by this card comes back into play after being deleted, can it attack that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player chooses which effect to use first between [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] and [BT2-040 Ophanimon]. If Ophanimon is used first Back for Revenge cannot be used. If Back for Revenge is used for then Ophanimon can no longer be used.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] on [BT2-040 Ophanimon] and it gets deleted with [BT2-109 Heat Viper]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Diaboromon token cannot be played again because it was removed from the game when it was deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this effect targeting a [Diaboromon] Token. What happens when it is deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't activate this effect when digivolving a card in your breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving this card onto a [Paildramon]/[Dinobeemon] in my breeding area, can I reduce the digivolution cost by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect is compulsory like [BT3-027 Paildramon]. So, [BT3-027 Paildramon]'s effect unsuspends it at the beginning of the attack. This card's effect then cannot be used to unsuspend itself. However, the effect was still activated as it was compulsory. So both [BT3-027 Paildramon] and [BT3-111 Imperialdrmaon: Dragon Mode]'s effects cannot be used on the second attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve this card onto [BT3-027 Paildramon] and attack with it deleting an opponent's in battle and surviving. I unsuspend it with its own effect. When I attack again, can I use this card's effect to unsuspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s inherited effect activates even outside the respective \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activation timings.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in the digivolution cards of a Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e with the timing of [On Play], [When Digivolving] or other timings, does this card\u2019s inherited effect not activate outside those timings?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's inherited effect is applied even if the Digimon doesn't have enough digivolution cards to activate \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is a digivolution card of a Digimon that has \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, but that Digimon does not have the required number of digivolution cards to activate its \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, does this effect not activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card did not have \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e at the time of being deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 9 cards in Trash, and my Digimon with this card as a digivolution card is deleted. That Digimon along with this card as a digivolution card was then sent to Trash due to being deleted, giving me 10 or more Trash. Does this card's \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon that was deleted has \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e at the time of deletion. As long as the Digimon is still in the trash it can be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 10 or more cards in my trash and a Digimon with this card as a digivolution card is deleted in battle. Before this card's effect has a chance to activate, another effect activates and reduces the number of cards in my trash to 9 or less. Does this card's \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activates. It is triggered after the whole \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect is resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, when does this card return to hand: before or after the additional effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals a Digimon card with [Hybrid] and a red Tamer card from my deck. Can I add both cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must add both cards to your hand. This card's Japanese text does not specify \"or\" in its card text.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals a Digimon card with [Hybrid] and a red Tamer card from my deck. Can I add only 1 of the cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you add that card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either [Hybrid] or a red Tamer card, can I add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from a LV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Red Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Red-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from aLV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30f4\u30ea\u30c8\u30e9\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Greymon\" (\u30b0\u30ec\u30a4\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Greymon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even you have have both a Hybrid form Digimon card and a Red Tamer card in its digivolution cards, it only gets +4000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon has both a Hybrid form Digimon card and a Red Tamer card in its digivolution cards, does it get +8000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as [Your Turn] effects only activate in the Battle Area, it is treated only as a Red card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is this card also treated as a Yellow card in Hand, Deck, Trash or revealed from Security Check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as [Your Turn] effects do not activate in Breeding Area, this card is not treated as a Yellow Digimon in Breeding Area, thus unable to digivolve into a Digimon that can digivolve from a Yellow Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this card in my Breeding Area into a Digimon that can digivolve from a Yellow Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if multiple Red or Yellow Tamer are suspended at the same time, as there is only 1 effect timing where Tamers are being suspended, it only gets \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: When 2 of my Red or Yellow Tamers are suspended at the same time, does this Digimon get \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as there are 2 effect timings where Red or Yellow Tamers are suspended, it gets \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e twice, giving it a total of \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: When 2 of my Red or Yellow Tamers are suspended at different effect timings, does this Digimon get \uff1cSecurity Attack +2\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activates. It is triggered after the whole \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect is resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, when does this card return to hand: before or after the additional effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals a Digimon card with [Hybrid] and a blue Tamer card from my deck. Can I add both cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must add both cards to your hand. This card's Japanese text does not specify \"or\" in its card text.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals a Digimon card with [Hybrid] and a blue Tamer card from my deck. Can I add only 1 of the cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you add that card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either [Hybrid] or a blue Tamer card, can I add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from aLV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from aLV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name Garummon (\u30ac\u30eb\u30e0\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Garurumon\" (\u30ac\u30eb\u30eb\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When the condition is met, your opponent cannot choose this Digimon as a target of attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's effect of cannot be attacked on opponent's turn mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect only stops the opponent from declaring an attack on this card, \uff1cBlocker\uff1e will resolve as per normal.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e effect in response to my opponent's attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as no colour is specified by the effect, it activates regardless of the colour of the Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate regardless of the colour of Tamer I have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if this card's [When Attacking] effect does not trash any digivolution card of your opponent's Digimon at all, you do not get the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and Memory +1 effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon attacks, and my opponent has no Digimon with digivolution cards, so the [When Attacking] effect does not trash any digivolution card. Does the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and Memory +1 still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when your opponent has 3 or less cards in hand, there is no plus memory.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I Digivolve into this Digimon, and my opponent has 3 or less cards in hand, does this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect plus any Memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If this Digimon attacks, Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e cannot redirect the attack.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: How does \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon\" work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot this card's effect does not target that Digimon.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e Digimon has the effect \"unaffected by your opponent's Digimon effects\". Can it still block this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you are unable to trash your Security, this effect cannot be used.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 cards in your Security Stack, can I still give my opponent's Digimon -2000 DP from this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect only trash Security cards, it doesn\u2019t not count as you receiving an attack. The game will just continue as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: Regarding this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, if I have 0 cards in your Security Stack at the end of my opponent's turn, do I lose the game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [Security] effect of the card trashed by this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiples of this Digimon in my Battle Area at the end of my opponent's turn, do I trash as many Security as the number of this Digimon I have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose to use it or not.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I use this card's effect as long as it attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you are unable to add your Security to hand, you cannot use this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 cards in your Security Stack, can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Once Per Turn] restriction stops this effect from activating at all in the 2nd attack, including the part where 1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -6000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect to give 1 of my opponent's Digimon -6000 DP, then put this Digimon to Active, then attack again in the same turn, can I give my opponent's Digimon -6000 DP again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Digimon played after the effect's activation also lose DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does [BT4-049 Varodurumon]'s \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect also decrease the DP of Digimon that were played after the activation of its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activates. It is triggered after the whole \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect is resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, when does this card return to hand: before or after the additional effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No you cannot, as this effect specifies to target \"1 of your opponent's Suspended digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect on my opponent's Unsuspended digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect on [Orochimon] itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as no colour is specified by the effect, it activates regardless of the colour of Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate regardless of the colour of Tamer I have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Digimon is LV4 or below, it is suspended regardless of being Played by you or your opponent.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also suspend my digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolving is not Playing, they are not suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect suspend Digimon that digivolve into a level 4 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as moving from Breeding Area is not Playing, it is not suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect suspend level 4 or below Digimon moved from Breeding Area to Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also send digimon already suspended prior to this effect to the bottom of my opponent's Deck as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activates. It is triggered after the whole \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect is resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, when does this card return to hand: before or after the additional effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect apply to [Golemon] itself as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effects for both copies are triggered, but since the cards themselves have been deleted and sent to the trash, they're no longer in the battle area, which means their effects can't be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this Digimon in my battle area, and both are deleted at the same time by an opponent's skill. Do both copies activate their [Your Turn] skills?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect on [Gogmamon] itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The order you return cards in is public information.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to return multiple cards to my deck, do I need to tell my opponent the order I return the cards in? "
    }
  ],
  "BT4-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When this Digimon attacks, regardless of what the attack target is, your opponent player can choose to change the target of that attack to 1 of their Unsuspended digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [When Attacking] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you are.\n",
      "question": "Q: When attacking with this card, am I required to announce the target of attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is not an effect that lets you attack your opponent's Unsuspended digimon. You only attack your opponent\u2019s Unsuspended digimon when your opponent chooses to change the target of that attack to 1 of their Unsuspended digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack my opponent's Unsuspended digimon with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the player who is currently being attacked gets to decide whether or not to switch the target because it says \"your opponent may\" (\u76f8\u624b\u306f...\u3092\u9078\u3079\u308b). If they choose not to, the attack proceeds as it was originally declared.\n",
      "question": "Q: Your opponent attacks with [Blastmon]. If you have an unsuspended Digimon in play, are you forced to switch the target of attack to it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activates. It is triggered after the whole \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect is resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, when does this card return to hand: before or after the additional effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only trash 1 Option card to get Memory +1 in 1 attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, can I trash 2 Option cards from hand to get Memory +2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if multiple Tamers are suspended at the same time, as there is only 1 effect timing where Tamers are suspended, you only get Memory +1.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, when my opponent suspends multiple of their Tamers by using the effect of [BT2-041 ShineGreymon], do I get Memory +1 for each Tamer suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though the effect was triggered it cannot be activated because the Digimon no longer has the effect. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a [BT1-086 Matt Ishida] in play. My opponent has a Digimon with [BT4-084 NeoDevimon] in its digivolution cards. I play a Blue Digimon and then use Matt's effect to remove NeoDevimon from its sources. Can the effect of NeoDevimon be used?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's [On Play] effect specified to target [Cerberusmon] this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I destroy this card itself with its [On Play] effect to get Memory +9?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's [On Play] effect specified to target [Cerberusmon], you cannot choose [Cerberusmon: Werewolf Mode] as the target of this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I destroy another 1 of my [Cerberusmon: Werewolf Mode] to get Memory +9?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the Digimon Played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect also get \uff1cRush\uff1e from this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Digimon that gain \uff1cRush\uff1e from this card's effect keep it after Digivolving, and can attack the turn they come into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon Played from Trash by this card's effect digivolves, can that Digimon still attack with the effect of \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Anubismon gets \uff1cRush\uff1e from its own effect when played from the trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: If [BT4-087 Anubismon] is played from the trash by the effect of [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!], does it get \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Anubismon was not on the field at the time the Digimon was played.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT5-107 Revive from the Darkness!!] to delete [BT4-087 Anubismon] and play a Digimon. Does that Digimon gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, all Digimon played gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [ST6-16 Nail Bone] to play multiple Digimon at the same time. Does only 1 Digimon gain \uff1cRush\uff1e like [EX2-037 Reapermon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they both trigger at the same time. So you can choose which effect to activate first.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my Level 5 Purple Digimon into this card while under the effects of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%], and trash [BT6-078 SkullGreymon]. Can I use the [When Digivolving] effect of this card before the \"when this card is trashed from your hand\" effect of SkullGreymon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No they do not.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do the cards trashed by this cards' [Opponent's Turn] effect activate their [Security] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the player who is trashing chooses 2 cards from their hand to trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Deletion] effect, does the player whose cards in hand are to be trashed choose what to trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as your Security was reduced once, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon in my Battle Area, my opponent's Digimon checks [BT1-107 Holy Wave] from my Security, and I gain 1 card in your Security Stack from the [Security] effect. Although the number of Security I end up with is the same, does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as both Digimon's effect activates, you trash 2 of your opponent's Security cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 of this Digimon in my Battle Area, my opponent\u2019s Digimon performs a Check and reduced 1 of my Security. Do both Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] activate, trashing 2 of my opponent's Security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Security Stack is reduced by being trashed from effects such as [BT2-020 Gallantmon] etc. instead of from Security Check, does this card's effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [Security] effect must be activated before [Opponent's Turn]'s effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I check a card with a [Security] effect. Can I choose to use this card's effect first before the [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The turn can only be passed after the attack, or if you declared not to attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card's [When Digivolving] effect even if the Memory is moved to 1 or more on my opponent's side after digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the restriction of \"Digimon cannot attack on the turn it's Played\" cannot be nullified by this effect, it cannot attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card attack when digivolving from a Digimon that was played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, although you declare an attack from this card's effect first, the attack itself is only resolved after all effects activated from digivolving Digimon are resolved. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, If there are other effects that activate from digivolving Digimon, can I finish the attack before resolving those effects first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon attacks not by the effect of its [When Digivolving] effect, can I target my opponent's Unsuspended digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I pick the same 1 of my opponent's Digimon twice for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, after using it once for the 1st time, can I take some other actions first, then use the 2nd time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Tamer will be able to attack in the same way as a Digimon, and will also receive effects that target Digimon. It will also be deleted in battles with Digimon or Security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect treat this Tamer as a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the DP of this card, which is treated as a Digimon due to the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, is reduced to 0 by an opponent's effect, will it be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, When this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] activates, this card is treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, so when it is suspended, it is considered to meet the conditions \"When this Tamer is suspended\".\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card, treated as a Digimon due to the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, is suspended, this card's [Your Turn] effect of \"When this tamer is suspended\" activate because it's currently a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. The effect of this card is only treated as a \"Digimon\", and when it is placed in the evolution source of another Digimon, it is treated as a Tamer card and the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect that was activated is lost.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card, which is treated as a Digimon due to the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, is chosen for the effect of \"Place 1 Digimon as a digivolution card of another Digimon\". Does that count as \"digivolving from this Digimon\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as no colour is specified, Digimon of any colour gets +1000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 3 or less cards in your Security Stack, do my Digimon of any colour get +1000 DP from this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can use it when digivolving into Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e with any trigger timing.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I only use this card's [Your Turn] effect when digivolving into a Digimon with a \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect with the [When Digivolving] timing?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The order you return cards in is public information.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to return multiple cards to my deck, do I need to tell my opponent the order I return the cards in? "
    }
  ],
  "BT4-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, all attacks and effects are to be resolved before the turn can be passed, the attack is not stopped.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon performs a Security Check from attacking, and I use this card's effect to get Memory +1, putting the Memory to 1 or more on my side. If that attacking Digimon still has Security not Checked yet from \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, does that attack get stopped?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as your Security Stack was reduced once, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Tamer in my Battle Area, my opponent's Digimon checks [BT1-107 Holy Wave] from my Security, and I gain 1 card from my Security Stack from the [Security] effect. Although the number of Security cards I end up with is the same, can I suspend this card to get Memory +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as your Security was reduced once, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Tamer in my Battle Area, and I Play [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi] and activate its [On Play] effect to add a Yellow Card from my Security to Hand, then activate \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e . Although the number of Security cards I end up with is the same, can I suspend this card to get Memory +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Security is reduced by being trashed from effects, like of Digimon like [BT2-020 Gallantmon] etc. instead of from Security Check, does this card's effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect when I reduce my Security Stack by my own card's effects like [BT4-104 Blinding Ray] etc?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [Security] effect must be activated before [All Turns]'s effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I check a card with a [Security] effect. Can I choose to use this card's effect first before the [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if your opponent does not declare to use their \uff1cBlocker\uff1e effect to block that attack, you do not get Memory +3.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon under the effect of this card attacks my opponent's Digimon, do I get Memory +3?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as the target of this effect is all of your Digimon, even Digimon that are put to your Battle Area afterwards also receive the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does my Digimon moved from Breeding Area to Battle Area on my next turn also get \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from this card's [Security] effect on my next turn after it was activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when my opponent does not have any Digimon that are 6000 DP or less to Play a 4 Cost or less Tamer card from my hand without paying its cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they are deleted by effects and not by battle.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon under the effect of this card attacks my opponent's Digimon without digivolution cards, do those of my opponent's Digimon count as being \"deleted by battle\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This card's obtained effect is resolved before the declaration of Blocking. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: On my opponent's turn, my opponent uses this card, and attacks my Digimon without digivolution cards. Can I use my other Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to prevent my attacked Digimon from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: On my opponent's turn, my opponent uses this card, and attacks my Digimon without digivolution cards. Can I use my other Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to start a battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's effect must be resolved before declaration of \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, even if you Block with a Digimon with no digivolution cards, the effect does not happen, and your Blocking Digimon enters battle.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: On my opponent's turn, my opponent uses this card, and attacks my Digimon. I then activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e of my other Digimon that has no digivolution cards. Does my Digimon that Blocked get deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that Digimon with higher DP was deleted before battle happens, the attacking Digimon is not deleted. So the battle ends.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon under the effect of this card attacks a Digimon without digivolution cards that has higher DP than my Digimon. Does my attacking Digimon lose the battle and get deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as \uff1cPiercing\uff1e requires your Digimon to destroy your opponent's Digimon in battle and survive, if your opponent's Digimon was deleted by this card's effect instead, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e does not activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e under the effect of this card attacks my opponent's Digimon without digivolution cards, does its \uff1cPiercing\uff1e effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that Digimon was deleted by effects and not battle, your Digimon is not unsuspended.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with effects that requires my Digimon to destroy my opponent's Digimon in battle to put itself to Active, like [BT1-112 Dimension Scissor] etc, attacks my opponent's Digimon without digivolution cards and destroys it by this card's effect, do I put my Digimon to Active?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon is not deleted, as its trigger condition of \"declaring an attack on a Digimon with no digivolution cards\" was not fulfilled. The effect cannot be used to delete the Digimon. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon under this card's effect attacks my opponent's Digimon with 1 digivolution card, then my Digimon's other [When Attacking] effect trash that 1 digivolution card, what happens to my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Mother D-Reaper was returned to the bottom of your Digi-Egg Deck instead so the condition of \"return 1 Digimon to your hand\" was not fulfilled.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card returns my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] to my hand, can I return my opponent's Digimon to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The Token was removed from play instead so the condition of \"return 1 Digimon to your hand\" was not fulfilled.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card returns a Token to my hand, can I return my opponent's Digimon to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that Digimon was already returned to your opponent's hand by this card's effect, you cannot activate this effect again to return that Digimon to the bottom of the deck instead.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 7 cards in hand when I used this card, resulting in my opponent having 8 cards in hand. Does the targeted Digimon that was returned to my opponent's hand, now return to the bottom of the deck instead?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as trashing the top 1 card of your Security Stack is not a requirement, you get Memory +2 when using this card even with 0 cards in your Security Stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I have 0 cards in my Security Stack to get Memory +2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it was not deleted, the effect does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the Digimon added to the Security Stack by this card's effect activate its [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can do either.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I don't have any Digimon, to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon, or when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon, to unsuspend 1 of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right. Even if your Digimon's original DP is not 16000, and only becomes 16000 or more after receving this effect's +3000DP, it gets \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon becomes 16000DP or more after receiving this card's +3000DP effect, does it then get \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the Digimon was selected for it to get \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from this card's effect, those effects will not be lost until the end of you opponent's next turn even if its DP is reduced to 15000 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon that gained \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from this card's effect has its DP reduced to 15000 or less by other effects, does it then lose its \uff1cBlocker\uff1e,\uff1cReboot\uff1e,\uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if your Digimon's DP is not at 16000 or more from resolving this card's effect, it does not get \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon's DP is 15000 or less after receiving the effects of this card. Its DP is then raised to 16000 or more by other effects. Does it get \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e at this point of time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have 1 Digimon with [D-Brigade] type, you can target your opponent's Digimon with Play Cost of 4 or less for this card's effect.If you have 2 Digimon with [D-Brigade] type, you can target your opponent's Digimon with Play Cost of 5 or less for this card's effect.In this manner, you add 1 to the selectable range of Play Cost of your opponent's Digimon you can target for this card's effect for each [D-Brigade] type Digimon you have.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"For each [D-Brigade] type Digimon you have, +1 to the Play Cost you can choose for this effect.\" mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as Option cards are only put to Trash after resolving their effects, this card itself is not counted.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in Trash when I use this card, then this card becomes the 10th card in my Trash. Do I get Memory +1?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-114": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I unsuspend [AncientGarurumon] this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, AncientGarurumon's Japanese text does not specify \"you may\" (\u3067\u304d\u308b). Effects that specify \"up to\" must also choose at least 1 card.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have suspended Digimon that can be targeted with this card's effect, am I required to unsuspend 1 or more of them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the effect must be activated on the first time you declare an attack with this card. You must also suspend at least 1 Digimon. If you don't have anything to unsuspend the effect was activated and the [Once Per Turn] effect cannot be activated again.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks and is unsuspended by another effect first. Then I declare this card's [When Attacking] effect but don't unsuspend anything. Can I use its [When Attacking] effect on the second attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is also included.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's interited effect also include the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards itself as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, both Digimon are deleted at the same time, and that Digimon is already to be deleted from having 0 DP, so you cannot do that.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and another of my Digimon is reduced to 0 DP at the same time by 1 of my opponent's effects. At this point of time, does this card's inherited effect give itself +2000 DP and stop itself from being deleted due to having 0 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only revealed either a Digimon card with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name or a Digimon card with [Omnimon]\u00a0in its name, you still add either of them to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if I do not reveal both a card with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name and a card with [Omnimon]\u00a0in its name, does that mean I don't get to add them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is an effect that nullifies the effects that reduces the cost to digivolve such as \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e, or [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!], etc. Even if your opponent activates those effects, they are unable to reduce the cost to digivolve, and must pay the digivolution cost as written on the cards to digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's effect of [cannot reduce digivolution costs] mean exactly?\u00a0"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this card in play, can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e of a card in my hand to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can, as the effects of cards like [BT2-111 Beelzemon] do not reduce the digivolution cost, but allows you to digivolve by paying a specified cost while ignoring digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this card in play, can I use effects of [Digivolve for X cost while ignoring the Digivolution requirements] like [BT2-111 Beelzemon] etc?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still suspend a Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e even though you can't reduce the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [BT5-008 Gaossmon], can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e to suspend a Digimon even though the cost is not reduced?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that card's effect does not \"reduce\" it \"sets\" the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve into [BT7-040 Rasenmon] for a lower digivolution cost if I have this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only revealed either a Digimon card with [Shoutmon]\u00a0in its name or a Digimon card with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, you still add either of them to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if I do not reveal both a card with [Shoutmon]\u00a0in its name and a card with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, does that mean I don't get to add them to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as [BT5-019 Shoutmon DX] can meet either condition of \"Digimon card with [Shoutmon]\u00a0in its name\" and \"Digimon card with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, you can add them both to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if I revealed 2 [BT5-019 Shoutmon DX] from among the 5 revealed cards, can I add them both to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No,you cannot Digivolve your [Shoutmon] in Breeding Area into this card with this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve my [Shoutmon] in Breeding Area into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards has the \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect, it gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e even if not attacking using \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's inherited effect, does that Digimon not gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e if it's not attacking by using \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my [Shoutmon] into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect requires you to be currently attacking with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon has an effect \"[When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\" but is not currently activating the effect of \uff1cBlitz\uff1e. Is it possible to attack my opponent's unsuspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: As the effect lasts the turn, you get +4000 DP in total.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon attacks, I use its [When Attacking] effect to trash a 3000 DP Red Digimon card from my hand to give this Digmon +3000 DP. On the same turn, this Digimon is able to make a 2nd attack due to other effects. I use the effect a 2nd time to Discard a Red 1000 DP Digimon card from my hand. Does this Digimon now get +4000 DP in total, or only +1000 DP from the last card trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Level 5 Digimon into this Digimon, can I put a Red Level 4 or below, or a Level 7 Digimon card from my hand to the top most digivolution cards card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes a Level 3 Digimon. The digivolution cards under this Digimon remain as they are, and their inherited effects can still activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to put a Level 3 Digimon card on the top of its digivolution cards. This Digimon then receives the effect of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e and is trashed. What happens to this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card itself is trashed due to \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e, then this Digimon becomes a Level 3 Digimon. As \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e is unable to trash any further when the Digimon becomes Level 3, the \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect ends. The digivolution cards under this Digimon remain as they are, and their inherited effects can still activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to put a Level 3 Digimon card on the top of its digivolution cards. This Digimon then receives the effect of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e. How do I resolve this?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you chose to resolve \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first, you will suspend this Digimon, and declare attack. The actual attack will only happen after all other [When Digivolving] effects have finished resolving. It will activate after your [When Attacking] effects but before your opponent's [Reaction]/[Counter] Timing effects. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Since this card has 2 [When Digivolving] effects, if I choose to resolve \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first, does that mean I resolve the other [When Digivolving] effect after the attack from \uff1cBlitz\uff1e ends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can attack your opponent's unsuspended Digimon due to [ZeigGreymon]'s inherited effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to put [BT5-017 ZeigGreymon] from my hand to the top of this Digimon's digivolution cards. I then activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e to attack. Does [ZeigGreymon]'s inherited effect then allow me to attack my opponent's unsuspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still delete Digimon without doing the first part of the [When Digivolving].\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete Digimon even if I don't place a card on its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if there is a valid target and you have not deleted equal to the number of [ZeigGreymon]/[OmniShoutmon] in its digivolution cards you must delete that target.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attempt to delete less Digimon than the number of [ZeigGreymon]/[OmniShoutmon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only revealed either a Digimon card with [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name or a Digimon card with [Omnimon]\u00a0in its name, you still add either of them to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if I do not reveal both a card with [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name and a card with [Omnimon]\u00a0in its name, does that mean I don't get to add them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is an effect that nullifies the effects that reduces the cost to digivolve such as \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e, or [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!], etc. Even if your opponent activates those effects, they are unable to reduce the cost to digivolve, and must pay the digivolution cost as written on the cards to digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's effect of [cannot reduce digivolution costs] mean exactly? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this card in play, can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e of a card in my hand to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can, as the effects of cards like [BT2-111 Beelzemon] do not reduce the digivolution cost, but allows you to digivolve by paying a specified cost while ignoring digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this card in play, can I use effects of [Digivolve for X cost while ignoring the Digivolution requirements] like [BT2-111 Beelzemon] etc?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still suspend a Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e even though you can't reduce the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [BT5-021 Syakomon], can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e to suspend a Digimon even though the cost is not reduced?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that card's effect does not \"reduce\" it \"sets\" the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve into [BT7-040 Rasenmon] for a lower digivolution cost if I have this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, effects that return Digimon to hand are not treated as trashing digivolution cards, you do not get Memory +1.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon are returned to hand, do I get Memory +1 from this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you trash multiple Digimon's digivolution cards at the same time, you only get Memory +1.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I trash 2 of my opponent's Digimon's digivolution cards at the same time, do I get Memory +2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent trashes a digivolution card with one of their effects like [BT5-111 Omnimon X] or \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The target of that attack is changed to this Digimon and battle happens as per normal. This card's effect stops your opponent from choosing this card as an attack target, so as the user of this card, you are able to change the attack target to this Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon gained \uff1cBlocker\uff1e from other effects. I then activate this Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e against an opponent's Digimon's attack. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use [BT4-090 Chaosmon]'s [When Digivolving] effect to choose this Digimon as the target of attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The attack target will be changed to This Digimon and the battle will happen.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon unsuspended, and my opponent's [BT4-075 Blastmon] attacks. Can I change the attack target to this Digimon due to [Blastmon]'s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, that Digimon does not have [On Deletion].\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has [On Deletion] has an inherited effect, can this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect target it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that Digimon was given [On Deletion] while in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon was given [On Deletion] from its digivolution card's inherited effect, can this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect target it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that Digimon was given [On Deletion] while in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon was given [On Deletion] from an Option card's effect, can this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect target it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if your opponent only have a Digimon with no digivolution cards because of this card's [When Attacking] effect, it gets \uff1cJamming\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has no Digimon with no digivolution cards, but when I attack with this Digimon and its [When Attacking] effect trashes my opponent's Digimon's digivolution cards, resulting in my opponent now having a Digimon with no digivolution cards. Does that attack get \uff1cJamming\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the digivolution cards are lost after the declaration of attack, this card's effect does not interrupt and stop the attack from continuing.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play, my Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e attacks my opponent Player, and the Security Check reveals a [BT1-101 Howling Crusher], and its [Security] effect removed all of my attacking Digimon's digivolution cards. Is that attack now interrupted and ends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's [When Attacking] effects has already finished resolving before this, that attack does not gain \uff1cJamming\uff1e. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e attacks my opponent Player, and a Digimon is Played via its [Security] effect. Since there is now a Digimon with no digivolution cards in my opponent's Battle Area, does my 2nd Check gain \uff1cJamming\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon can still be suspended but the attack will not be redirected.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent still suspend their Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e if they have no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is an effect that nullifies the effects that reduces the cost to digivolve such as \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e, or [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!], etc. Even if your opponent activates those effects, they are unable to reduce the cost to digivolve, and must pay the digivolution cost as written on the cards to digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's effect of [cannot reduce digivolution costs] mean exactly? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this card in play, can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e of a card in my hand to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can, as the effects of cards like [BT2-111 Beelzemon] do not reduce the digivolution cost, but allows you to digivolve by paying a specified cost while ignoring digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this card in play, can I use effects of [Digivolve for X cost while ignoring the Digivolution requirements] like [BT2-111 Beelzemon] etc?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still suspend a Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e even though you can't reduce the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [BT5-033 Cutemon], can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e to suspend a Digimon even though the cost is not reduced?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that card's effect does not \"reduce\" it \"sets\" the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve into [BT7-040 Rasenmon] for a lower digivolution cost if I have this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this Digimon itself is included.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect include this Digimon itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Only 1 Digimon can be targetted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Digimon, can I choose 2 of my opponent's Digimon to get -1000 DP each?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot, as its [On Play] effect has already activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: After Playing this Digimon, I Play another Digimon on the same turn. Do I get to -1000 DP to 1 of my opponent's Digimon one more time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Without showing your opponent, you look at all the cards in your Security Stack. Choose 1 card you want to add to your hand, reveal only that card to your opponent before adding it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does [look at your Security stack...reveal it, and add it to your hand..etc] of this card's effect mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Without performing \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e, shuffle your Security Stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens when there are no cards in my Security Stack that I can add to my hand with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you do not have to add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If you have a [Holy Warrior]/[Warrior]\u00a0trait in Security, do you have to add it to your handif you checked security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to look at your security. If you do not look at security you must still shuffle the security.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to check the security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Security Digimon has 0 DP, a battle still happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Security Digimon revealed during Security Checks becomes 0 DP from this card's inherited effect, is that Security Digimon trashed without battling?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect is activated as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Security Digimon revealed during Security Checks that has a [Security] effect becomes 0 DP from this card's inherited effect, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that card is no longer a Security Digimon the moment it is Played, it does not receive the effects of DP reduction anymore.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Security Digimon that has its DP reduced by this card's inherited effect is Played via its [Security] effect. Does that Digimon still has its DP reduced?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Security Digimon has 0 DP, a battle still happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Security Digimon revealed during Security Checks becomes 0 DP from this card's interited effect, is that Security Digimon trashed without battling?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect is activated as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Security Digimon revealed during Security Checks that has a [Security] effect becomes 0 DP from this card's interited effect, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that card is no longer a Security Digimon the moment it is Played, it does not receive the effects of DP Minus anymore.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Security Digimon that has its DP reduced by this card's interited effect is Played via its [Security] effect. Does that Digimon still has its DP reduced?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates even in Breeding Phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate even if my opponent moves their Digimon from Breeding Area to Battle Area in their Breeding Phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the Security Digimon has 0 DP, a battle still happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Security Digimon revealed during Security Checks becomes 0 DP from this card's interited effect, is that Security Digimon trashed without battling?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect is activated as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Security Digimon revealed during Security Checks that has a [Security] effect becomes 0 DP from this card's interited effect, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that card is no longer a Security Digimon the moment it is Played, it does not receive the effects of DP Minus anymore.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Security Digimon that has its DP reduced by this card's interited effect is Played via its [Security] effect. Does that Digimon still has its DP reduced?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect can choose itself.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, can I choose to put itself on the bottom of 1 of my Green Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The [On Deletion] effect is activated as [Palmon], but since the effect of changing the name is lost when the card is placed in teh trash due to the deletion, this card becomes [Palmon].\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is affected by the effect of [BT11-043 KingSukamon], and this card was renamed to [Sukamon] and then deleted. If there are no other [Palmon] cards in the trash, can this card's [On Deletion] effect be used to place this card under a Green Digimon as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve [BT5-056 Rafflesimon] on top of another [BT5-056 Rafflesimon]. Can I use the [Once Per Turn] effect of the new Rafflesimon if the old Rafflesimon used it before?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect is applied as a Global Effect. If it satisfies the condition afterwards, it gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect, one of my Digimon without \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e becomes a Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, does that Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect is applied as a Global Effect. So if it no longer satisfies the condition then it no longer has the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect, one of my Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e becomes a Digimon without \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, does that Digimon keep the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it has already resolved and applied a Global effect, the Global effect continues applying even after Rosemon leaves the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect, this card leaves the battle area does the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e continue being applied?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only revealed either an [Unidentified] Type Digimon card or a [Arata Sanada], you still add them to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if I do not reveal an [Unidentified] Type Digimon card and a [Arata Sanada], does that mean I don't get to add them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Return that card face down back to the top of your deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, what do I do with the top 1 card of my deck after confirming it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since that Digimon is now a different name, it has lost \uff1cRush\uff1e and cannot attack anymore.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon that has \uff1cRush\uff1e from this card's effect is digivolved into a Digimon with a different name, does that mean that Digimon cannot attack anymore on the turn it was played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It is only other Digimon that share a name that gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I play [BT5-063 Kurisarimon] this turn, and then digivolve it into a new Digimon. Does the Digimon on top of Kurisarimon gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, from the point of time when it's Played, it is treated as a normal Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is a Digimon Played by this card's effect also treated as a Security Digimon in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the outcome of the battle, it is played after the battle ends.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, can the Digimon be Played even if it lost the battle against the attacking Digimon as a Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The timing to Play this Digimon is after its battle with the attacking Digimon. So it is played before the remaining checks happen.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if this was revealed from a Check, but the attacking Digimon still has remaining checks left, is this Digimon Played first, or do the remaining checks finish first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your [Keramon] in your Breeding Area cannot digivolve into this card with this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve my [Keramon] in my Breeding Area into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Played by an effect, it is a special card that is treated like any other Digimon or Tamer With this card's effect, a Token that is treated a s Digimon named [Diaboromon] is played. For more rule details on Tokens, please check the Rule Manual.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What is a [Token]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my [Shoutmon] into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the point of time when you use this \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e,\u00a0 your opponent does not have any Digimon that are 6 cost or Below, or if there are no Digimon that can be deleted by this effect, It refers to a situation where your opponent does not have a Digimon that can be deleted by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect of \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less. If no Digimon was deleted by this effect...\" mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when you use this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, if there is a valid target of [opponen'ts Digimon with 6 Play cost or below], you must delete it. You cannot choose not to activate an effect if there is a valid target.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, and my opponent has a 6 cost or below Digimon, can I choose not to delete that Digimon to trash the top 1 card of my oppponent's Security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it was a valid target of 6 cost or below Digimon, you can target it with this effect, then fail to delete it because of its effect of [cannot be deleted by opponent's effects].\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a 6 cost or below Digimon with the effect [This Digimon cannot be deleted by opponent's effects], and another Digimon without that effect, when I use this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, can I purposely choose the Digimon that has the effect of [This Digimon cannot be deleted by opponent's effect] to trash the top 1 card of my opponent's Security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, no Digimon was deleted by this effect so you will trash the top card of your opponent's Security.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I target my opponent's Digimon for deletion, but it activates an effect that prevents it. Do I still get to trash a card from security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's condition is \"has been deleted by an effect\" and a Digimon being deleted by having 0 DP is a game rule, and not an effect, it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is deleted by being put to 0 DP by my opponent's effects and is deleted. Does this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect does not trigger. This effect behaves the same way as an effect that reads \"When this Digimon is deleted by an effect\". \n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is deleted, but not by an effect. Does its [On Deletion] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, can I return a Level 3 Digimon card that has a [On Deletion] inherited effect to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though the Digimon has [On Deletion], the Digimon card does not have [On Deletion], so it cannot be returned.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is deleted at the same time as another Digimon that gained an [On Deletion] effect from its digivolution cards. Can I add that Digimon card to hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, when I have another Digimon, can I choose which of the 3 effects to activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player can choose which order to activate them in.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have no other Digimon, in which order do I activate the 3 effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  \u25fc Played by an effect, it is a special card that is treated like any other Digimon or Tamer. \u25fc With this card's effect, a Token that is treated a s Digimon named [Diaboromon] is played. \u25fc For more rule details on Tokens, please check the Rule Manual.\n",
      "question": "Q: What is a [Token]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I play this card, can I delete a [Diaboromon Token to reduce this card's Play cost by 12 with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect does not stop the effect from triggering, it only prevents the player from activating the triggered effect. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent the effect from triggering or activating?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect only prevents effects that triggered from a [When Digivolving] timing from activating.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has an effect with double conditions such as [When Attacking][When Digivolving]. Can the effect still activate if it attacks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you choose to resolve the effects of \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first, you will suspend this Digimon and declare attack, then unsuspend this Digimon. The attack itself only happens after any other effects of the same timing are resolved\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, can I choose to resolve \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first to attack, then unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's [All Turns] effects nullifies the effect of it being deleted or returned to hand or deck, it is not treated to have been deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this Digimon's [All Turns] effect, can I use my other Digimon's [When a Digimon is deleted] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e was resolved and as the Digimon is still in play, it can perform security checks.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon deletes a Digimon with \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e in battle while it has [BT3-016 Durandamon] in its digivolution cards. Does the Digimon's security check from \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still happen?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent uses this card's effect to trash a digivolution card. Can I use [BT2-085 Joe Kido]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, after Omnimon prevents the first Retaliation effect. The second Retaliation effect can be activated by the opponent to try and delete it again.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon deletes a Digimon in battle that has 2 copies of the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect from different sources. If this Digimon prevents one of the effects by trashing a level 6, can the other still delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can Play any Purple or Black Digimon card with Play cost of 8 or less that were originally already in your Trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I choose any 2 Purple or Black Digimon card with Play cost of 8 or less in my Trash even if they were not trashed by this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose 1 Black Digimon and 1 Purple Digimon to play with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to play 1 Black Digimon and 1 Purple Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect apply even if my opponent only has 1 Digimon with no digivolution cards and the rest of their Digimon have digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Your opponent has to have a Digimon in their battle area for it to activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect apply when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon in their battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is a \"Do <X> to <Y> effect. As such, it follows the rules detailed in the Detailed Rules. (Found in Effect Resolution/Related Information#Costs)\n",
      "question": "Q: When my blue Digimon attacks, can I suspend this Tamer even if my opponent has no Digimon in the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. [Start of Your Turn] effects are activated before Digimon are unsuspended in the Unsuspend Phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a suspended Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and becomes Active in my Unsuspend Phase, does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the effect says \"you may\", you can choose not to digivolve it.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Your Turn] effect, if my Green Level 5 Digimon attacks and reveals a Green Level 6 Digimon, must I digivolve into that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Your Turn] effect, if 2 or more Green Level 6 Digimon are revealed, can I choose which card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon attacks and digivolves usinig this card's [Your Turn] effect, do I Draw 1 from the Digivolution Bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Your Turn] effect, if I revealed a non-Green Level 6 Digimon, can I digivolve into them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Although you can activate both Tamer's effect in 1 attack, you are to resolve the 2 Tamer's effect 1 by 1\u00a0 and not at the same time. First you suspend the 1st Tamer, reveal the top 3 cards of your deck, and choose a card to digivolve into. After that, you can choose to activate the 2nd Tamer's effect or not. If you digivolved into a Green Level 6 Digimon from the 1st Tamer's effect, even if the 2nd Tamer's effect reveals a Green Level 6 Digimon, you cannot digivolve your now Level 6 Digimon into the revealed Green Level 6 Digimon unless it fulfills the digivolution requirement (Like [BT5-056 Rafflesimon] etc).\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this Tamer, and my Green Level 5 Digimon attacks, can I suspended both Tamers and reveal the top 6 cards of my deck to choose a card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates immediately after you draw the bonus card for digivolving. Even if there are other [When Attacking] or \"When one of your Digimon attacks\" effects, the [When Digivolving] effect activates first as a newly triggered effect. (See more in Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If the Level 6 Digimon I digivolve into with this card's [Your Turn] effect has a [When Digivolving] effect, at what timing do they activate>?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it is already passed timing for [When Attacking] effects to activate, they do not activate,.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the Level 6 Digimon I digivolve into with this card's [Your Turn] effect has a [When Attacking] effect, does that effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  \u25fc Played by an effect, it is a special card that is treated like any other Digimon or Tamer. \u25fc With this card's effect, a Token that is treated a s Digimon named [Diaboromon] is played. \u25fc For more rule details on Tokens, please check the Rule Manual.\n",
      "question": "Q: What is a [Token]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it gives your own Digimon the effect as well.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also give my own Level 3 Digimon the effect of \"[When Attacking] Memory -1\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as both effects are activated separately, there will be a total of Memory -2.\n",
      "question": "Q: If there are 2 of this Tamer in play, when a Level 3 Digimon attacks, does it become Memory -2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving Digimon in your breeding area doesn't trigger the effect to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon in my breeding area. Can I use this Tamer's effect to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve my Red Tamer into a Digimon with the effect of [BT4-011 Agunimon]. Can I suspend this card to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving Digimon in your breeding area doesn't trigger the effect that reduces digivolution cost by 1.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon in my breeding area into a Digimon card with [Greymon]/[Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name. Can I use this Tamer's effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, each copy of this Tamer may be be suspended to reduce the digivolution cost by 1 each.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the second effect of this Tamer stack if there are multiple copies in play in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [ST5-04 ToyAgumon] is not named [Agumon]/[Gabumon]. The effect to play a Digimon does not have \"in its name\" in the card text.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play [ToyAgumon]/[Agumon Expert] with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is meant to have a [Your Turn] effect.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card's printing in BT-05: Booster Battle Of Omni has [Main] as its effect and its RB-01: Reboot Booster Rising Wind printing uses [Your Turn]. Which version is correct?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I put a Red Level 4 or less Digimon card from my hand under the digivolution cards of a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They remain in the digivolution cards. However as it is not a Digimon anymore, the inherited effects do not activate. If that Tamer digivolves into a Digimon again, the inherited effects will activate as per normal.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I put a Digimon card under a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer. That Digimon then receive the effect of \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e and becomes a Tamer card. What happens to the digivolution cards below the Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to place a digivolution card underneath a Token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, but a card will not be placed as a digivolution cards under the Token.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to target a Token with this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, can I choose a different Digimon to Return to Hand instead of the Digimon I chose to trash a digivolution card from?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 Digimon, can I use this card's effect of \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -3000 DP\" twice on the same Digimon to give it -6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in this case you just become unable to trash your opponent's Security Cards and you do not win the game.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Level 7 Digimon, and has 0 Security cards. Do I win the game if I use this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still attack Digimon, and Security Checks from \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still happen.\n",
      "question": "Q: After my opponent activate this card's [Security] effect, my Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e attacks and deletes my opponent's Digimon in battle. Does a Security Check happen?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has no Digimon I can target with \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e, can I still use this option to play a [Diaboromon Token]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I only have a [Diaboromon Token] in my Battle Area, can I use this option to play a new [Diaboromon Token]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has no Digimon that will be affected \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e, can I still use this option to delete all of my opponent's Digimon with Play cost of 3 or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as that Digimon is Played after the you already deleted your Digimon from this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Using this card's effect, I played a Digimon with effects that says [When your other Digimon are deleted], does that effect activate since I deleted my 1 of my Digimon with this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. \"Then,\" effects are independent of each other.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I don't have a Digimon to delete can I still play a level 5 or lower Purple Digimon from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if your opponent does not have either a Level 4 or Level 5 unsuspended Digimon, the effect still activates. If your opponent has one or the other, you would do as much as you can and delete the Level 4 or Level 5 unsuspended Digimon level that your opponent does have.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate if my opponent does not have both a Level 4 and a Level 5 unsuspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the turn I used this card, I activate an effect that involves digivolving for a cost. Can I use this card's effect to suspend a Digimon and reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not return to the bottom of the deck because Breath of the Gods prevent it from happening.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I activate [BT5-109 Mega Digimon Fusion!] and [BT3-105 Breath of the Gods] on a Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e then digivolve the Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e into a level 7 Digimon, does the level 7 Digimon return to the bottom of the deck at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve on top of a tamer using the effect of [BT7-112 Susanoomon], can I use this card's effect to reduce the memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also delete all of my Digimon and Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot digivolve your Digimon with [Omnimon]\u00a0in its name that's in your Breeding Area into this card with its effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve my Digimon with [Omnimon]\u00a0in its name that's in my Breeding Area into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As the attack target is lost, the attack ends without battle.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I attack an opponent's Digimon, then uses this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect to delete the target of attack, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as you did not delete your opponent's Digimon in battle, the condition for \uff1cPiercing\uff1e is not fulfilled.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and attacks an opponent's Digimon, then uses this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect to delete the target of attack, does a Securitiy Check from \uff1cPiercing\uff1e happen?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that scenario, a battle between this Digimon and the blocking Digimon will happen.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks my Digimon with this Digimon, and uses its [When Attacking] effect to delete the target of attack. Can I still activate my other Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect is a [Reaction]/[Counter] effect. So the opponent's [When Attacking] effects will be activated first. (See more in Attack Resolution and Attack Resolution/Old)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end my opponent's Digimon's attack before their [When Attacking] effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the [On Deletion] effect activates immediately and before the [Reaction]/[Counter] step. (See more in Attack Resolution and Attack Resolution/Old)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent Digimon activates their [When Attacking] effect to delete another of their Digimon that has [On Deletion] effects, I then use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end that attack. Do those [On Deletion] effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon attack, can I activate my [BT1-082 Rosemon]'s effect before activating this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it is already passed the timing of [When your opponent's Digimon attacks] at this point of time after battle, you cannot activate this effect. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end my opponent's Digimon's attack after the DP comparison from battling?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the attack happens, and any [When Attacking] and [End of Attack] effects still activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect. Is it treated as that attack never happened?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to trash 2 of this card's Digivolution cards. Can I use [BT2-085 Joe Kido]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can still trash the digivolution cards but there is no attack to negate anymore.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon and then uses an effect to delete the attacking Digimon before I use the [Opponent's Turn] effect. Can I still use the effect of [BT5-111 Omnimon X-Anti-body] to negate the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can trash the digivolution cards of the second Omnimon X-Anti-body, but there is no longer an attack to end for the second one.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon. I have 2 [BT5-111 Omnimon X-Anti-body]. Can I use both of their effects to end the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can suspend your \uff1cBlocker\uff1e Digimon but the attack will not be redirected.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon. I have this card and a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect first and then suspend the \uff1cBlocker\uff1e Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [End of Attack] effect will happen first.\n[5]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a [End of Attack] effect, and I have a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e Digimon with this Digimon. If I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect first. What happens first between the [End of Attack] effect and my \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When this card is revealed from a Security Check, a battle between this card and the attacking Digimon does not happen, and this card is Played into the Battle Area by this effect. As a battle did not happen, the attacking Digimon is not deleted even if it has lower DP than this card.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [Security] effect of [Without battling] mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After this Digimon is played, continue with the remaining checks.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens when this card is revealed from a Security Check while my opponent's Digimon still has remaining checks from \uff1cSecurity Attack +X\uff1e effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I delete my opponent's Digimon that digivolved from Tamer with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will be sent to the trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I am affected by \"cannot be played by effects\", and this card's [Security] effect does not play it. Does the battle still occur?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, even if the attack is blocked, as long as the attack target was declared to be the player, the effect activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks the player, and is blocked by the opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon's effect activate in this case?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, you cannot. \"That Digimon's digivolution cards are trashed\" is just an explanation of what happens to the digivolution cards of the Digimon that was returned to hand. It does not count as an effect that trashes digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon's digivolution card is trashed due to my effect of \"Return 1 of your opponent's Digimon to hand. That Digimon's digivolution cards are trashed\", can I use this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot activate the effect of [BT2-085 Joe Kido].\n",
      "question": "Q: I use \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e while I have this Tamer in play. Can I use the [Your Turn] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent trashes a digivolution card with one of their effects like [BT5-111 Omnimon X] or \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, even if the attack is blocked by a Digimon, as long as the attack target was declared to be the player, the effect does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks the player, and is blocked by the opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon's effect activate in this case?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect did not fulfill its trigger condition. See more in Effect Resolution\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card attacks a player and then one of my effects redirects it to an opponent's Digimon. Does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when I activate an effect like \"\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, then trash 1 card from my hand\"\u00a0?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, both Digimon's effects are activated so you get a total of gain 2 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this Digimon in my Battle Area when I play a [Tai Kamiya], does that mean I get a total of gain 2 memory after activating each of their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, the turn is only passed after that attack fully resolves.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Tamer with [Tai Kamiya]\u00a0in its name, is played by a [Security] effect, this Digimon's effect gives me Gain 1 memory and puts the Memory to 1 on my side, does it become my turn immediately?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as long as the Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e activates even if the attack is not via the effect of \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's inherited effect, must the attack be via the effect of \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in order to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this cards' effect, if I reveal 2 of the same card with [Huckmon]/[Jesmon]/[Sistermon]\u00a0in their name, can I add both of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, regardless of how many Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name you have in play, you only delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in their name in play, do I get to delete 2 of my opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or lower with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes you can, as this Digimon is also treated as a Black Digimon on your turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Digimon into a Digimon with a digivolution requirement of \u201cBlack, level 5\u201d?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as [Your Turn] effects do not activate in the Breeding Area, this card is not treated as a Black Digimon in your Breeding Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in my Breeding Area, can I digivolve it into a Digimon that digivolves from a Black Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon attacks and plays a Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name, does that Digimon being played also activate this Digimon's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, as using the Option Card or not is up to you. As long as no Option Cards were used by this effect, you delete 1 of your opponent's 4000 DP or lower Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve into this Digimon, can I intentionally not use a Cost 7 Option Card so that I can delete 1 of my opponent's 4000 DP or lower Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, you cannot ignore the colour restriction.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use a Cost 7 Option Card from this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect, do I ignore the colour restriction?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to delete 1 of my opponent's 13000 DP or lower Digimon, does this card's [Your Turn] effect also activate and trash 1 of my opponent's security cards from the top?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, you win the game.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent only has 1 security card left, and this Digimon attacks, and trashes that security card with its [Your Turn] effect, leaving my opponent with 0 security cards, do I win the game if that same attack is not blocked?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, both Digimon's effects are activated so you get a total of gain 2 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this Digimon in my Battle Area when I play a [Matt Ishida], does that mean I get a total of gain 2 memory after activating each of their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, the turn is only passed after that attack fully resolves.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Tamer with [Matt Ishida]\u00a0in its name is played by a [Security] effect, this Digimon's effect gives me gain 1 memory and puts the memory to 1 on my side, does it become my turn immediately?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when my opponent does not have any Digimon at all in their Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Memory gain effects of the cards do not happen, but the memory loss effects are still able to activate. So at the end of the turn, the memory loss of the specified amount will happen. The memory effects above are mandatory.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this Digimon on their side, what happens to the \"[When Attacking] Gain 3 memory. At the end of the turn, lose 3 memory\" effects of [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], and [BT1-058 Chirinmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still lose memory from effects even if your opponent cannot gain memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in play and use the effect of a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. Does my opponent still gain memory from my card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's [Your Turn] effect is no longer active when MaloMyotismon's effect resolves.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in play and my opponent has [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]. My opponent plays [BT2-077 Kimeramon] and deletes 1 of their Digimon and this card. Does my opponent gain memory with [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, that Tamer's inherited effect is treated as a Digimon's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with [BT7-087 Koji Minamoto] in its digivolution cards. Does my opponent gain memory from that Tamer's effect when I have this card in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate when my opponent does not have any Digimon at all in their Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when my opponent does not have any Digimon at all in their Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When your Digimon attack, your opponent cannot redirect the attack when activating \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201cAll of your Digimon cannot be blocked by your opponent's Digimon\u201d mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from its effect and updates its security attack value. You re-calculate its security attack and continue checking security based on its new security attack. (For more information see Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has no Digimon in play but reveals a [ST8-06 Coredramon] from this card's security check, does this card check another Security card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It ends when the current turn ends.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Deletion] effect is activated on my opponent's turn, when does the \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e end?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, both Digimon's effects are activated so you get to draw a total of 2 cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Digimon with this card in their digivolution cards in my Battle Area when 1 card is removed from your security stack, do I get a total of 2 cards after activating each of their \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as this card's [On Play] effect says \"You may trash\", whether you trash cards from the top of your security stack or not is up to you.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I trash cards from the top of your security stack until there are 3 left from this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  As you cannot trash any security cards, nothing happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to this card's [On Play] effect when I have 3 or fewer security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 5 security cards, can I choose to only trash 1 security card and gin 1 memory with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if a card is removed from my security stack because of my own effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if a card is removed from my security stack because of my own effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as the effect requires you to \"trash the top card of your security stack\" to activate, if you cannot trash the top card of your security stack, the effect cannot activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 security cards, can I still activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as this card's [When Digivolving] effect says \"You may trash\", it is up to your choice.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve into this Digimon, must I trash the top card of my security stack because off this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as the effect requires you to \"trash the top card of your security stack\" to activate, if you cannot trash security cards, the effect cannot activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate when I have 0 security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [When Digivolving] effect, my security is then at 3 or less. Does this card's [All Turns] effect then take effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as your Security Stack was reduced once, you can. However, in order to \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e your security must be at 3 or less after the resolution of [BT1-107 Holy Wave]'s effect. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon in my Battle Area, my opponent's Digimon checks [BT1-107 Holy Wave] from my Security, and I gain 1 card from my Security Stack from the [Security] effect. Although the number of Security cards I end up with is the same, can I \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e with its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as your Security was reduced once, you can. However, in order to \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e your security must be at 3 or less after the resolution of [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi]'s effect. (See more in Activation#Activation Conditions)\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon in my Battle Area, and I Play [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi] and activate its [On Play] effect to add a Yellow Card from my Security to Hand, then activate \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e. Although the number of Security cards I end up with is the same, can I \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e with its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Security is reduced by being trashed from effects, like of Digimon like [BT2-020 Gallantmon] etc. instead of from Security Check, does this card's [All Turns] effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect when I reduce my Security Stack by my own card's effects like [BT4-104 Blinding Ray] etc?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Fundamentally, this is possible. However, the effects don\u2019t activate simultaneously, but one at a time in any order. Once one results in you having 4 cards in your security stack, any remaining copies of the effect don\u2019t activate. Any [BT6-044 Dynasmon] whose effects failed to activate can still be activated later in the turn. (They don\u2019t count toward the [Once Per Turn] limit.)\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 or more copies of this Digimon in play. My opponent attacks with a Digimon, removing a card from my security stack. Do all of the effects on copies of this Digimon activate simultaneously, activating for each one?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [Security] effect must be activated before [All Turns]'s effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I check a card with a [Security] effect. Can I choose to use this card's effect first before the [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect activates first. After the [Security] effect and any effects triggered by its activation have finished activating, this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon in my Battle Area, my opponent\u2019s Digimon performs a security check, flipping over a card with a [Security] effect. Which activates first: This card\u2019s [All Turns] effect, or the [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, if only either 1 of them are revealed, you can add just that to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, must both 1 [Menoa Bellucci] Tamer card and 1 Digimon card with [Eosmon]\u00a0in its name be revealed among the 5 cards to be able to add them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from aLV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve on top of a tamer with this effect can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must suspend another Digimon in the Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend the tamer for the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Green Digimon, so it is not counted as Red.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Red-Green Tamer into this card, if I use the effect of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%]. Can I discard a Red Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer card's [Security] effect does not become an inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card has a Tamer card as a digivolution card, does that Tamer Card's [Security] effect become this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve from aLV3 Digimon if the requirements are fulfilled instead of a Tamer Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you draw a card from the digivolution Bonus even when digivolving from a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolve a Tamer card into this card, do I draw a card from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as digivolving is not Playing, it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card on the turn its digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it digivolved from a Tamer, the restriction of being unable to attack the turn it is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this card after digivolving from a Tamer that was Played on the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted while having a Tamer card as a digivolution card, what happens to that Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve on top of a tamer with this effect can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must suspend another Digimon in the Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend the tamer for the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Green Digimon, so it is not counted as Red.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Red-Green Tamer into this card, if I use the effect of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%]. Can I discard a Red Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Eldradimon's effect prevents the reduction of DP. But it does not prevent its original DP from being set to another number.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can [BT1-105 Blast Fire] to set the DP of Eldradimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the new Digimon has -3000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses [BT3-101 Bifrost] and targets this card. Eldradimon is then hit by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e. Does the new Digimon have the decreased DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the new Digimon has -3000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses [BT3-101 Bifrost] and targets this card. I digivolve Eldradimon into a new Digimon. Does the new Digimon have the decreased DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, it activates at the end of battle regardless of the outcome of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Security] effect activate even if it loses the battle with the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  As this card's [Security] effect activates at the end of its battle, the effect activates before the next check happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: After the battle this card is checked from my opponent's Digimon's attack, if that Digimon still has remaining checks, does this card's [Security] effect activate first, or do the remaining checks happen first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, at the point of time when this card is played by the effect, it is treated as a normal Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is this Digimon also counted as a security Digimon after it is played into the Battle Area via its effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, it activates at the end of battle regardless of the outcome of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Security] effect activate even if it loses the battle with the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  As this card's [Security] effect activates at the end of its battle, the effect activates before the next check happens.\n",
      "question": "Q: After the battle this card is checked from my opponent's Digimon's attack, if that Digimon still has remaining checks, does this card's [Security] effect activate first, or do the remaining checks happen first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if only either 1 of them are revealed, you can add just that to your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, must both a Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait and a Cost 7 Option Card be revealed among the 4 cards to be able to add them to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my Digimon with [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must add both cards to your hand. This card's Japanese text does not specify \"/or\" in its card text.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals a Digimon card with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait and a Cost 7 Option card from my deck. Can I add only 1 of the cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals a Digimon card with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait and a Cost 7 Option card from my deck. Can I add both cards to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes you can, as this Digimon is also treated as a Red Digimon on your turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Digimon into a Digimon with a digivolution requirement of \u201cRed, level 5\u201d?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as [Your Turn] effects do not activate in the Breeding Area, this card is not treated as a Red Digimon in your Breeding Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in my Breeding Area, can I digivolve it into a Digimon that digivolves from a Red Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at the point of checking security when your opponent no longer has any unsuspended Digimon, the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e is lost.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent only has 1 unsuspended Digimon, and my Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks. If my opponent blocks with their \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, is this card's inherited effect of \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e then lost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as this card's [When Digivolving] effect says \"You can use\", it is up to you to choose to use it or not. If you did not use it, you would then delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with play Cost 4 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if a Cost 7 Option Card was revealed, must I use that Option Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does. In this case, you reveal as many cards as you can and resolve the remainder of the effect as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 or less cards in my deck, does this card's [When Digivolving] effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, you cannot ignore the colour restriction.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use a Cost 7 Option Card from this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect, do I ignore the colour restriction?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As long as you have another Purple Digimon letting you use Purple Option cards, you can use the Option to play the Candlemon trashed by this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal [BT3-076 Candlemon] from the top and [ST6-16 Nail Bone]? Can I use Nail Bone's effect to play the Candlemon."
    }
  ],
  "BT6-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Among all of your opponent's Digimon in the Battle Area, find which Digimon has a play Cost with the lowest number. If multiple Digimon has the same play Cost as that number, all of them are targeted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"All of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest play Cost\" mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at the point of checking security when your opponent no longer has any unsuspended Digimon, the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e is lost.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent only has 1 unsuspended Digimon, and my Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks. If my opponent blocks with their \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, is this card's inherited effect of \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e then lost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: ' No, as it says \"You may trash\". It is up to you to choose to trash or not. However if you did not trash a card, you do not return a Digimon with the [Seven Great Demon Lords]/[Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait from your trash to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, must I trash 1 card from my hand when this card is played?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must trash a card in your hand in order to activate it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when my hand is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon does not have its [Your Turn] effect at the time of trashing a card in the hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card into a Level 5 Digimon while under the effects of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%]. Does the [Your Turn] effect of the Digimon on top of this card activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card\u2019s [On Play] effect can only be used to place cards whose names match either [Kinkakumon]/[Ginkakumon] exactly.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to place a [Ginkakumon Promote] from my trash in this card\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you choose to place cards underneath this card you must do as much as possible or none at all. If you have one, you can place one but if you have both you must place both.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have both [BT6-073 Ginkakumon] and [BT6-071 Kinkakumon] in my trash. Can I choose to place only 1 of them into this card's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a black card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a black Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Rebellimon This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a black Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must trash a card in your hand in order to activate it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when my hand is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they both trigger at the same time. So you can choose which effect to activate first.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my Level 5 Purple Digimon into [BT4-087 Anubismon] while under the effects of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%], and trash this card from the hand. Can I use the [When Digivolving] effect of [BT4-087 Anubismon] before the \"when this card is trashed from your hand\" effect of SkullGreymon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The [On Deletion] effect activates after the card moves to your trash, meeting the requirement for you to have 10 cards in your trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in my trash when this Digimon is deleted. If this results in my having 10 cards in my trash, does this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If possible, you must trash 1 card in your hand for this card\u2019s effect. \u201cThen, you may play 1 purple Level 4 or lower Digimon card from your trash without paying its memory cost\u201d is phrased \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether or not to play a card using the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect force me to trash 1 card in my hand when this card digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to trash a purple Level 4 or lower Digimon card in my hand, then play it with this effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to trash a card in my hand. Does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can\u2019t trash a card in your hand, but since you don\u2019t need to trash a card to activate the second part of the effect, you can still play a purple Level 4 or lower Digimon card from your trash without paying its memory cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: When happens when this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activates while my hand is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you choose not to play a Tamer, your opponent can still use this card\u2019s effect to play a Tamer of their own.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I don\u2019t play a Tamer using this card\u2019s [On Play] effect, does that prevent my opponent from playing a Tamer card, as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is treated as \"[Sistermon Ciel] and [Data] Attribute\" because it is a special rule and not an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in the hand or breeding area. Is this card still treated as \"[Sistermon Ciel] and [Data] Attribute\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card is treated as both [Virus] and [Virus], but it is treated as one card number, and it is treated as having three traits in total including [Champion] and [Puppet].\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have four traits, [Champion]/[Puppet]/[Virus], and [Virus]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Normally, you are only allowed to put up to 4 copies of a card of the same Card Number. This card's effect changes the number of copies of this exact card allowed in your deck to 50 instead.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"You can put up to 50 cards that has the same Card Number as this card in your Deck\" mean exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, you can activate it. In this case, you trash as many security cards as you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 1 or fewer security cards, does that mean I cannot activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, this card's [Main] effect specifies to target only cards that are [Agumon].\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Main] effect, are cards like [Agumon Expert]/[ToyAgumon]\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as long as you had 1 or more security cards at the point of time after activating this effect, your [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] is deleted even if your security is 0 on the same turn afterwards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [Main] effect and digivolve into an [Agumon - Bond of Bravery]. At this point of time I have 1 or more security cards, but on the same turn my security cards are reduced to 0 because of other effects. Does that mean I don't have to delete that [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] at the end of this turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  The [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] that was digivolved using the [Main] effect of the 1st one is deleted as you had 1 or more security cards after activating the effect. The [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] digivolved using the [Main] of the 2nd copy of this card is not deleted as you had 0 security cards after activating the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 of this card. I use the [Main] effect of the 1st to digivolve a Digimon into [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] and have 1 or more security cards. I then use the [Main] effect of the 2nd copy of this card to digivolve another Digimon into another [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] and is left with 0 security cards. What happens to those [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] at the end of this turn in this scenario?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, you can activate it. In this case, you trash as many security cards as you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 1 or fewer security cards, does that mean I cannot activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as long as you had 1 or more security cards at the point of time after activating this effect, your [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] is deleted even if your security is 0 on the same turn afterwards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [Main] effect and digivolve into a [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship]. At this point of time I have 1 or more security cards, but on the same turn my security cards are reduced to 0 because of other effects. Does that mean I don't have to delete that [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] at the end of this turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  The [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] that was digivolved using the [Main] effect of the 1st one is deleted as you had 1 or more security cards after activating the effect. The [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] digivolved using the [Main] of the 2nd copy of this card is not deleted as you had 0 security cards after activating the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 of this card. I use the [Main] effect of the 1st to digivolve a Digimon into [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] and have 1 or more security cards. I then use the [Main] effect of the 2nd copy of this card to digivolve another Digimon into another [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] and is left with 0 security cards. What happens to those [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] at the end of this turn in this scenario?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as the effect says you have to have fewer security cards than your opponent, having the same number of security cards do not activate this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have the same number of security as my opponent, does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes you get gain 2 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I get gain 2 memory from this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect if my opponent has no Digimon at all in their Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  As long as you have any Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait in your Battle Area, you can use this Option even if you do not have any Red Digimon or Tamer in your Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"If you have Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait, you can Use this Option while ignoring the colour requirement\" mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Among all of your opponent's Digimon in the Battle Area, find which Digimon has a DP with the smallest number. If multiple Digimon has their DP as that number, all of them are deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"All of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest DP\" mean exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's effect has already activated, that Digimon cannot attack and block until the effect ends.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon cannot attack and block after receiving the effect of this card. That Digimon then digivolves and gains a digivolution card. Can that Digimon now attack or block?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose a different Digimon from that one that had 2 of their digivolution cards trashed from the bottom from this card's effect to receive the effect of \"1 of your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards cannot attack and block until the end of your opponent's next turn\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn\u2019t count toward your color requirements for Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a blue Option card even if I have no other blue Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 3 Digimon in play. Can I choose to put a Level 6 or higher Digimon on the bottom of my opponent's deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it does not say \"You may do X to do Y\", and says \"Do X. Then, do Y.\" you can use this card even if you have 0 security cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 0 security cards. Does that mean I cannot use this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, as cards revealed from your deck are public information until they are placed to your security stack face-down, you have to show your opponent which of the 2 cards revealed you are putting on top of your security stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I show my opponent the card I am placing on top of my security stack from this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, you can. In this case you reveal as many cards as you can from your deck and perform the remainder of the effect as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if I only have 1 or less cards in my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn\u2019t count toward color requirements for Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a yellow Option card even if I have no other yellow Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Both cards will go to your hand instead of one card going into your security stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I am placed under an effect that prevents me from placing cards in my security, such as [BT9-103 Kongou]. What happens to the cards revealed by this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Your opponent must lose 2 memory. Which means when your opponent's Digimon under the effect of this card is deleted, move the memory counter by 2 towards your side.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon that was given the effect \"[On Deletion] Lose 2 memory\" from the effect of this card is deleted, how do we move the Memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  As long as you have any Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait in your Battle Area, you can use this Option even if you do not have any Black Digimon or Tamer in your Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"If you have a Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait, you can Use this Option while ignoring the colour requirement\" mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, both you and your opponent's Digimon with play Cost of 7 or less are deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do my own Digimon with play Cost of 7 or less also get deleted by this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Among all of your opponent's Digimon in the Battle Area, find which Digimon has a play Cost with the biggest number. If multiple Digimon has the same play Cost as that number, all of them are targeted.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"All of your opponent's Digimon with the highest play Cost\" mean exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, as it does not say \"You may return\", you can use this this card even if you have no Digimon Cards in your trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have no Digimon Cards at all in my trash. Does that mean I cannot use this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn\u2019t count toward color requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a purple Option card even if I have no other purple Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  As long as you have any Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait in your Battle Area, you can use this Option even if you do not have any Purple Digimon or Tamer in your Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"If you have Digimon with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait, you can Use this Option while ignoring the colour requirement\" mean exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, as the DP plus takes effect at the point off time your Digimon is played, the boosted DP is used for this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 [ST1-12 Tai Kamiya] when using this card. A [BT6-085 Eosmon] is played from my hand will get +1000 DP to become 7000 DP. Does that mean I can delete my opponent's Digimon with 7000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, it activates at the end of battle regardless of the outcome of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Security] effect activate even if it loses the battle with the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, even if the attacking Digimon cannot attack player, the attack that was already declared is not interrupted or stopped and resolves as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the attacking Digimon receives this card's [Security] effect of \"Cannot attack player\" does this effect end that attack even if there are remaining Checks no done yet?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon under this card's effect of \"Cannot attack player\" has the effect of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. If that Digimon attacks and defeats a Digimon and survives the battle, does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still let me perform a security Check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes it can. Digimon that are not present at the time of the activation of this card's [Security] effect are not targeted.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 11 or less Digimon in the Battle Area; my opponent then activates this card's [Security] effect. Afterwards on the same turn, I play a new Digimon with \uff1cRush\uff1e Can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  No it does not.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [End of Attack] effect activate if it is deleted after attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. As the timing for [When Attacking] effects to trigger has already passed. (From Card Rulings:EX1-040)\n",
      "question": "Q: My [BT8-066 Hisyaryumon] attacks, and digivolves into [BT6-111 Alphamon] via it's own effect. Can I use [BT6-111 Alphamon]'s [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  No, you cannot ignore the colour restriction.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use a Cost 7 Option Card from this Digimon's [On Play] effect, do I ignore the colour restriction?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The cards in your hand count as private information, so you don\u2019t have to reveal whether you have an Option card you can use in your hand. As such, you can choose not to use an Option card regardless of whether you have one you can use in your hand. (For example, after using this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to return a 7-cost Option card from your trash to your hand.)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect force me to use an Option card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can use a different card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to return an Option card from my trash to my hand. Do I have to use that card with this card\u2019s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 1 memory and only 1 [Three Musketeers] card in my trash. Can I play this card from my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. These option cards \"change the cost to pay\" when they are used, but the card's cost itself has not changed, so they cannot be used with this card's effect. However, [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has an effect that changes the cost of the card when it is in your hand, so if you have two yellow Tamers in the Battle Area, its cost is 7 and it can be used with this Digimon's [On Play] effect.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: When I use a 7-cost Option Card for this Digimon's [On Play] effect, can I use an option card that changes its cost depending on a condition, such as [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] or [BT11-108 DG Dimension]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. No colour is specified, so you can activate it regardless of the colour of Tamer you have in play.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do Tamers of any color make the effect of this card's active?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect activates first.\n",
      "question": "Q: Which activates first: This card's Inherited Effect, or the effect that activates when you trash this card with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a Digimon digivolves, even if it happens due to an effect, it is not counted as an effect placing digivolution cards under that Digimon. \n",
      "question": "Q: When one of my effects digivolves a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple cards are added to the Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, if they were added by a single effect, you only draw 1 card. \n",
      "question": "Q: If one of my effects places 2 or more cards at the same time under a Digimon that has this card's inherited effect, can I draw that many cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose whether or not to reveal cards from your deck, but if any Tamer cards are revealed among the cards, you must trash 1 of them. \n",
      "question": "Q: If there are Tamer cards among the cards revealed with this card's inherited effect, do I have to trash 1 of them?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30f4\u30ea\u30c8\u30e9\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Greymon\" (\u30b0\u30ec\u30a4\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Greymon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Red Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Red-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you play this card with no Tamers in play, you only get to play 1 red Tamer card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I play this card while I have no Tamers in play, and play a red Tamer from my hand with this card's effect, do I then also gain 2 memory from this effect since I now have a Tamer in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple Digimon are deleted, if they were deleted by a single effect, you only gain 1 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I delete 2 or more of my opponent\u2019s Digimon at the same time, does this card\u2019s inherited effect allow me to gain 1 memory for each Digimon deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. All [Security] effects on non-Option cards activate normally.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards performs a security check, if the checked card is a Digimon card or a Tamer card, does its [Security] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, its play cost is reduced by the total number of Option cards in both you and your opponent's trashes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is this card\u2019s play cost reduced by 1 for each Option card in ONLY my trash or my opponent\u2019s trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's owner decides the order the cards are returned to the bottom of the deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to return cards from both players\u2019 trashes to the bottom of their owners\u2019 decks. Who decides which order the cards are placed in?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Immediately after the attack target is changed by a block. Since the effect of this Digimon is triggered by blocking the opponent, it will be activated before the battle with the blocked Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this Digimon, and it is blocked by an opponent's Digimon at the block timing. When does this card's [Your Turn] effect activating?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's effect activates first. The [Your Turn] effect is triggered by your opponent activating \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block this Digimon's attack. Because \uff1cBlocker\uff1e is a reaction timing effect, that means the [Your Turn] effect is triggered after reaction timing effects have been triggered. According to the rules, effects that were triggered later have activation priority, so the [Your Turn] effect activates first.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this Digimon, and it is blocked by an opponent's Digimon at the reaction timing. My opponent has another \"when an opponent's Digimon attacks\" effect that is still pending activation. Does that effect activate before this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 red or black level 5 card with the [Cyborg]\u00a0trait in its traits from my hand or trash on top of this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [When Digivolving] effect even if my opponent has no Digimon with 6000 DP or less in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my [Machinedramon] into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card become a Digimon as a result of \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e doesn\u2019t count as playing it, so you can\u2019t draw any cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is targeted with \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e by my opponent, resulting in this card now being the Digimon\u2019s top card. Do I draw 2 cards with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30ac\u30eb\u30e0\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Garurumon\" (\u30ac\u30eb\u30eb\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Once a Digimon is targeted by this card's [When Digivolving] effect, it becomes unable to attack or block until the end of your opponent\u2019s turn, even if it gains a digivolution card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect prevents a Digimon from attacking or blocking, if that Digimon gains a digivolution card afterwards, can it attack or block?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Blue Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Blue-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you play this card with no Tamers in play, you only get to play 1 blue Tamer card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I play this card while I have no Tamers in play, and play a blue Tamer from my hand with this card's effect, do I then also gain 2 memory from this effect since I now have a Tamer in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect places a Digimon card from my hand under 1 of my Digimon. Can I place it under this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It enters play as a new Digimon, unsuspended. Additionally, it does not carry over any effects on the source Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect plays a level 3 Digimon card from the digivolution cards of a suspended Digimon. Does the level 3 Digimon enter play suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having a digivolution card become a Digimon as a result of \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e does not count as playing that card, so this card's [Your Turn] effect does not trigger.\n",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon with digivolution cards is targeted by my opponent\u2019s \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e, resulting in it becoming one of the Digimon in its digivolution cards. When this happens, can I return 1 of my opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to its owner's hand with this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the effect can be activated both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. You can activate it as a [When Digivolving] effect when you digivolve this Digimon, then activate it again on following turns as a [When Attacking] effect by attacking with this Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that activates at both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] timings. What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter which timing the effect is triggered at, it is still the same effect and can only be activated [Once Per Turn]. If the effect has been triggered at [When Digivolving] and activated, it can not be activated again on the same turn, even if it's triggered [When Attacking].\n",
      "question": "Q: This card has a [When Digivolving][When Attacking][Once Per Turn] effect, but can I activate it twice in the same turn by both digivolving and attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when my Digimon is returned to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when a card effect allows you to draw and trash card from your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not treated as drawing from an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate if my card effect performs a digivolution and draws from its digivolution bonus?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Return this card to its owner\u2019s hand after \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: I trash this card from a Digimon's digivolution cards to activate \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e. Do I return this card to its owner's hand before or after the \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Yellow Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Yellow-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Yellow Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Yellow-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a suspended Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and this card in its digivolution cards, and my opponent attacks me with a Digimon. I unsuspend the Digimon with this card's inherited effect. Can I now block the opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect activates first.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e to trash this card from a Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Which activates first: This card\u2019s inherited effect, or the effect that activates when you trash this card with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cost is equal to the number of cards in your security stack minus the amount reduced by the effect. If you have 4 security cards and activate an effect that reduces digivolution costs by 2, the final digivolution cost will be 2. (4 minus 2.)\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card from my hand, I activate an effect on another card that reduces digivolution costs. What happens to this card\u2019s digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This card's \uff1cDigi-Burst up to 4\uff1e allows you to choose any number of digivolution cards to trash, from 1 to 4. If you have 3 or fewer digivolution cards, you can activate the effect as long as you can trash 1 or more of them.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s \uff1cDigi-Burst up to\uff1e reads \u201cup to 4.\u201d Can I activate the effect if I have 3 or fewer digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect can only target 1 of your opponent's Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I trash 2 digivolution cards to activate this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst up to\uff1e. Can I have 2 of my opponent's Digimon both get -3000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect sets the digivolution cost. It does not reduce.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve into this card for 4 cost or less even if my opponent has [BT5-021 Syakomon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you digivolve into this card while at 2 or fewer security cards, you only go up to 3 security cards with \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect when I have 2 or fewer security cards to go up to 3 security cards with \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e. Do I now gain 2 memory for being at 3 or more security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you revealed only a card with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in its traits or [J.P. Shibayama], you still add that card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 5 cards with this card's [When Digivolving] effect. If the cards revealed only include either a card with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in its traits or [J.P. Shibayama], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve on top of a tamer with this effect can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must suspend another Digimon in the Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend the tamer for the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Green Digimon, so it is not counted as Red.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Red-Green Tamer into this card, if I use the effect of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%]. Can I discard a Red Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30dc\u30eb\u30b0\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Kabuterimon\" (\u30ab\u30d6\u30c6\u30ea\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Kabuterimon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must suspend another Digimon in the Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend the tamer for the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered] to reduce the memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Green Digimon, so it is not counted as Red.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Red-Green Tamer into this card, if I use the effect of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%]. Can I discard a Red Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It is too late to trigger those [When Attacking] effects because it did not have them when the attack was declared. \n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve into a green level 6 Digimon with this card's [When Attacking] effect. Can I activate that Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect is mandatory. You reveal as many cards as you can, up to 3.\n",
      "question": "Q: When attacking, do I have to reveal 3 cards from my deck with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cYou may digivolve,\u201d so you can choose not to.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a green level 6 Digimon card is among the cards revealed with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, do I have to digivolve into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can digivolve into the Digimon of your choosing.\n",
      "question": "Q: If 2 or more green level 6 Digimon cards are among the cards revealed with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, can I choose either card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, do I draw a card as a digivolution bonus? "
    }
  ],
  "BT7-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cThis Digimon can digivolve,\u201d so you can choose not to.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a card with the [Hybrid]/[Insectoid]\u00a0trait in this Digimon's digivolution cards. Does this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect force me to digivolve this Digimon into a Digimon card with the [Insectoid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues. The turn doesn\u2019t switch over just yet. If the memory gauge is still at 1 or more on your opponent\u2019s side after the attack ends and any effects triggered by it finish activating, only then does the turn switch over.\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card's [When Attacking] effect, paying the digivolution cost moves the memory gauge to 1 or more on my opponent\u2019s side. What happens to the attack? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is too late to trigger this card's [When Attacking] effect, since the Digimon didn't have it when the attack was declared.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with [EX1-035 Kabuterimon] and digivolve into this card with its [When Attacking] effect. Can I then digivolve again on the same attack with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore its digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into a Digimon card in my hand with the [Insectoid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait in its traits with this card's [When Attacking] effect, can I ignore that card's digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reduce the digivolution cost of 3 with another effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I am using this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve, can I reduce its digivolution cost of that effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Using this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I prevent my opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during my opponent's next unsuspend phase by applying this effect to it while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Your opponent must trash 1 card in their hand for each Digimon they unsuspend.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent unsuspends 2 or more of their Digimon. Does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect allow my opponent to unsuspend all of their Digimon by trashing 1 card in their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If anything causes an opponent\u2019s Digimon to unsuspend, whether it\u2019s an effect or your opponent\u2019s unsuspend phase, your opponent must trash a card in their hand to unsuspend it.\n",
      "question": "Q: If an effect causes an opponent\u2019s Digimon to unsuspend, does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect force my opponent to trash a card in their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose which of your Digimon to unsuspend, and trash a card in your hand for each one. Digimon will not unsuspend unless you choose to trash a card in your hand, so even if you have fewer cards in hand than suspended Digimon in play, you can still choose to unsuspend specific Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I have 3 suspended Digimon in play, do I need to have 3 or more cards in hand during my unsuspend phase in order to unsuspend my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect only affects Digimon. Your opponent can unsuspend their Tamers normally, without trashing cards in their hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect require my opponent to trash cards in their hand to also unsuspend their Tamer cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Your opponent\u2019s Digimon now have two copies of \u201c[Your Turn] You must trash 1 card in your hand to unsuspend this Digimon\u201d on them, which means they have to trash 2 cards in their hand to unsuspend 1 of their Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have two of these Digimon in play. Does my opponent have to trash 2 cards in their hand for each Digimon they want to unsuspend?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not mandatory. You can choose not to trash a card, but the Digimon will remain suspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: If it would be mandatory to unsuspend a Digimon, is it mandatory to trash a card from your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will only activate after all Digimon affected by this card's [Your Turn] effect have unsuspended. So your opponent trashes all of their cards first before unsuspending all the Digimon that were not prevented from unsuspending, only after the Digimon have unsuspended will the \"when this card is trashed from your hand\" effects activate. (For more information see Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent trashes a card with the effect of \"when this card is trashed from your hand by one of your effects\" for the [Your Turn] effect of this card, when does it activate during the unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will only trigger after the effect has fully resolved along with other effects triggered by the currently resolving effect. (For more information see Effect Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent is unsuspending by an effect and I have this card in play. My opponent trashes a card with \"when this card is trashed from hand\" for the [Your Turn] effect of this card. When does that effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After your opponent finishes trashing cards from their hand for each Digimon they want to unsuspend, all of their Digimon, Tamers, and your Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e will be unsuspended at the same time.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I also have a Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e and my opponent has suspended Tamers, what order does every card unsuspend during the Unsuspend Phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you revealed only a card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its traits or [Kota Domoto], you still add that card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 3 cards with this card's [On Play]\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a Digimon digivolves, even if it happens due to an effect, it is not counted as an effect placing digivolution cards under that Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When one of my effects digivolves a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple cards are added to the Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, you only gain 1 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If one of my effects places 2 or more cards at the same time under a Digimon that has this card's inherited effect, do I gain that much memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is placed in one of my Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose a [DeadlyAxemon] with no digivolution cards with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect place one of my [DeadlyAxemon] with no digivolution cards at the bottom of this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect to trash digivolution cards is considered reminder text, so it does not trigger.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's effect to trash a digivolution card from my [DeadlyAxemon]. Does this trigger the effect of my opponent's [BT8-029 Frozomon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Black Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Black-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Black Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Black-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You don't have to place both a [SkullKnightmon] and a [DeadlyAxemon]. You can also place either of them on their own from either your hand or trash in this Digimon's digivolution cards. However, if both are in your trash, you must place them into its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect place cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards if I don\u2019t have both a [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] in either my hand or trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can mix and match [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] from both your hand and trash to place in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect place a [SkullKnightmon] in my hand and a [DeadlyAxemon] in my trash in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you have both cards you must play both. Otherwise, play as much as you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have both [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card's [All Turns] effect require me to play both?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's [All Turns] effect triggers at the same time as \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion). So it activates before the Digimon has been deleted. Its effect does not prevent its own deletion but you can use \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) and this card's effect to protect it from deletion.\n",
      "question": "Q: When does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon that were played are not deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent plays [BT6-105 Geralt Schw\u00e4rmer] and I use this card's effect to play [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] from its digivolution cards. Do those Digimon also get deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not trigger as it was not about to be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon has already an effect applied that says it \"can't be deleted\", does this card's [All Turns] still trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30c9\u30eb\u30b0\u30ec\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Greymon\" (\u30b0\u30ec\u30a4\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Greymon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to activate it. However, after revealing a card from your deck, you must perform the rest of the effect to the best of your ability.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Once you choose to reveal cards, you must trash all Tamer cards you reveal.\n",
      "question": "Q: If Tamer cards are among the 5 cards revealed by this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, am I required to trash them? "
    }
  ],
  "BT7-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Purple Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Purple-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I don\u2019t have [Eyesmon: Scatter Mode] in my trash. If I trash both this card and [Eyesmon: Scatter Mode] in my hand with an effect, can I play this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon was not on the field at the time your Digimon would unsuspend from the Unsuspend Phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: I discard this card from the [Your Turn] effect of [BT7-055 Ebonwumon]. If this card is suspended by the effect of [BT4-060 Lotosmon] can it still unsuspend during the Unsuspend Phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect treats the tamer as a pure Purple Digimon, so it is not counted as green.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my dual-coloured Purple-Green Tamer into this card, can I use the effect of [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: A purple Tamer card is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. If this Digimon is deleted, can its [On Deletion] effect play that purple Tamer card from my trash without paying its memory cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can activate. The Digimon only considers its situation prior to its deletion.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is deleted with only 1 Digimon card [Hybrid]\u00a0trait, if that Digimon card [Hybrid]\u00a0trait leaves the Trash. Can this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I delete this card itself with its [When Digivolving] effect to delete 1 of my opponent's level 6 or lower Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you don\u2019t play a Tamer from your trash, everything following \u201cThen,\u201d still activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: I do not play a purple Tamer card from my trash with this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect. Does the \u201cfor each Tamer you have in play, delete 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon\u201d part of the effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if there is a valid target and you have not deleted equal to the number of Tamers you must delete that target.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attempt to delete less Digimon than the number of Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Tamer card is in a Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. If that Digimon is deleted, can this card's [All Turns] effect play the Tamer card that used to be in that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards from my trash without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you revealed only a card with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait or a Tamer card, you still add that card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 5 cards with this card's [On Play] effect. If the cards revealed only include either a card with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait or a Tamer card, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect can only place [Sistermon Blanc].\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I place a [Sistermon Blanc (Awakened)] from my hand or trash at the bottom of this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Those cards have [Huckmon]/[Sistermon]\u00a0in their name in their names, so you can add one of them to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect return [BaoHuckmon]/[SaviorHuckmon]/[Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect can only place [Sistermon Ciel].\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I place a [Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)] from my hand or trash at the bottom of this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Those cards have [Huckmon]/[Sistermon]\u00a0in their name, so you can add one of them to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect return [BaoHuckmon]/[SaviorHuckmon]/[Sistermon Blanc (Awakened)]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card's inherited effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The card text reads, \"By doing <X>, you may <Y>\" so you can choose to only place 5 cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait under this Tamer without digivolving.The effect is a \"do <X> to <Y>\", <X> can be done even if you can't do <Y> (don't have an [EmperorGreymon]). However, as the hand is a private area, you are not required to verify if you have an EmperorGreymon or not.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 5 cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait under this Tamer from my trash, and then choose not to digivolve into [EmperorGreymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I only have 4 cards in my trash with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait, can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 4 cards from my trash under this Tamer without digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I am activating another card's effect to digivolve, can I digivolve this Tamer into [EmperorGreymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \"as if this Tamer is a level 5 red Digimon.\" only applies if you are using its effect to digivolve into [EmperorGreymon]. It does not keep applying afterwards.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"as if this Tamer is a level 5 red Digimon.\" apply even if you choose not to digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Once a Digimon is targeted by this card's inherited effect, it becomes unable to attack or block until the end of your opponent\u2019s turn, even if it gains a digivolution card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Attacking] effect prevents a Digimon from attacking or blocking, if that Digimon gains a digivolution card afterwards, can it attack or block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card's inherited effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an opponent's effect returns one of my Digimon to its owner's hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The card text reads, \"By doing <X>, you may <Y>\" so you can choose to only place 5 cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait under this Tamer without digivolving.The effect is a \"do <X> to <Y>\", <X> can be done even if you can't do <Y> (don't have an [MagnaGarurumon]). However, as the hand is a private area, you are not required to verify if you have an EmperorGreymon or not.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 5 cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait under this Tamer from my hand, and then choose not to digivolve into [MagnaGarurumon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I only have 4 cards in my hand with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait, can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 4 cards from my hand under this Tamer without digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I am activating another card's effect to digivolve, can I digivolve this Tamer into [EmperorGreymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \"as if this Tamer is a level 5 blue Digimon.\" only applies if you are using its effect to digivolve into [EmperorGreymon]. It does not keep applying afterwards.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"as if this Tamer is a level 5 blue Digimon.\" apply even if you choose not to digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you do not have to add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If you have a [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait in Security, do you have to add it to your hand if you checked security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to look at your security. If you do not look at security you must still shuffle the security.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to check the security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if a Security Digimon\u2019s DP is reduced to 0, they still battle the Digimon performing the security check.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then, during a security check, I flip one of my opponent\u2019s Security Digimon, whose DP is reduced to 0 by this card\u2019s [Main] effect. Is the opponent\u2019s Security Digimon deleted without a battle taking place?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When your security stack is empty, this card\u2019s memory cost is 0.\n",
      "question": "Q: My security stack is empty. Can I use this card without paying any memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You didn\u2019t have a [Rasenmon] in play when you used this card, so it's too late to give it \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to have an opponent\u2019s Digimon get -3000 DP, then play a [Rasenmon]. Can I have that [Rasenmon] gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This card's effect is only considered 7 \"when you would use this card\". It is not considered to have a use cost of 7 while in your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 7 Security and a yellow tamer, can I use the effect of [BT6-112 BeelStarmon] to play it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can use this card, but no effect will occur. This will still trigger any effects that trigger when you use Option cards, however.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I don\u2019t have a Digimon with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait in play? If I can, what does the effect do?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Using this card's [Main] effect, can I prevent my opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during my opponent's next unsuspend phase by applying this effect to it while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Whether or not you play a Digimon with this card\u2019s effect is irrelevant. You still place it in your battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect, but there are either no black Digimon cards with play costs of 4 or less among the revealed cards, or there is one, but I choose not to play it. Do I discard this card instead of placing it in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I don\u2019t have a Digimon with 5 or more digivolution cards and [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its traits in play. Can I delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less and [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its traits with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with 5 or more digivolution cards and [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its traits in play. Can I delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less and [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its traits with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to delete 1 of my purple Digimon. Can I then return that Digimon card to my hand with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [On Deletion] effect is triggered, but it cannot activate because the Digimon card leaves the trash before that.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to delete 1 of my purple Digimon with an [On Deletion] effect and return it to my hand. What happens to the [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digi-Egg cards are not treated as Digimon cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this effect return Purple Digi-Egg cards from the trash to my hand, and then to the bottom of the Digi-Egg Deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The number of Digimon you can delete is equal to the total number of Digimon with [Hybrid] in their traits and Tamers you have in play. For example, if you have 2 Digimon with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in their traits and 1 Tamer in play, you can choose a total of 3 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does \u201cFor each Digimon with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in its traits and each Tamer you have in play, delete 1 of your opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon\u201d mean that I can delete 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon for each pair of [Hybrid]\u00a0trait Digimon and Tamer I have in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if there is a valid target and you have not deleted equal to the number of Tamers you must delete that target.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attempt to delete less Digimon than the number of Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 10 or more cards in my trash. Can I use this card's effect to play a purple level 5 Digimon card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 10 or more cards in my trash, can I play a Yellow Digimon card with [Lucemon]\u00a0in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. It must be played from the trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 10 or more cards in my trash, can I play a Digimon card with [Lucemon]\u00a0in its name from my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in your battle area, you can use this Option card even if you don\u2019t have a white Digimon or Tamer in play. \n",
      "question": "Q: \"If you have a Digimon card with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in play, you may use this Option card without meeting its colour requirement\" how does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the effect can be activated both [On Play] and [When Digivolving].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that has both [On Play] and [When Digivolving] timings. What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my [Lucemon] into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card\u2019s digivolution requirement icon refers to all colors. Currently, this Digimon can digivolve onto a level 6 Digimon that\u2019s red, blue, yellow, green, black, purple, or white.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What color cards does this card\u2019s digivolution requirement icon refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can mix and match cards from your hand and trash. As long as you return a total of 10 cards to the bottom of your deck, you can activate the effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \"10 Tamer cards and/or cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in their traits from your hand and/or trash,\" but does this mean I can only activate the effect by returning 10 cards in my hand or 10 cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card adds a Tamer card to its digivolution cards, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 6 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, DigiEgg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve onto a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with this Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It's trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must reveal this card from your hand in advance. You must perform the \"placing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\" part of the effect before the digivolution takes place, so you must reveal the card from your hand first. If it is revealed, it is no longer treated as being in your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \"placing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\" effect while this card is still in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, you can\u2019t digivolve even after performing the actions described by the effect. After revealing this card, it is trashed. Note that the game will not view this as you trashing a card in your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s \"placing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\" effect when I have no Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this card from a Tamer by activating an effect other than this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect is \"By doing <X>, you may <Y>\", but if you do, this card will be trashed. You must have 10 cards in your trash and/or hand to reveal this card, but you can also do this without a Tamer in the battle area.The procedure is:\nReveal the Susanoomon to the opponent,\nPlace 10 cards on the bottom of your deck in any order,\nTrash the Susanoomon.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s \"placing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\" effect but choose not to digivolve this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The colour of the tamer does not change because colour is not mentioned in this card's text.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What colour is the Tamer treated as, when digivolving into this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate if my opponent does not have a single Digimon in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect gives +1000 DP even if you have 6 security cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 6 security cards, does this card's effect give +2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card itself is added to my Digimon's digivolution cards, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if cards are trashed from my deck by my own effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards that revealed from deck then trashed are not treated as \"trashed from deck\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an effect reveals cards from my deck and \"trash any remaining cards\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add an option card with 2 colours that includes red to my hand with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a card with an effect that says \"This colour of this Digimon is also treated as red\" to my hand with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you have 2 yellow Digimon in play, this effect only reduces its play cost by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect reduce its play cost by 2 if I have 2 yellow Digimon in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: As the effect has already been activated, the +3000 DP effect will continue \"for the turn\".\n",
      "question": "Q: After this card gets +3000 DP from its [When Attacking] effect, if I activate \uff1cArmor Purge\uff1e to trash this card. What happens to the +3000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-021 Flamedramon] can digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Veemon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-021 Flamedramon], as an effect? Can [BT8-021 Flamedramon] digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card count itself as a Digimon with [Tyrannomon]\u00a0in its name for this card's effect to gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Other than this Digimon and 1 of your opponent's Digimon that was chosen, delete all of you and your opponent's Digimon, and gain 1 memory for each Digimon that was deleted by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [When Digivolving] effect do exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding area cannot be a target of any effects, so they are not deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect also delete Digimon in breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding area cannot be a target of any effects, so they cannot be chosen. Also, regardless of the choice, this effect does not delete Digimon in breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent choose the Digimon in their breeding area for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Delete all of your Digimon except this Digimon, then gain 1 memory for each Digimon deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to this card's [When Digivolving] effect if my opponent does not have a single Digimon in their battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When Digimon would be deleted by this effect, can my opponent activate \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) or \uff1cArmor Purge\uff1e etc, to stop their Digimon that was not chosen, from being deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards, and 1 of your other Digimon, can DNA digivolve into a Digimon in your hand that can DNA digivolve, before the turn is passed to your opponent.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve into a Digimon card without a DNA digovolution effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that does not have a DNA digivolve effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve your Digimon that is not the correct colour or level  specified by the card with DNA digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve my Digimon in play that is not the colour and level specified by the card with DNA digivolve in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon from DNA Digivolve is treated as a new Digimon so the old DIgimon is no longer in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's [End of Your Turn] effect has triggered, and the Digimon it is underneath is used as part of a DNA Digivolve. Can I still activate this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add an option card with 2 colours that includes blue to my hand with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a card with an effect that says \"This colour of this Digimon is also treated as blue\" to my hand with this card's effect?."
    }
  ],
  "BT8-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you couldn't trash any digivolution card of your opponent's Digimon, the effect \"1 of your opponent's Digimon without digivolution cards gets -3000 DP\" will still activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if my opponent has no Digimon with digivolution cards, thus no digivolution card can be trashed, does that mean the part of \"1 of your opponent's Digimon without digivolution cards gets -3000 DP\" cannot activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-023 Submarimon] can digivolve from [Armadillomon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Armadillomon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-023 Submarimon], as an effect? Can [BT8-023 Submarimon] digivolve from [Armadillomon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When this Digimon would digivolve\" is after declaring a digivolution, but before paying the digivolution cost.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When exactly is the timing to activate this card's [Your Turn] effect of \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate even when DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my security is 3 or less, and my opponent's [EX3-016 SnowAgumon] and [EX3-019 Paledramon] cause the digivolution to fail. Will this card still \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-026 Halsemon] can digivolve from [Hawkmon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Hawkmon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-026 Halsemon], as an effect? Can [BT8-026 Halsemon] digivolve from [Hawkmon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving a Digimon is not playing it, so it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate if my opponent's Digimon digivolves into level 5 or above?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, moving a Digimon from breeding area is not playing it, so it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate when my opponent moves a level 5 or above Digimon from breeding area to battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding area are not referenced for effects, so it can attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has a Digimon with digivolution cards in their breeding area, does that mean this Digimon cannot attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when my opponent activates \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [When Attacking] effects activate if it has both blue and green cards its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [When Attacking] effects activate if it only has 1 two-coloured card that is both blue and green its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-032 Imperialdramon Fighter Mode] can digivolve from a Digimon [Dragon Mode] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 if name contains [Dragon Mode]>\", written in the text for [BT8-032 Imperialdramon Fighter Mode], as an effect? Can [BT8-032 Imperialdramon Fighter Mode] digivolve a Digimon whose name contains [Dragon Mode] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add an option card with 2 colours that includes yellow to my hand with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a card with an effect that says \"This colour of this Digimon is also treated as yellow\" to my hand with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the Digimon itself that has this card in its digivolution card is a blue Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: As the effect has already been activated, the instances of +2000 DP will persist \"until the end of your opponent's next turn\".\n",
      "question": "Q: After this card gets +2000 DP for each Digimon card with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in my trash from its [When Digivolving] effect, if I activate \uff1cArmor Purge\uff1e to trash this card, what happens to the instances of +2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-038 Magnamon] can digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 3 from [Veemon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-038 Magnamon], as an effect? Can [BT8-038 Magnamon] digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, regardless of how many tamers you have in play, only up to 3 Digimon get -5000 DP .\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect give up to 6 of my opponent's Digimon -5000 DP if I have 2 tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-039 Rapidmon] can digivolve from [Terriermon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 3 from [Terriermon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-039 Rapidmon], as an effect? Can [BT8-039 Rapidmon] digivolve from [Terriermon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it counts as having 2 colours, so you draw 2.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I trash a red card for this card's effect, does this Digimon then count as having 2 colours of yellow & red, letting me draw 2 cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is counted as a 3-coloured Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I trash a blue/green 2-coloured card for this card's effect, does this Digimon then count as having 3 colours of yellow, blue, & green?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this card activated its [When Digivolving] effect and then is \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e into a Tamer card. Does the Tamer also get treated as the colour of the trashed card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is activated as many times as the number of your tamers in play, so you can choose different targets for each activation.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, when I have multiple tamers in play, can I choose that many separate Digimon to give \uff1cSecurity Attack -2\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they are treated to be activated at the same time.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates 2 or more times, are they considered to be activated in separate different timings?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card's [Your Turn] effect is an effect that unsuspends your other Digimon when they digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my suspended digimon digivolves into this Digimon, can its [Your Turn] effect unsuspend this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, at the point of time when this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates, if a Digimon was a valid target for having \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, this card's effect will still continue and that Digimon cannot attack and block even if it loses its \uff1cBlocker\uff1e afterwards.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon that was targeted by this card's [When Digivolving] effect loses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e due to digivolving, DNA digivolving, or losing digivolution cards, does that Digimon then become able to attack and block?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-048 Shurimon] can digivolve from [Hawkmon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Hawkmon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-048 Shurimon], as an effect? Can [BT8-048 Shurimon] digivolve from [Hawkmon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can it suspend itself to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-051 Digmon] can digivolve from [Armadillomon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Armadillomon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-051 Digmon], as an effect? Can [BT8-051 Digmon] digivolve from [Armadillomon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-053 Lighdramon] can digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Veemon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-053 Lighdramon], as an effect? Can [BT8-053 Lighdramon] digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as those option cards are already used and their effects have already activated, they are not nullified by this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this Digimon in play, and on my turn after I used option cards such as [BT1-109 Smashed Potatoes] or [EX1-071 Win Rate: 60%] etc, to \"reduce the digivolution cost the next time my Digimon digivolves\", all of my opponent's Digimon then become suspended. In this scenario, do those option cards effects becomes nullified when my Digimon digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Activating the effect of \uff1cDelay\uff1e of an option card that was already placed in your battle area does not count as using an option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this Digimon in play, can I activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e of my option card with \uff1cDelay\uff1e that was already placed in my battle area from before?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect stops both players from digivolving with effects that says \"ignore digivolution requirements\", or from Digimon that do not meet the digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it doesn't say \"Ignore digivolution requirements\", and it is digivolving according to the digivolution requirements while treating the tamer as a Digimon, it can digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect stop effects of [Hybrid] form card's digivolutions of \"Your red tamer can digivolve into this card in your hand as if it was a red level 3 Digimon\" etc?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, DNA digivolution and special digivolutions written on the cards are treated as the digivolution requirements, so they are not stopped by this card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect stops DNA digivolutions or special digivolutions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as activates, as it is an effect that allows digivolving without paying its cost without ignoring digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is in play, can the effect \"can digivolve without paying its cost\" activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your opponent cannot digivolve ignoring level while this card's [All Turns] effect is active.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent activate the effect of [BT6-087 Tai Kamiya] to ignore level while this card is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can digivolve with the effect [BT7-051 RhinoKabuterimon] because it does not ignore digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve with the effect of [BT7-051 RhinoKabuterimon] which changes the memory cost of the digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does not ignore digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve into [BT7-040 Rasenmon] for an alternate digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect requires you to digivolve \"ignoring the digivolution requirements\" so you cannot digivolve using the effect of [BT9-098 Awakening of the Golden Knight].\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT9-098 Awakening of the Golden Knight] and my opponent has this card. Can I digivolve my [Magnamon] into [BT9-044 Magnamon (X Antibody)] because it fulfills the digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [Mamemon] even in the hand, deck, trash, and digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as effects do not activate in the breeding area, this card/Digimon is not treated as being [Mamemon] in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [Mamemon] even in breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [SkullKnightmon]/[DeadlyAxemon] even in the hand, deck, trash, and digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as effects do not activate in the breeding area, this card/Digimon is not treated as being [SkullKnightmon]/[DeadlyAxemon] in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [SkullKnightmon]/[DeadlyAxemon] even in breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the Digimon itself that has this card in its digivolution card is a red Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you return up to 4 cards from both your hands and trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, can I return up to 4 Digimon cards with [Mamemon]\u00a0in their names from both my hand and trash to the top of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. As this effect does not allow you to ignore digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve into any Digimon with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait regardless of digivolution requirements with this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. As the timing for [When Attacking] effects to trigger has already passed. (From Card Rulings:EX1-040)\n",
      "question": "Q: My [BT8-066 Hisyaryumon] attacks, and digivolves into [BT6-111 Alphamon] via it's own effect. Can I use [BT6-111 Alphamon]'s [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After revealing the 3 cards, all of them are trashed. However, since the effect is \"you may reveal the top 3 cards of your deck\", regardless of your opponent's Digimon, you can choose not to activate the effect when digivolving. If the effect is not activated, you do not reveal any cards, and no cards will be trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens for this card's [When Digivolving] effect if my opponent does not have a single Digimon on play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Play cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's \"play 1 Digimon card with [Mamemon]\u00a0in their names a memory cost of 10 or less \", which cost is it referring to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if there are both red and black cards in its digivolution cards, can I delete my opponent's tamer and Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it must be a combination of Digimon and tamers with an added total of play cost of up to 6.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if there are both red and black cards in its digivolution cards, can I choose my opponent's Digimon with play cost of up to 6, and my opponent's tamers with play cost of up to 6 separately?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [When Digivolving] effects activate if it only has 1 two-coloured card that is both red and black in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if there is a valid target (Digimon or Tamer) that exists for this effect, you must delete at least 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to delete a Digimon or Tamer with this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is an effect that nullifies \"reduce play cost by x\". You and your opponent will be unable to activate effects that reduce play costs, and must pay the play cost written on the cards in order to play them.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's \"can't reduce play costs.\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"play without paying its memory cost\" is not an effect that reduces play costs, so it can activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is in play, can \"play without paying its memory cost\" effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.Since the effect does not target Digimon, it will still take effect even if the Digimon reducing the play cost is in the Breeding Area.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect prevent the cost reduction of my opponent's [BT13-007 Yggdrasil 7D6]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the cost cannot be reduced. Because of this card's effect, effects that reduce the play cost of Tamers cannot be activated.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is present, can the opponent's [BT14-046 Togemon]'s [Your Turn] effect reduce the play cost of the green Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can only trash 1 purple Digimon card.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, must the 1 trashed card among the revealed cards be a purple Digimon card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect activate \"when a card is trashed from deck\" effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards that revealed from deck that are then trashed are not treated as \"trashed from deck\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an effect reveals cards from my deck and I must \"trash any remaining cards\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards that revealed from deck that are then trashed are not treated as \"trashed from deck\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an effect reveals cards from my deck and I must \"trash any remaining cards\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [When Digivolving] effects activate if it has both purple and yellow cards its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [When Digivolving] effects activate if it only has 1 2-coloured card that is both purple and yellow its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-082 Ophanimon: Falldown Mode] can digivolve from [Ophanimon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)\n",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Ophanimon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-082 Ophanimon Falldown Mode], as an effect? Can [BT8-082 Ophanimon Falldown Mode] digivolve from [Ophanimon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: In addition to this card's own colour of \"white\", it is also treated as the colours of the cards in its digivolution cards. For example when this card has a red card and a green card in its digivolution cards, this card is treated as a card with 3 colours, white, red, and green.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, regardless of the colour of the cards in digivolution cards, it only counts the colours of that Digimon, and the effect activates if it has 2 or more colours.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"When your Digimon with 2 or more colours attacks\", does it count the colour of the attacking Digimon's digivolution cards as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your opponent has to target your blue Digimon when attacking to trigger this effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect trigger when my opponent's Digimon attacks, and I block with my blue Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the initial target of the attack was a Blue Digimon you can activate this card's effect.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent declares an attack on a Blue Digimon and then \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e it into a non-Blue Digimon. Can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effects activate if I have both blue and green Digimon in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do both of this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effects activate if I only have 1 2-coloured Digimon that is both blue and green in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, regardless of the colour of the cards in digivolution cards, it only counts the colours of that Digimon, and the effect activates if it has 2 or more colours.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"When your Digimon with 2 or more colours attacks\", does it count the colour of the attacking Digimon's digivolution cards as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's[Opponent's Turn] effect activate when my opponent activates the effect of cards such as [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa] to move their level 3 Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area when it is not their breeding phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. This effect only counts Digimon that has 1 single card that has 2 or more colours among its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"card with 2 or more colour in its digivolution cards\" include Digimon with 1 red card and 1 blue card in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. Effects that add colours do not activate while they are in digivolution cards, it is only treated as a card with 1 colour.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"card with 2 or more colour in its digivolution cards\" include Digimon that has cards such as [BT3-040 Shakkoumon] with effects of \"This Digimon's colour is also treated as blue\" in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in this scenario the memory cost is reduced to 0. Use memory does not become negative, and 0 is the lowest value possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has 7 Digimon in play, and this card's memory cost is reduced by 7 by this card's effect, can I use this card to gain 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After the battle with the security Digimon, since that security Digimon cannot be played by its own effect, it is trashed as normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I attack and the security check reveals a Digimon with an effect of \"[Security] At the end of battle, play this Digimon without paying its memory cost\". What happens to the security Digimon in this scenario?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Main] effect of this card has been changed to \"Until end of your opponent's turn, \"your opponent cannot play Digimon with effects. Then, delete all of your opponent's Digimon with 6000 or less.\". So the effect to stop your opponent from playing is applied first before DarkKnight can interrupt the deletion.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [BT7-063 DarkKnightmon] with [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] in its digivolution cards. Can the interruptive [Your Turn] effect of [BT7-063 DarkKnightmon] play the Digimon before it's deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It ends when the current turn ends.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [Security] effect is activated on my opponent's turn, when does the \"opponent cannot play cards due to effects\" effect end?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of this card has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be demonstrated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card and a [EX2-003 Viximon] in my Digimon's digivolution cards while my opponent has 5 or more Digimon in play, will that card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only target Digimon for the \"cannot attack and block\" effect at the point of time of activating this card's effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, my opponent does not have any Digimon without digivolution cards, so I am unable to target any Digimon for the \"cannot attack and block\" effect. Afterwards, if a Digimon without digivolution cards enters my opponent's battle area, can I target that Digimon for the \"cannot attack and block\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It ends when the current turn ends.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [Security] effect is activated on my opponent's turn, when does the \"cannot attack or block\" effect end?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. This effect only counts Digimon that has 1 single card that has 2 or more colours among its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"card with 2 or more colours in its digivolution cards\" include Digimon with 1 red card and 1 blue card in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. Effects that add colours do not activate while they are in digivolution cards, it is only treated as a card with 1 colour.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"card with 2 or more colour in its digivolution cards\" include Digimon that has cards such as [BT3-040 Shakkoumon] with effects of \"This Digimon's colour is also treated as blue\" in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's effect, if I have 1 Digimon with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in my trash, does the Digimon that received -4000 DP also get an additional -1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, although you can target your opponent's Digimon or tamer that are already suspended with this card's effect, that card must be \"suspended by this card's effect\" for \"Your opponent's cards suspended with this effect can't unsuspend until the end of their next turn\" to be applicable.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I target my opponent's Digimon or tamer with this card's effect that is already suspended, does the part of the effect that reads \"Your opponent's cards suspended with this effect can't unsuspend until the end of their next turn\" apply to that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can choose any number of your opponent's Digimon, as long as the play costs of those Digimon are 15 or less when they are added together. For example, \"1 Digimon with play cost of 3\" + \"1 Digimon of play cost of 12\", or \"1 Digimon with play cost of 2\" + \"2 Digimon with play cost of 6\" etc, the effect that activates targets those Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does \"Choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose play costs add up to 15 or less\" mean exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you are free to choose in any way as long as the total play cost is 15 or less. However, you must choose at least 1 Digimon with play cost of 15 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose in a way so that the total play cost is less than 15 on purpose?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, regardless of what was the memory cost paid when the cards were played, you add together the play costs written on the cards, up to 15.\n",
      "question": "Q: For Digimon that were played with reduced costs, or played without paying their memory costs, do I treat them as that reduced play cost value or 0 play cost for this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can freely choose as long as the total play cost is 15 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose in a way so that the total play cost is less than 15 on purpose?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent does not have a single Digimon in play, or does not have any Digimon with level equal or lower than my Digimon in play, can I use this card to delete 1 of my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card deletes a Digimon without a level, can I delete one of my opponent's Digimon that does not have a level?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it will have 0 DP the Digimon will not be deleted until the effect of Flame Hellscythe is over. As such, you cannot play a Digimon via the effect of Flame Hellscythe. (Rules Processing)\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT9-047 Pomumon] or [BT9-033 Pillomon] in play. If I target that Digimon with the -6000 DP effect of this card. Can I still play a Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that scenario, you only unsuspend the Digimon that digivolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I trash 1 card from the top of my Digimon with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait, can I digivolve another one of my Digimon into a Digimon with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in my hand instead?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, in this scenario the part of the effect \"unsuspend that Digimon\" is not applied.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I trash 1 card from the top of my Digimon with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait, can I then choose not to digivolve into an Digimon with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not ignore digivolution requirements.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card to digivolve my Digimon into an Digimon with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in my hand, does it allow me to digivolve while ignoring the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It cannot be trashed, and as you will not trash any card from your Digimon. You can still perform the rest of the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I target my Digimon [Armor Form]\u00a0trait and no digivolution cards to trash the top card. What happens?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you trash more than 4 cards, you can only play 1 purple level 5 or lower Digimon card.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I trash 8 cards from the top of my deck with this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I play 2 purple level 5 or lower Digimon cards from my trash without paying their memory costs?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as the effect is \"For every 10 cards in your trash\", if you have 20 cards in your trash, you trash 6 cards from the top of your opponent's deck and give this Digimon +6000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Attacking] effect, if I have 20 cards in my trash, do I trash 6 cards from the top of my opponent's deck and give this Digimon +6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will activate in both timing [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. When you digivolving into this Digimon, it will activate as a [When Digivolving] effect, and for the following turns when this Digimon attacks, it will then activate again as a [When Attacking] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect has 2 timing, [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. What does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. If you do not do <X> you cannot do the rest of the effect. (See more in Effect Structure#Optional and Mandatory Effects\n",
      "question": "Q: This card has \"you may <X> to <Y>. Then, <Z>\" If I do not do <X>, am I still allowed to do <Z>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this effect activate when I return my own Digimon to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this effect activate when a card effect allows you to draw and trash card from your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not treated as drawing from an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate if my card effect performs a digivolution and draws from its digivolution bonus?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card effect activate during the timing of \u201cAdd a card from your security to your hand, then perform \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e\u201d\u00a0?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect refers to deletion effect that states \"Delete Digimon with X DP or less\" and \"Select opponent\u2019s Digimon with the total of X or less\". This effect enables the player to increase the limit by 1000 DP. However, this effect does not apply to effects such as \"Delete the Digimon that has lower DP than this Digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: What does the effect \"Add +1000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It only affects the maximum DP, so [BT3-098 Plasma Stake] will still delete only Digimon with 13000 DP or more.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect increase the minimum DP deletion of [BT3-098 Plasma Stake] from 13000 DP to 14000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect refers to deletion effect that states \"Delete Digimon with X DP or less\" and \"Select opponent\u2019s Digimon with the total of X or less\". This effect enables the player to increase the limit by 1000 DP. However, this effect does not apply to effects such as \"Delete the Digimon that has lower DP than this Digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: What does the effect \"Add +1000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It only affects the maximum DP, so [BT3-109 Plasma Stake] will still delete only Digimon with 12000 DP or more.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect increase the minimum DP deletion of [BT3-109 Plasma Stake] from 12000 DP to 13000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect states to trash 2 cards from the digivolution cards that have the same level. For example, by trashing 2 level 5 Digimon cards from its digivolution cards, this Digimon will not be deleted or returned to the deck/hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card, \"by trashing 2 cards with the same level\", require the 2 cards to be the same level as the current Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to trash this card when activating this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t. Due to the fact that the Digimon DP becomes 0 and it will be deleted due to rules and not the effect of the card. It will not be considered as deleted by card effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this evolution source effect activate when this Digimon DP reaches 0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot unsuspend a Digimon if the Digimon is not deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is chosen to be deleted by [BT5-106 Demonic Disaster], if it uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion do I still get to unsuspend a Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [OmniShoutmon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"When you have [OmniShoutmon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it's required to meet the condition you have cards with [WarGrowlmon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [WarGrowlmon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [MetalGreymon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [MetalGreymon]\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since this effect activates and checks for the card named [MetalGreymon]/[X Antibody] when digivolving, this Digimon does not gain +3000 DP if you place the card [X Antibody] under this card\u2019s digivolution cards after digivolving it.\n",
      "question": "Q: After I digivolve this Digimon, if I place the card [X Antibody] under this card\u2019s digivolution cards in the same turn, do I get +3000 DP due to its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [WarGreymon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [WarGreymon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\" does that mean I can activate the effect, if I have cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the security will be reduced when performing checks, if there is a [Security] effect during the checks, [Security] effects will be activated first, and this effect will be activated after. After that, if there are no other effects to be activated, you will gain 1 memory before battling the security Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect, when the player attacks the security and checks a Security Digimon and battles it. Does the player gain 1 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect of [When Digivolving] is when your opponent has no Digimon or Digimon with the lowest DP does not get deleted by this card effect. It also means during the timing when there is no target that can be deleted by this card effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: What is the effect of [When Digivolving] \"Delete 1 of your opponents Digimon with the lowest DP, if there is no Digimon was deleted by this effect\" meant?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t. You are required to pick a target if possible, during the activation of this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon when I activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If there are multiple Digimon with the lowest DP you can select either 1 of them as a target. So it\u2019s possible to choose a Digimon that has the effect of \"Can\u2019t be deleted by opponent card effects\" which will allow you to active this Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent has a Digimon that \"Can\u2019t be deleted by opponent\u2019s card effects\" and the Digimon has the same DP as this Digimon. During the activation of this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, can I choose my opponent\u2019s Digimon that has the effect of \"can\u2019t be deleted by your opponent\u2019s card effect\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [Gallantmon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [Gallantmon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does [When Digivolving] allow you to gain 1 memory for each Tamer your opponent has?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: While my opponent has multiple Tamers and only has 1 Digimon. Can I only suspend the Digimon and gain memory for each Tamer that my opponent has?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s a \"You May\" effect. You can choose not to use it and if it's not used [Once Per Turn], it will not be used.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to use the [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the blocking Digimon is deleted by this card effect and due to the attack target no longer being present, the battle will be skipped, and the attack will end.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I declare an attack. My opponent Digimon with 6000 DP blocks with a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e Digimon and suspends it. Due to the [All Turns] effect that Digimon is deleted. What will happen to the attack in this situation?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it had 6000 or less DP at the time it was suspended.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent declares an attack with [BT7-049 MameTyramon]. If they digivolve into a new Digimon, can this Digimon's effect still delete the newly digivolved Digimon even if it has more than 6000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is triggered as soon as the opponent declares an attack suspending the Digimon. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card's [All Turns] effect on the opponent's turn considered a [Reaction] effect during battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It is not a \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with X DP or less\" effect.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect receive the boost from [BT9-009 Guilmon X Antibody]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can add the card to your hand even though you only revealed cards with [Garurumon]/[Omnimon]/[X Antibody]\u00a0in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect mean that I can\u2019t add the cards to my hand unless I add both card with [Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No because the effect stated \"Add to hand\", thus you are required to add as much as possible from the revealed cards. You are required to add cards with [Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name and [X Antibody] to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal cards with [Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's inherited effect activate when my Digimon is returned to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when a card effect allows you to draw and trash card from your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not treated as drawing from an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate if my card effect performs a digivolution and draws from its digivolution bonus?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect states to trash 2 cards from the digivolution cards that have the same level. For example, by trashing 2 level 5 from the digivolution cards, this Digimon will not be deleted or returned to the deck/hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card \"By trashing 2 cards with the same level\" require the trashed cards to be the same level as the current Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to trash this card when activating this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As the requirement of \"when this Digimon attacks and deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives the battle\" of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e was not met, it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e attacked my Digimon, and my Digimon lost the battle. I then activate my Digimon's [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. What happens to my opponent's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because the Digimon will still have \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and it deleted a Digimon battle and survived it will trigger.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e gained from [BT8-103 Lightning Blade] and battles a Digimon with equal DP. I activate its [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it lost \uff1cPiercing\uff1e before the timing it would trigger and if it doesn't trigger it cannot activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from [EX1-008 MetalGreymon] in its digivolution cards, this card attacks a Digimon with equal DP and uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion by trashing [EX1-008 MetalGreymon]. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [WereGarurumon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [WereGarurumon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will be activated during the Main Phase, by revealing this card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: When is the timing of this card effect [Hand] [Main] activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reveal this card and not pay the cost. The card will be returned to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't want to pay 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must fulfil the condition to reveal this card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't have a Digimon [Justimon]/[Raidenmon]\u00a0in its name in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [MetalGarurumon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [MetalGarurumon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\" does that mean I can activate the effect, if I have cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card [Your Turn] effect be activated during my active phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon prevent Digimon from being played by the effect of an option card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This effect only applies to card effects that allows a Digimon to be played in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in the battle area, can play cost be reduced?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It will remain the top of the security stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: What will happen if I don\u2019t add the card to my hand, after I check the top card of the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [Angewomon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [Angewomon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\" does that mean I can activate the effect, if I have cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [RizeGreymon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [RizeGreymon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will be activated during the Main Phase, by revealing this card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: When is the timing of this card effect [Hand] [Main] activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reveal this card and not pay the cost. The card will be returned to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't want to pay 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must fulfil the condition to reveal this card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't have a Digimon [Justimon]/[Raidenmon]\u00a0in its name in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [Magnadramon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [Magnadramon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with the [Armor Form]/[X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have a card with the [Armor Form]/[X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards\" does that mean I can activate the effect, if I have cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Magnamon X will place itself into the top of security by its [All Turns], however, the minus DP effects will continue to apply on the new Digimon afterwards. If it still has 0 DP it will still be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this Digimon is to be deleted due to having 0 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot activate the [All Turns] effect at all.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I still place it into security if it does not have a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because it specifies the card name and you can only add a card with the name [X Antibody] to your hand. It does not apply to cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card effect, can I add a card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only revealed a card with the [Insectoid]/[X Antibody]\u00a0trait you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card effect, does it mean that I can\u2019t add both cards unless I add both [Insectoid]\u00a0trait\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No because the effect states \"Add to hand\", thus you are required to add as much as possible from the revealed cards. You are required to add cards with the [Insectoid]\u00a0trait and 1 [X Antibody] to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal cards with the [Insectoid]\u00a0trait\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is present in the battle area, can I move my Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area  using [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This effect only applies to card effects that makes a Digimon to be played in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in the battle area, can play cost be reduced?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon prevent Digimon from being played by the effect of an option card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, because this card only specifies [Leomon].\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play a [Leomon (X Antibody)] from this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t target this card as [Leomon] as the card name. This effect can\u2019t be applied to cards with [Leomon]\u00a0in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is also treated as having [Leomon]\u00a0in its name. Is it possible to target this card as [Leomon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [Okuwamon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [Okuwamon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will be activated during the Main Phase, by revealing this card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: When is the timing of this card effect [Hand] [Main] activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reveal this card and not pay the cost. The card will be returned to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't want to pay 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must fulfil the condition to reveal this card from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't have a Digimon [Justimon]/[Raidenmon]\u00a0in its name in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this Digimon\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, can I suspend my opponent\u2019s Digimon and change the attack target to that suspended Digimon by this card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [GranKuwagamon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [GranKuwagamon]\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect condition only prevents the declaration of an attack on that Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Digimon has \"This Digimon cannot be attacked.\", can this card's effect change the attack target to that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [Leomon]/[X Antibody]\u00a0in its name in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have cards with [Leomon]\u00a0in its name\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this inherited effect activate when this Digimon has the effect of \"This Digimon is also treated as red\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's Japanese name (\u30ed\u30fc\u30c0\u30fc\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) has \"Leomon\" (\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Leomon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you have either 1 of them in the trash the effect still activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] [On Play] effect only activate when there are [Raijinmon]/[Suijinmon], and [Fujinmon] in the trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will gain +3000 DP and you can \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on 1 of your opponent's Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of +3000 DP only activate when there are level 6 Digimon cards with 4 or more colours in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as having [Greymon]\u00a0in its name even in the hand, deck, trash, and digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as effects do not activate in the breeding area, this card/Digimon is not treated as being [Greymon]\u00a0in its name in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [Greymon]\u00a0in its name even in breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This Digimon only has [Greymon]\u00a0in its name, it does not count as being [Greymon].\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is also treated as having [Greymon]\u00a0in its name. Does this Digimon count as [Greymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the activation of the [When Digivolving] effect, can I use both \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e when I have both red and black cards in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in the deck, when revealed by [BT5-009 Shoutmon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I unsuspend my opponent's suspended Tamer by using this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [When Digivolving] effect to unsuspend 1 of my Tamers and 1 of my opponent\u2019s Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be only be 2 in total. It can be done by unsuspending 2 Tamers or 2 Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [When Digivolving] effect allow me to unsuspend 2 Tamers and 2 Digimon at the same time?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Divide the total of unsuspended Digimon and Tamer by 2. For example, if there are 3 unsuspended Digimon and 1 unsuspended Tamer, 2 security will be trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [End of Your Turn] effect of trashing my opponent\u2019s security cards only apply for each pair of 1 Tamer and 1 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can only add and trash cards with the [Undead]\u00a0trait or [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait.\n",
      "question": "Q: When [On Play] effect is activated, does that mean I can only trash cards with the [Undead]\u00a0trait or [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must add it to your hand as adding to hand happens first.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I activate [On Play] effect, among the revealed cards there is only 1 [Undead]\u00a0trait or [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait. Can I choose to either trash it or add it to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this inherited effect digivolve into any Digimon that has the [Undead]\u00a0trait or [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait in it\u2019s trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, because it\u2019s not there during the timing of declaring an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon digivolves to a Digimon that has the effect of [When Attacking], can I activate [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this inherited effect digivolve into any Digimon that has the [Undead]\u00a0trait or [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait in it\u2019s trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, because it\u2019s not there during the timing of declaring an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon digivolves into a Digimon that has the effect of [When Attacking], can I activate [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card of a Digimon with effects such as \"This Digimon is also treated as red\", will the inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since dual coloured card is also treated as both colours, both effects will activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the card trashed from hand by this card\u2019s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect was both a yellow and purple dual coloured card, will both effects of \"Delete 1 of opponent\u2019s level 3 Digimon\" and \"During this turn, 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon loses -3000 DP\" activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card of Digimon with effects such as \"This Digimon is also treated as red\", will the inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card itself can\u2019t be digivolved by its own effect. This effect can be used with another card\u2019s effect to digivolve from the trash by paying the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect be used to digivolve from trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon\u2019s [End of Attack] effect digivolve a card into any Digimon that has the [Undead]\u00a0trait or [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using the [On Play] effect can I choose to play a Digimon with 6000 DP or less when I have 1 or less security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [On Play] effect, when my security is 1 or less. Can I choose to play a Digimon with the [Angel]\u00a0trait or [Fallen Angel]\u00a0trait from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the activation of this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect of this card, does this card count as a card with [Dex]\u00a0in its name in the trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the activation of this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect, can I choose to play a purple or black level 3 Digimon when I have 5 or more Digimon with [Dex]\u00a0in its name in the trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution cards will remain in the trash. Only this card will come into play.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will this Digimon come back into play with its digivolution cards during the activation of its [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this Digimon will be treated as a new Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has an inherited effect with an [On Deletion] effect that was deleted  and then comes into play, can I choose the unresolved effect to be resolved when it comes into play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player of this card chooses.\n",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the arrangement order and the cards to be returned to the bottom of them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes it is possible to target a Digi-Egg with this effect, however it will be returned to the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to return a Digi-Egg to the bottom of the deck with this card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will only return 10 cards to the bottom of your opponent\u2019s deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: When activating the [When Digivolving] effect, if I have 2 Digimon with the [Mega]\u00a0trait, does that mean I can return 20 cards to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if that is the case do return as much as possible to the bottom of the deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the [When Digivolving] effect activate when my opponent has 9 or less trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect is mandatory to be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible not to activate [Start of Your Turn] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the opponent\u2019s security stack has 0 cards, it will activate. In this case, the security cards of the opponent can\u2019t be trashed, but \"trash the top card of this stack\" will be performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [Start of Your Turn] effect not activate when my opponent has 0 security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be trashed and because of that your opponent does not trash security.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card has no digivolution cards, does this Digimon still get trashed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if there is a valid target and you have not deleted equal to the number of [Mega]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards you must delete that target.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attempt to delete less Digimon than the number of [Mega]\u00a0trait in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will gain 2 memory due to the conditions being met.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the start of the turn, if both my opponent and I each have 3 security card, does that mean I gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will gain 2 memory due to the conditions being met.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the start of the turn, if both my opponent and I each have 8 or more cards in our hands, does that mean I gain 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [Your Turn] effect activate when my red or blue Digimon are active during the Unsuspend Phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will gain 2 memory due to the conditions being met.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the start of the turn, if both my opponent and I each have level 5 or higher Digimon, does that mean I gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will gain 2 memory due to the conditions being met.\n",
      "question": "Q: During the start of the turn, if both my opponent and I each have a suspended Digimon, does that mean I gain 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. [Start of Your Turn] effects are activated before Digimon are unsuspended in the Unsuspend Phase.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a suspended Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e or my Digimon is suspended, and becomes unsuspends in my Unsuspend Phase, does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect gain memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even you only reveal a [Tapirmon] or a 2-colored black card you can add both cards to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this effect not allow you to add cards to your hand unless you reveal a [Tapirmon] and a 2-colored black card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can you add a card that has the effect of treating it as another color, such as \"You can treat this card as red\" to your hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only reveal a card with the [X Antibody]/[X Antibody]\u00a0trait, you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card's effect, does it mean that I can\u2019t add both cards unless I add both a card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No because the effect stated \"Add to hand\", thus you are required to add as much as possible from the revealed cards. You are required to add cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait and [X Antibody] to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution requirements still apply.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card\u2019s [Main] effect, can I digivolve my Digimon to any card with [Shoutmon]\u00a0in its name by ignoring the digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s [Main] effect be stacked with \"Add 1000 to the maximum DP you can choose with DP-based deletion effects\" to make it able to delete a Digimon with 11000 DP or lower?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Choose any number of your opponent\u2019s Digimon so that the total DP of those Digimon adds up to 11000 or less, such as two 3000 DP Digimon and a 5000 DP Digimon, or two DP 4000 Digimon and a DP 3000 Digimon, and then activate the effect on those Digimon\n",
      "question": "Q: The card reads, 'Choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 11000 or less'. What does that actually mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You are free to choose so long as the total DP is 11000 or less. However, you must choose at least 1 Digimon if your opponent has any Digimon with DP 11000 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I deliberately choose fewer targets so that the total DP is less than 11000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Your opponent\u2019s Digimon\u2019s DP will only be reduced after Golemon is Deleted when this card\u2019s effect has finished activating. You may not choose an additional target at that point\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT4-066 Golemon] and I include Golemon as one of the targeted Digimon my opponent\u2019s other Digimon\u2019s DP will be reduced by 1000 when Golemon is Deleted. Can I include that loss of DP in my calculations when selecting Digimon to target?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.\n",
      "question": "Q: With this card\u2019s [Main] effect, can I choose my suspended Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name to attack the player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\" does that mean I can activate the effect, if I have cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using the [Main] effect to perform an attack, does the [When Attacking] effect of the attacking Digimon activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t. This card\u2019s effect only allows you to attack the opponent.\n",
      "question": "Q: When using this card\u2019s [Main] effect, If I have a card effect that allows me to attack my opponent\u2019s active Digimon, can I choose to attack the active Digimon instead?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\" does that mean I can activate the effect, if I have cards with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card effect activate even if my opponent only has 1 suspended Digimon or Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long the conditions are met. It will activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card if there is a Digimon that digivolves into a level 6 Digimon with the [Machine]\u00a0trait during the turn it was played, or when a level 6 Digimon with the [Machine]\u00a0trait comes into play, will that Digimon activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t. This effect applies to all levels. The part of opponent Digimon with 7 play cost or lower applies to the effect of \"Can\u2019t attack the player\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of \"Your opponent can\u2019t increase either players' security\" only apply to your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 7 play cost or lower?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The cards are not considered to be added back into security.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card was used previously and then the opponent uses an effect that reveals cards from security. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The rest of the cards are returned to security. Returning a card revealed by an effect from a hidden location, such as a deck or security, in its original location is not considered to have increased/decreased the number of cards from the original location, so this card's effect will not impact that situation.\n",
      "question": "Q: While this card's \"cards can't be added to security stacks by your opponent's effects\" is active, I digivolve into [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)] to reveal all of my opponent's security. What happens to the card revealed from the security?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution requirements still apply.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card\u2019s [Main] effect, can I digivolve my Digimon in to any card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait by ignoring the digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to place the card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait that was revealed by this card effect and trashed, at the bottom of 1 of your Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution requirements still apply.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card\u2019s [Main] effect, can I digivolve my Digimon to any card with [Dex]/[DeathX]\u00a0in its name by ignoring the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it\u2019s possible if the conditions are met.\n",
      "question": "Q: By digivolving with this cards effect, is it possible to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t. It is only applied to 1 Digimon. For the effect \"Then,\" you can select another Digimon other than the selected Digimon for \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on 1 of your opponent's Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the activation of the [Main] effect if I trash 2 cards from my hand, can I \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on 2 of your opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e will be activated twice. Even if the top card becomes a Tamer or Option card, the top card will continue to be trashed by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: During the activation of the [Main] effect if I trash 2 cards from my hand, will I \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on 1 of your opponent's Digimon twice or \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on 2 of your opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It performs \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e 3 times on the same Digimon. So you must do as much as you can.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e on 1 of my opponent's Digimon, or does it perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e 3 times on the same Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the [Main] effect allows it to be placed into 1 of your Digimon digivolution cards. Like Digimon and Digi-Egg cards, this card can activate it\u2019s inherited effect when it\u2019s in its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is an option card, but it has inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution requirements still apply.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, can I digivolve my Digimon to any card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait by ignoring the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it\u2019s possible if the conditions are met.\n",
      "question": "Q: By digivolving with this card effect, is it possible to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can't be trashed by \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect due to its effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be trashed with the effect of \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e\u00a0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s like level 2 Digimon, this card can\u2019t exist in the battle area, thus it will be trashed. If there are digivolution cards beneath this card, they will be trashed as well.\n",
      "question": "Q: What will happen if this card becomes the top card of a Digimon due to \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can\u2019t be trashed, however the card above this card will be trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: What will happen if my opponent card effect such as \"trash 2 digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of your opponent Digimon\" when this card is at the bottom of the digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"as the bottom digivolution card\" tells you where to place X Antibody, it is not part of the conditionl.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be placed as a digivolution card underneath a Digimon which has [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards but not as the bottom digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of \"If both players have 3 or more Digimon in play in total\" include both you and your opponent?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, all Digimon without [X Antibody]\u00a0trait will be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: When both players have 3 or more Digimon, is it possible to only delete 1 Digimon without with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your current turn will resume without a turn change.\n",
      "question": "Q: By using the [End of Your Turn] effect, if the memory returns to your side from your opponent\u2019s side, will it be considered as the changing from your turn to your opponent's turn, and then to your turn again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can because it\u2019s not considered trashing.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I return [BT9-109 X Antibody] from this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards to the bottom of the deck when using [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You would resolve both the lose 2 memory effect of Gravity Crush and the [End of Your Turn] effect of this card. If after both have resolved, the memory is at 0 or more on your side. Your Main Phase will continue, if the turn would end again Gravity Crush will trigger again. The same will apply for any other [End of Your Turn], [End of All Turns], and [End of Opponent's Turn] effects. (For more information see End of Turn Procedures)\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I have activated [BT1-090 Gravity Crush] in the same turn as I activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it counts the overall total of your opponent\u2019s Digimon and Tamer. If your opponent has 2 Digimon and 1 Tamer, the cost reduction will be 9.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card comes into play, do I reduce 3 cost for each pair of your opponent\u2019s Digimon and Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, after this card has \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e a Digimon into a Level 2 Digimon, it will be deleted by this effect before it gets trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect delete Level 2 Digimon before they get trashed by Rules Processing?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only add either 1 of them to your hand\n",
      "question": "Q: When I reveal both a Digimon card with [Agumon]\u00a0in its name and a Tamer card from this card's Evolution Source effect, can I add them both to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a Tamer card or a Digimon card with  [Agumon]\u00a0in its name that is not Red with this card's Evolution Source effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [When Attacking] effects activate before a block can be declared. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and attacks the opposing player, and my opponent's Digimon blocks the attack. Does this card's effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [When Attacking] effects activate before a block can be declared. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its Evolution Source attacks my opponent Player, and my opponent's Digimon blocks the attack. Does this card's effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect can only play cards that are named [Tai Kamiya].\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play card with [Tai Kamiya]\u00a0in its name like [Tai Kamiya & Matt Ishida] with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. When revealed from your deck by an effect, this card's effect does not activate, so it is not treated as a Green Digimon card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this is revealed from my deck by effects like [ST4-03 Tentomon], can I treat this card as a Green Digimon card and add it to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as it's during your turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I evolve this Digimon in my Battle Area into a Digimon that has an digivolution requirement of [Green LV4]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. As this Digimon's effect is not active in the Breeding Area, it is not treated as a Green Digimon. This Digimon's [Your Turn] effect is only active in the Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I evolve this Digimon in my breeding area into a Digimon that has an digivolution requirement of [Green LV4]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [When Attacking] effects activate before a block can be declared. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card's inherited effect attacks my opponent, and my opponent's Digimon blocks the attack. Does this card's effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as \uff1cPiercing\uff1e has already activated, you continue to perform the rest of the security checks.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card's inherited effect also has \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from another card's effect. This Digimon then attacked my opponent's Digimon and performs Security Check due to its \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. The 1st check's Security effect activates \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [When Attacking] effects activate before a block can be declared.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks my opponent Player, and my opponent's Digimon blocks the attack. Does this card's effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [When Attacking] effects activate before a block can be declared. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks my opponent Player, and my opponent's Digimon blocks the attack. Does this card's effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect destroy my oppponent's Digimon that gained \uff1cBlocker\uff1e from an Option card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [When Attacking] effects activate before a block can be declared. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks my opponent Player, and my opponent's Digimon blocks the attack. Does this card's effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only add either 1 of them to your hand\n",
      "question": "Q: When I reveal both a Digimon card with [Gabumon]\u00a0in its name and a Tamer card from this card's Evolution Source effect, can I add them both to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a Tamer card or a Digimon card with  [Gabumon]\u00a0in its name that is not Blue with this card's Evolution Source effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect does not trigger when your already unsuspended Digimon receives an effect that unsuspends it.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my turn's Main Phase, I activate an effect that unsuspends my already unsuspended Digimon with this card's inherited effect. Does this card's inherited effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect can only play cards that are named [Matt Ishida].\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play card with [Matt Ishida]\u00a0in its name like [Tai Kamiya & Matt Ishida] with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If this Digimon attacks, Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e cannot redirect the attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's inherited effect of \"This Digimon can't be blocked\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can my Digimon with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name that has this card's inherited effect attack my opponent's Digimon that are suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. It cannot be suspended by \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name that has this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name that has this card's inherited effect attacks, even if I cannot block, can I still declare to activate my Digimon's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You get Memory +1.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates, how much Memory do I plus if I have 5 cards in my  hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Attacking] effect, can I target my opponent's Digimon that has a [On Deletion] effect gained from an Option card's effect or gained from its digivolution card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you have 4 Blue cards, there is only 1 colour, so it only gets +1000DP. No matter how many cards of the same colour it has in its Evolution Sources, it only counts as 1 colour for the effect's [For each different colour].\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 Blue cards in this Digimon's Evolution Sources, does it get +4000DP from this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as you have 3 or more Security at the point of time when this card's Evolution Source effect activates, the effect is not lost for the turn even if your Security is reduced to 2 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect gives my opponent's Digimon -2000DP. On the same turn my Security is reduced to 2 or less. Does this card's effect of -2000DP disappear?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as your Security becomes 3 due to this card being checked, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 4 Security when my opponent's Digimon attacks. This card is then revealed from the Check. Does this card's [Security] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as you have 3 or more Security at the point of time when this card's Evolution Source effect activates, the effect is not lost until the end of your opponent's next turn even if your Security is reduced to 2 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect gives this Digimon +1000DP. On the same turn my Security is reduced to 2 or less. Does this card's effect of +1000DP disappear?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. As your Security was increased once due to the effect of \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e, you get Memory +1.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards in play. My [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi] activates its effect to add 1 Yellow card from my Security to my hand, then my Security increased from the effect of \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e. Do I get the Memory +1 from this card's Evolution Source effect even though the number of my Security is the same in the end?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as you have 3 or more Security at the point of time when this card's Evolution Source effect activates, the effect is not lost until the end of your opponent's next turn even if your Security is reduced to 2 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect gives this Digimon +4000DP. On the same turn my Security is reduced to 2 or less. Does this card's effect of +4000DP disappear?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as [All of your opponent's Security Digimon] receives the effect [For the turn], all of the Security Digimon your opponent reveals from a Check gets -3000DP until the turn ends\n",
      "question": "Q: After this card's [When Attacking] effect activates and that attack ends, does my opponent's Securitiy Digimon still get -3000DP during my other Digimon's attack on the player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as you have 3 or more Security at the point of time when this card's inherited effect activates, the effect is not lost for the turn even if your Security is reduced to 2 or less.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect gives my opponent's Security Digimon and 1 Digimon -3000DP. On the same turn my Security is reduced to 2 or less. Does this card's effect of -3000DP disappear?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving onto an unsuspended Digimon into this card, can I still activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect to discard 1 of my Security?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cost is reduced by 1 even when you digivolve this Digimon or your other Digimon as long as the condition is met.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect reduce the digivolution cost by 1 affect Digimon other than itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as it's the same turn, the effect continues until the next time you evolve your Digimon into a Digimon card that has the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait.\n",
      "question": "Q: After this card's inherited effect activates, I digivolve my Digimon into a Digimon card that does not have [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait. Does this inherited effect then become nullified?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as it\u2019s the same turn, you reduce the digivolution cost by 1 for each attack. However, the mumber of digivolution cost reduced is reset once you evolve your Digimon into a Digimon card that has the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its digivolution Source attacks 2 or more times in the same turn due to other effects. Does the effect of reducing digivolution cost by 1 stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution cost reduction from this card's effect cannot be used in evolutions in your breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also reduce the digivolution cost by 1 when I evolve my Digimon in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution cost is only reduced by 1 when you are evolving your Digimon into a Digimon card in your hand that has the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon that has the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait in my Battle Area evolves, is the digivolution cost reduced by 1 from this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As long as it was successfully activated and resolved when it attacked you can still reduce the digivolution cost of your next digivolution by 1 even if the Digimon is deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks and is deleted during the attack. Can I still reduce the digivolution cost of the next time I digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the timing for [When Attacking] effects to trigger has already passed, it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: After my Digimon evolved from from this card's [When Attacking] effect, if that Digimon has a [When Attacking] effect, does it activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues as per normal. The turn does not pass until that attack ends\n",
      "question": "Q: After paying the Memory cost to evolve my Digimon from this card's [When Attacking] effect, the Memory is put to 1 or more on my opponent's side. What happens to that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it says [You can evolve], it doesn't have to evolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I evolve this Digimon from its [When Attacking]\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot ignore the digivolution conditions.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I evolve my Digimon into a Digimon card in my hand that has the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait while ignoring its Evolution conditions with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as \uff1cPiercing\uff1e has already activated, you continue to perform the security checks.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card's Evolution Source effect also has \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e from another card's effect. This Digimon then attacked my opponent's Digimon and performs Security Check due to its \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. The 1st check's Security effect activates \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on my attacking Digimon, discarding 1 card from this Digimon stack from the top. This Digimon then becomes a Digimon that does not have [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name, nor [Free]\u00a0trait, hence losing its \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. Does that mean I can't perform the 2nd check?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues. The turn does not pass yet. At the end of that attack after all effects triggered from that attack have activated, if the Memory is at 1 or more on your opponent's side, the turn is then passed.\n",
      "question": "Q: After paying the Memory cost to evolve my Digimon from this card's [When Attacking] effect, the Memory is put to 1 or more on my opponent's side. What happens to that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. As the timing for [When Attacking] effects to trigger has already passed.\n",
      "question": "Q: My [EX1-035 Kabuterimon] attacks, and evolves into this card with its [When Attacking] effect. Can I continue to use this card's [When Attacking] effect to evolve again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it says [You can evolve], it doesn't have to evolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I evolve this Digimon from its [When Attacking]\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot ignore the digivolution conditions.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I evolve my Digimon into a Digimon card in my hand that has the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait while ignoring its Evolution conditions with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon becomes active even when your other Digimon with the [Insectoid]/[Ancient Insectoid]\u00a0trait destroys an opponent's Digimon in battle and survives.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon become Active from its effect only when this Digimon itself destroys an opponent's Digimon in battle and survives?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it refers to the name of the Digimon that has this card as its digivolution card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does [Digimon with the same name as this Digimon] refer to Digimon named [Keramon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it refers to the name of the Digimon that has this card in its Evolution Sources.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does [Digimon with the same name as this Digimon] refer to Digimon named [Kurisarimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it says [You can reveal], you can choose not to activate it. However once you choose to activate it and opened cards from your deck, you must fulfil the remainder of the effect as much as possible\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it says [You can reveal], you can choose not to activate it. However once you choose to activate it and opened cards from your deck, you must fulfil the remainder of the effect as much as possible\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it says [You can reveal], you can choose not to activate it. However once you choose to activate it and opened cards from your deck, you must fulfil the remainder of the effect as much as possible\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in Breeding Area are not subjected to this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect also activate when my opponent evolves a Digimon in their Breeding Area into a LV5 or higher Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it refers to the name of the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does [Digimon with the same name as this Digimon] refer to Digimon named [Infermon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this Digimon is destroyed before its effect can activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent evolves their Digimon into a LV5 or higher Digimon, but its [When Digivolving] effect destroys this Digimon. Does this Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] effect give me Memory +1 in this case?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this effect does not activate in the Breeding Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I evolve this Digimon in my Breeding Area into a Digimon card in my hand with [Etemon]\u00a0in its name, is the evolution cost reduced by 1?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, regardless of how many Digimon are destroyed at the same time, this card's inherited effect only lets you draw 1 card per turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: When 2 of my oppoent's Digimon are deleted at the same time by 1 effecet, does this card's inherited effect let me draw 2 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack the player.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I have no Digimon with [Myotismon]\u00a0in its name, can this Digimon attack the player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As this card's [Your Turn] effect is an effect that disallows you from choosing your opponent's Digimon as the target of this Digimon's attack, a battle happens as per normal when it is blocked.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon attacks the player while I do not have any Digimon with [Myotismon]\u00a0in its name, my opponent's Digimon blocks that attack. What happens?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I return this card itself to my hand with this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card's inherited effect activates do I have to return a level 4 or lower card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says [You can discard], you can choose not to activate it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this effect does not activate in the Breeding Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I evolve this Digimon in my Breeding Area into a Digimon card in my hand with [Myotismon]\u00a0in its name, is the evolution cost reduced by 1?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card is not present anymore before the attack ended, its [End of Attack] effect does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks the player, and [BT2-105 Spider Shooter] is checked, activating \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on this Digimon, thus discarding this card. Does this card's [End of Attack] effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as this card's [On Deletion] effect can only play a card named [Agumon].\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I Play [Agumon - Bond of Bravery]/[Agumon Expert] from my trash with this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I play a Purple LV4 or below Digimon card that has \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e in it's inherited effect from my trash with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, regardless of how many Digimon are destroyed at the same time, this card's [Your Turn] effect only lets you draw 1 card per turn\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon's [On Play] effect destroys 4 of my opponent Digimon, does its [Your Turn] effect let me draw 4 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if Diaboromon is destroyed by a [When Attacking] effect, your Diaboromon Token has already lost its \uff1cBlocker\uff1e at the [Reaction]/[Counter] timing.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon and a Diaboromon Token in my Battle Area. My opponent's Digimon attacks, and destroys this Digimon with its [When Attacking] effect. Can I still activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e of my Diaboromon Token to block that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as the [Security] effects has already activated when it was Checked, you play a Token regardless of the outcome of that battle.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Security] effect, can I play a Token at the end of this the battle with the attacking Digimon even if this card lost the battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Token is played first. Proceed with the next Check only after all [Security] effects and any other effects from that battle that were triggered are activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Security] effect, after this card is checked, the attacking Digimon still has remaining Security Checks. Is the Token played first or do the remaining Checks happen first?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my LV5 or above Digimon that has Evolution Sources is destroyed, can I put this Tamer to Rest with its [All Turns] effect to get Memory +1 even if my Breeding Area is not empty?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it deletes a single Digimon that fulfils both conditions.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card delete 1 Digimon that has both \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and 1 Digimon with 6000 DP or less each?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent loses the 2 memory. The memory marker will be moved 2 spaces towards you every time your opponent attacks with a Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card, do I lose 2 memory every time my opponent attacks with a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as the effect says [All of your opponent's Digimon], Digimon that is put to the Battle Area after this card is used also receive the effect of this card\n",
      "question": "Q: On my opponent's next turn after using this card, do my opponent's newly played Digimon and Digimon moved from their Breeding Area also have the effect \"[When Attacking] Memory -2\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if the Memory is at 1 or more on your side, as your opponent is in the middle of an attack using \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, it is still considered to be your opponent's turn, so this card's effect is still valid. The Memory is increased by 2 as seen from your side\n",
      "question": "Q: On my opponent's next turn after using this card, my opponent's Digimon attacks using \uff1cBlitz\uff1e while the Memory is at 1 or more on my side. Does the Memory still increase by 2 as seen from my side?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You trash a Red Digimon card. You are to trash a Digimon card that is the same colour as the Digimon in your Battle Area you are going to digivolve from for this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I digivolve my Red Digimon into a White Digimon. Do I trash a Red or White Digimon card for this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect cannot reduce the digivolution cost of digivolving Digimon in your Breeding Area.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving my Digimon in my Breeding Area, does this card's effect reduce the digivolution cost by 4?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: On my turn after using this card, I digivolve a Blue Digimon in my Battle Area that has the effect [This Digimon is also treated as a Red Digimon]. Can I trash a Red Digimon to reduce the digivolution cost by 4 with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You don't trash the card in your hand with this effect until you digivolve. [BT7-085 Takuya Kanbara]'s [Main] effect reads, \"By placing 5 cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait from your trash under this Tamer in any order, digivolve into [EmperorGreymon]\". As such, you place the cards under [Takuya Kanbara] before you begin digivolving, at which point you can trash a card in your hand with this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I activate [BT7-085 Takuya Kanbara]'s [Main] effect. Can I use this card's effect specifically to trash a card with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait from my hand first, so that I can place it under [BT7-085 Takuya Kanbara] using its effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The card you trash can match any one of the Digimon\u2019s colors. For example, when digivolving a blue/green Digimon, you can trash either a blue or a green card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving from a multicolor Digimon, what color cards can I trash with this card\u2019s effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The card you trash can match any of the colors of either Digimon. For example, when DNA digivolving a blue Digimon and green Digimon, you can trash either a blue or green card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I reduce the memory cost of a DNA digivolution with this card's effect? If I can, what color cards can I trash with this card\u2019s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, when I activate an effect that performs a digivolution. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will trigger the effects of cards like [BT6-079 SkullGreymon].\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card's lingering effect treated as the card being trashed by one of \"your effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve on top of a tamer using the effect of [BT7-112 Susanoomon], can I use this card's effect to reduce the memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as activating [Security] effects do not count as Using an Option card, the [Security] effect activates as per normal\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I attack the player, and the Security check reveals an Option card. Does that Option card's [Security] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as activating the \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect of an option card that was already in the Battle Area do not count as using an Option card, you can activate it as per normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: On my turn after my opponent used this card, can I activate the \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect of the Option card that was placed in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The cards must be:\u30fbThe cards are in your hand or trash:\u30fbThey are cards that has the [Cyborg]\u00a0trait\u30fbThey are Red or Black Digimon cards\u30fbThey are level 5 Digimon cardsAs long as the above conditions are met and have different card numbers, you can add those cards into this card's digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: I don't really understand the conditions of placing cards in this card's digivolution cards from its [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as the effect says [You may trash], you can choose not to trash them.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is deleted while it has 2 or more level 5 Digimon cards in its digivolution cards, can I choose not to trash them to let this Digimon be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot unsuspend a Digimon if this card is not deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is chosen to be deleted by [BT5-106 Demonic Disaster], if it uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion do I still get to unsuspend a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As the requirement of \"when this Digimon attacks and deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives the battle\" of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e was not met, it does not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e attacked my Digimon, and my Digimon lost the battle. I then activate my Digimon's [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. What happens to my opponent's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because the Digimon will still have \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and it deleted a Digimon battle and survived it will trigger.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e gained from [BT8-103 Lightning Blade] and battles a Digimon with equal DP. I activate its [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it lost \uff1cPiercing\uff1e before the timing it would trigger and if it doesn't trigger it cannot activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from [EX1-008 MetalGreymon] in its digivolution cards, this card attacks a Digimon with equal DP and uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion by trashing [EX1-008 MetalGreymon]. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's inherited effect be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's \uff1cBlocker\uff1e Digimon suspends by blocking?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it is a Digi-Egg card, you must put it in the Digi-Egg deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card go in the Main deck or the Digi-Egg deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be placed in the breeding area and become a Digimon without a Lv.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is hatched during the Breeding Phase, should it be placed in the breeding area or the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without Lv. (Excluding special digivolution requirements).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have Lv., Can I digivolve from this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be attacked. The effect that \"can attack even an unsuspended Digimon\" is an effect that gives additional targets for an attack by that Digimon, so it cannot be prevented by \"not being affected by the opponent's effect\" on this card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card in the battle area be attacked by an opponent's Digimon that has the effect of \"attacking even an unsuspended Digimon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card can be deleted depending on the result of the battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card in the battle area be deleted if it is attacked by an opponent's Digimon and has the same DP or a higher opponent?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effects you activate will also affect this card. However, if this card moves to your hand, deck, or security, it's a Digi-Egg card, so instead of moving to those locations, it's placed face down at the bottom of your Digi-Egg deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card receive the effects that I activated, such as \"delete one of your Digimon\" and \"resting one of your Digimon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card in the battle area deleted by my own effect or move to my hand / deck / security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of [BT8-071 Psychemon] does not target this Digimon, so the effect of reducing the play cost by this card will not work.\n",
      "question": "Q: When the opponent has [BT8-071 Psychemon], is it possible to reduce the play cost of a Digimon [D-Reaper]\u00a0trait by using this Digimon's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not. The Digi-Egg card is never placed in Security and just sent straight to the bottom of the Digi-Egg Deck from the Battle Area.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use the effect of [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] to place this card in Security, would this trigger the effect of [BT6-044 Dynasmon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a card with [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name and [Takato Matsuki], you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is the effect of this card not added to the hand unless there are both [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name and [Takato Matsuki] among the four opened cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of this card is \"add... and...\", so you should add cards to your hand as much as possible. In this situation, you must add both a card with [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name and [Takato Matsuki] to your hand one by one.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect of this card, if there are both [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name and [Takato Matsuki] among the four opened cards, add only one of them to your hand. Is it possible to put one back under the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the effect of selecting the target to be deleted refers to its DP, such as \"Delete Digimon with DP X or less\" and \"Choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 8000 or less and delete them\". This effect would increase the value of the referenced DP by +1000. However, it will not work on an effect taht references the DP not written in the effect text, such as \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon whose DP is less than this Digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"Add +1000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon.\" of this card mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card increase the upper limit of the DP deletion effect that I activated by +1000 even if it is not the effect of this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It only affects the maximum DP, so [BT3-109 Plasma Stake] will still delete only Digimon with 12000 DP or more.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect increase the minimum DP deletion of [BT3-109 Plasma Stake] from 12000 DP to 13000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the effect of selecting the target to be deleted refers to its DP, such as \"Delete Digimon with DP X or less\" and \"Choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 8000 or less and delete them\". This effect would increase the value of the referenced DP by +1000. However, it will not work on an effect taht references the DP not written in the effect text, such as \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon whose DP is less than this Digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"Add +2000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon.\" of this card mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will. If you have a Red Tamer in the battle area, you can choose your opponent's Digimon so that the total DP is 8000 or less with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [When Attacking] effect of this card, \"Choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 6000 or less\", receive the effect of \"Add +2000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of \"Add +2000 DP to the maximum DP of your effects that delete Digimon\" of this card increase the maximum DP of a deletion effect that I activated other than the effect of this Digimon by +2000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It only affects the maximum DP, so [BT3-109 Plasma Stake] will still delete only Digimon with 12000 DP or more.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect increase the minimum DP deletion of [BT3-109 Plasma Stake] from 12000 DP to 13000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the time when the effect is activated, your opponent has no Digimon with 10000 DP or less, or the selected Digimon does not get deleted by this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: When does the condition for \"If this effect does not delete a Digimon\" from its [When Digivolving] effect be satisfied?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a suitable target, you must delete it. if the deletion is prevented, you can discard the top 5 of each player's decks.\n",
      "question": "Q: If there is an opponent's Digimon with 10000 DP or less, can I discard the top 5 of each player's decks by activating the [When Digivolving] effect of this card and not choosing an opponent's Digimon to delete?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be added to my hand as a card with [Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name when it is opened from the deck with the [On Play] effect of [EX2-008 Guilmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) that activated prevents the deletion \"from this effect\" and the condition of \"If this effect does not delete a Digimon\", so the effect of \"trashing 5 cards from the top of each player's deck\" is performed.\n",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon is deleted by the [When Digivolving] effect of this card, but the opponent activates \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) and the selected Digimon isn't deleted, but the Digimon that activated \uff1cDecoy\uff1e  (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) is deleted. Is the condition of \"If this effect does not delete a Digimon\" fulfilled?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [ChaosGallantmon] even in the hand, deck, trash, and digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as effects do not activate in the breeding area, this card/Digimon is not treated as being [ChaosGallantmon] in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect treat this card as being [ChaosGallantmon] even in breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect is \"this effect does not increase the security to 6 or more\", so it will only increase until it reaches 5.\n",
      "question": "Q: With this card's effect, does the security increase with \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e only until the number of cards reaches 5?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a card with [Kyubimon]/[Taomon]/[Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name and [Rika Nonaka], you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is the effect of this card not added to the hand unless there are both [Kyubimon]/[Taomon]/[Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name and [Rika Nonaka] among the four opened cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of this card is \"add... and...\", so you should add cards to your hand as much as possible. In this situation, you must add both a card with [Kyubimon]/[Taomon]/[Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name and [Rika Nonaka] to your hand one by one.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect of this card, if there are both [Kyubimon]/[Taomon]/[Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name and [Rika Nonaka] among the four opened cards, add only one of them to your hand. Is it possible to put one back under the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's evolutionary effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's evolutionary effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's inherited effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's inherited effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with the effect of \"While you have [Shu-Chong Wong] in play, your [Lopmon] can digivolve into this card in your hand for a digivolution cost of 3, ignoring its digivolution requirements\". Is it possible to reduce the evolution cost by effects such as [EX1-071 Win Rate: 60%!]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect to digivolve my Digimon in the Battle Area, can I use it to digivolve my [Lopmon] into this card while I have [Shu-Chong Wong] in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's evolutionary effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's evolutionary effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect was not active when the Option card was used.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have this Digimon in play, and use [EX2-070 Digivolution Plug-In S] to digivolve this Digimon into a Level 6 Digimon. Does this card's inherited [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the effect of this card can be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They will be trashed. This effect is the only card that can be placed in the digivolution cards of your Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is placed in the digivolution cards of your Digimon with the [End of Attack] effect of this card, what happens to the digivolution cards under this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to place this card in the digivolution cards of my Digimon that does not have Lv. With the [End of Attack] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will have both effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card has two inherited effects, but if this card becomes a digivolution card, will both be available?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. The effect of this card has been changed to \"1 of your other Digimon\".\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible for this card to target itself when choosing to place it underneath a Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have two or more, you will only gain 1 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card add 2 memory if I have 4 black tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you don't have your own tamer, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e will work as usual.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card was given \uff1cPiercing\uff1e for some effect, and attacks an opponent's Digimon without a tamer in play and deletes the opponent's Digimon in battle. Can this Digimon perform security checks by the effect of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect of this card prevents it from declaring an attack against the opponent's Digimon, so if it is blocked by the opponent's Digimon, it will battle a Digimon as normal.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card attacks a player and is blocked by an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it still cannot declare attacks against Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has [BT8-067 MetalGreymon] in its digivolution cost. Can it attack Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e against the opponent's Digimon that unsuspend during the opponent's Unsuspend Phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you would choose which Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: For the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card, when multiple opponent's Digimon unsuspend during the opponent's active phase, can I choose which Digimon will be \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is a mandatory effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible for the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card to not consume [Once Per Turn] without deliberately exerting \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e when the opponent's Digimon is unsuspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the unsuspended Digimon has no digivolution cards or is a level 3 Digimon, \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e will still be attempted.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible for the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card to be unable to \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e if the opponent's selected Digimon does not have a digivolution card or it's a level 3 Digimon that unsuspends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if your opponent chooses which Digimon's [Your Turn] effect to activate first and trash from hand for. All Digimon are unsuspended at the same time after all the [Your Turn] effects granted by [BT7-055 Ebonwumon] have been resolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I also have [BT7-055 Ebonwumon] in play, does my opponent get to choose which Digimon is \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e because they choose which Digimon to discard for first?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it won't work if you don't have any tamers.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Attacking] effect work if I don't have any tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can select and activate the same effect multiple times.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it okay to activate the same effect more than once when there are multiple tamers of this card when using this card's [When Attacking] to activate its [When Digivolving]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose a non-original [When Digivolving] effect that was given to this Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect choose another [When Digivolving] effect that was not its original [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a card with [Beelzemon]\u00a0in its name and [Ai & Mako], you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is the effect of this card not added to the hand unless there are both [Beelzemon]\u00a0in its name and [Ai & Mako] among the four opened cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of this card is \"add... and...\", so you should add cards to your hand as much as possible. In this situation, you must add both a card with [Beelzemon]\u00a0in its name and [Ai & Mako] to your hand one by one.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect of this card, if there are both [Beelzemon]\u00a0in its name and [Ai & Mako] among the four opened cards, add only one of them to your hand. Is it possible to put one back under the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the deck are not considered to be \"trashed from the deck\" even if they were trashed by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card was revealed and trashed with the \"Reveal... from your deck\" effect. In that case, will the effect of \"when this card is trashed from the deck\" be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect has a card number specified, so if the card number is different from that of [EX2-039 Impmon], the effect of \"when this card is discarded from the deck\" will be triggered.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is discarded from the deck by the effect of [BT2-068 Impmon], will the effect of \"when this card is trashed from the deck\" be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it was trashed by the effect of the top card which was a [EX2-039 Impmon].\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has [BT2-007 Pagumon] in its digivolution cards, and declares an attack. The [When Attacking] inherited effect trashes another copy of this card. Does that Impmon's effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it was trashed by the effect of the top card which was a [EX2-039 Impmon].\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has [ST6-01 Pagumon] in its digivolution cards, and is deleted. The [On Deletion] inherited effect trashes another copy of this card. Does that Impmon's effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Each player chooses from their own hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the cards in hand to be discarded by the [When Digivolving] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be after the draw. [When Digivolving] effects trigger when the draw of the digivolution bonus is finished.\n",
      "question": "Q: When does the [When Digivolving] effect of this card activate before or after the draw from the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If a player has 5 or less cards in your hand, that player does not discard.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the [When Digivolving] effect of this card if a player has 5 or less cards in your hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the deck are not considered to be \"trashed from the deck\" even if they were trashed by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card was revealed and trashed with the \"Reveal... from your deck\" effect. In that case, will the effect of \"when this card is trashed from the deck\" be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect is triggered both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. After digivolving and activating as a [When Digivolving] effect, if you attack with this Digimon next turn, it will be triggered as a [When Attacking] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: There are two timings for this card's effect, [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. What does this mean?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve my Red Tamer into a Digimon with the effect of [BT4-011 Agunimon]. Can I suspend this card to gain 1 memory, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, and have 1 of my Digimon get +3000 DP for the turn?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A:  Normally, you are only allowed to put up to 4 copies of a card of the same Card Number. This card's effect changes the number of copies of this exact card allowed in your deck to 50 instead.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"You can put up to 50 cards that has the same Card Number as this card in your Deck\" mean exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you only have a card with the [D-Reaper]\u00a0trait and [ADR-02 Searcher], you can add it to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is the effect of this card not added to the hand unless there are both [D-Reaper]\u00a0trait and [ADR-02 Searcher] among the three opened cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect of this card is \"add... and...\", so you should add cards to your hand as much as possible. In this situation, you must add both a card with the [D-Reaper]\u00a0trait and [ADR-02 Searcher] to your hand one by one.\n",
      "question": "Q: Due to the effect of this card, if there are both [D-Reaper]\u00a0trait and [ADR-02 Searcher] among the four opened cards, add only one of them to your hand. Is it possible to put one back under the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may add them both to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include 2 [ADR-02 Searcher]\n"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: In that case, all revealed cards will be returned to the bottom of the deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I activate the effect of this card without a [Mother D-Reaper]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, from the time it is played due to this effect, it will be treated as a normal Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is played from Security with its [Security] effect is that Digimon treated as a Security Digimon even in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, before the second check, the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card will give \uff1cSecurity Attack -1\uff1e (This Digimon checks 1 fewer security card) to the attacking opponent's Digimon, so the second check will not be performed and the attack will finish.\n",
      "question": "Q: An opponent Digimon with \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e attacks the player, this card is turned over at the first check, and is played to the battle area with the [Security] effect. If I have [Mother D-Reaper] in play with 6 or more digivolution cards, can the [Opponent's Turn] effect of this card prevent the opponent's second check?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a card without a level and you can't digivolve into this card (except with special digivolution).\n",
      "question": "Q: This card does not have a level. Can I digivolve from this card or digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may.\n",
      "question": "Q: It says, \"trash 7 or more digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of your [Mother D-Reaper]\". When this card would be played, can I trash 8 or more digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect \"sets the play cost to 0\" it does not reduce. So [BT8-071 Psychemon] does not prevent this card's play cost from becoming 0.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT8-071 Psychemon] in play, and I would play this card. Does this card's play cost get reduced?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will as it interrupts the digivolution. Therefore, even if you fail to evolve you will still obtain the effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attempt to digivolve into a Digimon with [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name, but the effect of [EX3-016 SnowAgumon] and [EX3-019 Paledramon] cause the digivolution to fail. Will the effect of \"[When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\" still be given to that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot declare an attack while you are in the middle of resolving an attack (from the first \uff1cBlitz\uff1e). The second \uff1cBlitz\uff1e will fail to declare an attack.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I gave my Digimon \"[When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e\" effect of this card. I digivolve into [BT5-086 Omnimon]. Since there are two instances of the same \"[When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e\" effect, can I activate the first \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, unsuspend, and then activate the second \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the new Digimon keeps the \"[When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e\" effect and if the memory is at 1 or more on the opponent's side, it can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e. (For more information see Persistent Effects)\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve into a Digimon with [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name but the memory remains at 0 or more on my side so \uff1cBlitz\uff1e cannot activate. If that same Digimon then digivolves into a Digimon without [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name, can that Digimon activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not triggered by a digivolution in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is this card's [Your Turn] effect triggered when my Digimon digivolves from level 5 to level 6 in the breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It cannot digivolve, and the level 6 Digimon card issued for evolution will be returned to your hand. The level 5 Digimon will be deleted and you will not pay the digivolution cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: When my level 5 digivolves to level 6, what happens if the effect of this card deletes the digivolving level 5 Digimon to disappear?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to use either the [When Digivolving] or [On Deletion] effect first.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve into a level 6 Digimon card with a [When Digivolving] effect and delete a Digimon with an [On Deletion] effect. Can I choose which effect to activate first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you do you will reduce the digivolution cost by the total.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve into a level 6 Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e, can I use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e to suspend a Digimon and then this card to delete the suspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not satisfy the condition.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does [Beelzemon: Blast Mode] satisfy the condition of the \"if the attacking Digimon is [Beelzemon]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If [ST14-02 Impmon] attacked and digivolved into [Beelzemon] with its [When Attacking] effect. Can I use this card's effect to digivolve [Beelzemon] into [Beelzemon: Blast Mode]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since the effect does not have \"you may\", if there is a suitable target, it cannot be intentionally excluded.\n",
      "question": "Q: When there is an opponent Digimon with 3000 DP or less, can this card \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e by intentionally not selecting that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to digivolve into a Digimon card with a special digivolution requirement memory cost of 3 or less by the effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card is intended for \"1 of your Digimon\", so you cannot be used for DNA Digivolution.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the effect of this card be used to digivolve a Digimon card with a DNA Digivolve with an digivolution cost of 3 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve a [Lopmon] into [EX2-022 Antylamon] while I have [Suzie Wong] in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve a [Machinedramon] into [BT7-017 Chaosdramon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e deducts the digivolution cost after the digivolving cards have been decided.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve into [BT3-056 Ceresmon], if I intend to use \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the two effects of this card and [BT6-087 Tai Kamiya] cannot interrupt each other.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve a [Agumon] into a [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] assuming colour is correct, while I have [BT6-087 Tai Kamiya] in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Your Turn] effect of [BT2-062 Infermon] deducts the digivolution cost after the digivolving cards have been decided.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve [BT2-062 Infermon] into [BT2-082 Diaboromon] using this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though the digivolution cost of [ST7-09 Gallantmon] is 3, the digivolution condition given by effect of [ST7-03 Guilmon] has a digivolution cost of 4.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve [ST7-03 Guilmon] into [ST7-09 Gallantmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, when you choose the Digimon to digivolve from for this card's effect, the Tamer is still being treated as a Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be used to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon that treats it as a Digimon, like [BT4-027 KendoGarurumon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the deck are not considered to be \"trashed from the deck\" even if they were trashed by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card was revealed and trashed with the \"Reveal... from your deck\" effect. In that case, will the effect of \"when this card is trashed from the deck\" be triggered?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card choose a Digimon that digivolves after revealing the card from the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolution requirements cannot be ignored.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the effect of this card digivolve my Digimon ignoring the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the effect of this card digivolve into a Digimon card that can evolve with special requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's an \"you may\" effect, so it's possible to choose not to digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: The effect of this card is that even if the revealed card contains a digivolvable Digimon card, can I add one Digimon card to my hand by intentionally not digivolving it?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not activated because it wasn't revealed in a security check.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the security card of the opponent trashed by the [When Attacking] effect of this card activate their [Security] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you win the game.\n",
      "question": "Q: When the opponent's security is 1 or more, it attacks with this Digimon, and the [When Attacking] effect trashes all of the opponent's security. If the attack is not blocked, can I win the game if it has a net positive security attack?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the deck are not considered to be \"trashed from the deck\" even if they were trashed by that effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card was revealed and trashed with the \"Reveal... from your deck\" effect. In that case, will the effect of \"when this card is trashed from the deck\" be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect cannot delete Digimon with no level.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect delete Digimon with no Level if my opponent does not have any Digimon with a level in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient DragonCategory:Baby DragonCategory:Beast DragonCategory:Bird DragonCategory:Dark DragonCategory:DragonCategory:Dragon WarriorCategory:Earth DragonCategory:Evil DragonCategory:Holy DragonCategory:Light DragonCategory:Machine DragonCategory:Mythical DragonCategory:Rock DragonCategory:Sky DragonCategory:DinosaurCategory:AnkylosaurCategory:PlesiosaurCategory:PterosaurCategory:CeratopsianCategory:Ancient DragonkinCategory:DragonkinCategory:Fire DragonCategory:Four Great DragonsCategory:Mini Dragon\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u7adc), does it include traits other than [Dragon] (\u7adc)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient DragonCategory:Baby DragonCategory:Beast DragonCategory:Bird DragonCategory:Dark DragonCategory:DragonCategory:Dragon WarriorCategory:Earth DragonCategory:Evil DragonCategory:Holy DragonCategory:Light DragonCategory:Machine DragonCategory:Mythical DragonCategory:Rock DragonCategory:Sky DragonCategory:DinosaurCategory:AnkylosaurCategory:PlesiosaurCategory:PterosaurCategory:CeratopsianCategory:Ancient DragonkinCategory:DragonkinCategory:Fire DragonCategory:Four Great DragonsCategory:Mini Dragon\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u7adc), does it include traits other than [Dragon] (\u7adc)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 Digimon card [Rock Dragon]/[Earth Dragon]/[Bird Dragon]/[Machine Dragon]/[Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait and 1 [Hina Kurihara], am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card [Rock Dragon]/[Earth Dragon]/[Bird Dragon]/[Machine Dragon]/[Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait and 1 [Hina Kurihara], am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient DragonCategory:Baby DragonCategory:Beast DragonCategory:Bird DragonCategory:Dark DragonCategory:DragonCategory:Dragon WarriorCategory:Earth DragonCategory:Evil DragonCategory:Holy DragonCategory:Light DragonCategory:Machine DragonCategory:Mythical DragonCategory:Rock DragonCategory:Sky DragonCategory:DinosaurCategory:AnkylosaurCategory:PlesiosaurCategory:PterosaurCategory:CeratopsianCategory:Ancient DragonkinCategory:DragonkinCategory:Fire DragonCategory:Four Great DragonsCategory:Mini Dragon\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u7adc), does it include traits other than [Dragon] (\u7adc)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot unsuspend a Digimon if this card is not deleted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is chosen to be deleted by [BT5-106 Demonic Disaster], if it uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion do I still get to unsuspend a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As the requirement of \"when this Digimon attacks and deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives the battle\" of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e was not met, it does not activate.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e attacked my Digimon, and my Digimon lost the battle. I then activate my Digimon's [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. What happens to my opponent's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because the Digimon will still have \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and it deleted a Digimon battle and survived it will trigger.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e gained from [BT8-103 Lightning Blade] and battles a Digimon with equal DP. I activate its [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it lost \uff1cPiercing\uff1e before the timing it would trigger and if it doesn't trigger it cannot activate.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from [EX1-008 MetalGreymon] in its digivolution cards, this card attacks a Digimon with equal DP and uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion by trashing [EX1-008 MetalGreymon]. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It performs \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e 3 times on the same Digimon. So you must do as much as you can.\n[4]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e on 1 of my opponent's Digimon, or does it perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e 3 times on the same Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e will be activated three times. Even if the top card becomes a Tamer or Option card, the top card will continue to be trashed by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e.\n[5]",
      "question": "Q: If I place 3 cards under this Digimon for its [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect and target a Digimon for \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e that has a Tamer or Option card as its topmost digivolution source, will this effect \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e past the Tamer or Option card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient DragonCategory:Baby DragonCategory:Beast DragonCategory:Bird DragonCategory:Dark DragonCategory:DragonCategory:Dragon WarriorCategory:Earth DragonCategory:Evil DragonCategory:Holy DragonCategory:Light DragonCategory:Machine DragonCategory:Mythical DragonCategory:Rock DragonCategory:Sky DragonCategory:DinosaurCategory:AnkylosaurCategory:PlesiosaurCategory:PterosaurCategory:CeratopsianCategory:Ancient DragonkinCategory:DragonkinCategory:Fire DragonCategory:Four Great DragonsCategory:Mini Dragon\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Dragon]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u7adc), does it include traits other than [Dragon] (\u7adc)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, because [BT11-015 OmniShoutmon] is also treated as a [Shoutmon] there would be two cards with the same name.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use both [BT11-015 OmniShoutmon] and an [Shoutmon] for its DigiXros requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the Digimon that gained \uff1cJamming\uff1e from the [On Play] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does \"that Digimon\" refer to the Digimon that gained \uff1cJamming\uff1e? Or does it refer to this card that was played from the digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, there will be two of this effect. So the total digivolution cost is +2.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this card underneath my Digimon in the battle area. Will the digivolution cost for my opponent's digivolution be increased by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When performing a DNA Digivolution, it increases by 1. Even though there are two Digimon digivolving, the effect will only take place once.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. My opponent performs a DNA Digivolution with two Digimon with no digivolution cards. How much does the digivolution cost increase by?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be increased by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. My opponent performs a DNA Digivolution with 1 Digimon with a digivolution card and 1 Digimon with no digivolution cards. Will the digivolution cost be increased by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Tamer is \"treated as red level 3 Digimon\" by the effect of Agunimon. So, the digivolution cost will be increased by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent digivolves using the effect of [BT4-011 Agunimon] on top of a Tamer. Will the digivolution cost be increased by +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer is \"treated as red level 3 Digimon\" by the effect of Agunimon so the cards underneath the Tamer are treated as digivolution cards. So, the digivolution cost will not be increased by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent digivolves using the effect of [BT4-011 Agunimon] on top of a Tamer that has a card underneath it. Will the digivolution cost be increased by +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cost will be considered to have failed. The revealed card for the digivolution will be returned to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon without digivolution cards digivolves, what happens if the digivolution cost is added by this effect, and as a result the digivolution cost cannot be paid?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the Digimon that gained \uff1cBlocker\uff1e from the [On Play] effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does \"that Digimon\" refer to the Digimon that gained \uff1cBlocker\uff1e? Or does it refer to this card that was played from the digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, there will be two of this effect. So the total digivolution cost is +2.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this card underneath my Digimon in the battle area. Will the digivolution cost for my opponent's digivolution be increased by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When performing a DNA Digivolution, it increases by 1. Even though there are two Digimon digivolving, the effect will only take place once.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. My opponent performs a DNA Digivolution with two Digimon with no digivolution cards. How much does the digivolution cost increase by?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be increased by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. My opponent performs a DNA Digivolution with 1 Digimon with a digivolution card and 1 Digimon with no digivolution cards. Will the digivolution cost be increased by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Tamer is \"treated as red level 3 Digimon\" by the effect of Agunimon. So, the digivolution cost will be increased by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent digivolves using the effect of [BT4-011 Agunimon] on top of a Tamer. Will the digivolution cost be increased by +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Tamer is \"treated as red level 3 Digimon\" by the effect of Agunimon so the cards underneath the Tamer are treated as digivolution cards. So, the digivolution cost will not be increased by 1.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent digivolves using the effect of [BT4-011 Agunimon] on top of a Tamer that has a card underneath it. Will the digivolution cost be increased by +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cost will be considered to have failed. The revealed card for the digivolution will be returned to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon without digivolution cards digivolves, what happens if the digivolution cost is added by this effect, and as a result the digivolution cost cannot be paid?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose a different Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to select a different Digimon for this card's [When Digivolving] effect from the Digimon that had its digivolution cards trashed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect lets you choose which digivolution cards to trash.\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated on an opponent's Digimon that has 4 digivolution cards. Is it possible to choose which digivolution cards I trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [All Turns] effect activate when it is suspended by \uff1cEvade\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses the Digimon that attacks.\n",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Digimon to attack with this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After your Digimon is suspended, the attack is declared right afterwards.\n",
      "question": "Q: When is the attack declared for this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, in that case the attack will not happen. The effect ends without declaring an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent choose a Digimon with \"cannot attack\" for this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, in that case you would suspend a Digimon and the effect will end without an attack being declared.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect activate even if there are no Digimon in the opponent's battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Because both the [When Attacking] and \"when suspended\" effects are triggered by this same effect. The turn player's effects (i.e. your opponent's [When Attacking] effects) will be activated first, and then the non-turn player's (i.e. your \"when suspended\" effects) next.\n",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect, I suspend a [EX3-044 Breakdramon] or [EX3-074 Examon]. What is the resolution of the [When Attacking] and \"when suspended\" effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. After the first Digimon attacks and after activating the [When Attacking] effects. The second [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect of this card will be activated, and will fail to force an opponent's Digimon to attack because the first attack is still on-going.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this card, can I activate the [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect to force 2 Digimon to attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of Examon will only activate after the attack is declared. So it can be targeted for an attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: With my opponent's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect of this card, they suspend their [EX3-074 Examon]. Is it possible for my Digimon to attack the Examon even though it unsuspends when it becomes suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can target the suspended Digimon with this card's effect, and if so, the attack will not happen.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has an unsuspended Digimon and another Digimon that is still suspended. Can my opponent choose to target the suspended Digimon for this card's effect? If so, what happens?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will not draw. This card's [On Deletion] effect only places the Option card it into the Battle Area. It does not use the Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the Battle Area with this card's [On Deletion] effect, will the Option card's \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. After that, place this card in the Battle Area.\" effect let me draw 1 card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 Digimon card [Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits and 1 card [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card with [Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits and 1 card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:AngelCategory:Mini AngelCategory:Fallen AngelCategory:ArchangelCategory:CherubCategory:ThroneCategory:AuthorityCategory:SeraphCategory:Virtue\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5929\u4f7f\u578b), does it include traits other than [Angel] (\u5929\u4f7f\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You will look at your security without revealing it to your opponent. After that, choose any card to reveal to the opponent and add to your hand. Then, if the card added to your hand is a yellow card, \uff1cRecovery +1 (Deck)\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's [On Play] effect work?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 Digimon card [Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits and 1 card [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card 1 Digimon card [Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits and 1 card [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:AngelCategory:Mini AngelCategory:Fallen AngelCategory:ArchangelCategory:CherubCategory:ThroneCategory:AuthorityCategory:SeraphCategory:Virtue\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Angel]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5929\u4f7f\u578b), does it include traits other than [Angel] (\u5929\u4f7f\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 Digimon card [dramon]\u00a0in its name and 1 card [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card 1 Digimon card [dramon]\u00a0in its name and 1 card [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will not draw. This card's [When Digivolving] effect only places the Option card it into the Battle Area. It does not use the Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the Battle Area with this card's [When Digivolving] effect, will the Option card's \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. After that, place this card in the Battle Area.\" effect let me draw 1 card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will not draw. This card's [When Digivolving] effect only places the Option card it into the Battle Area. It does not use the Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the Battle Area with this card's [When Digivolving] effect, will the Option card's \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. After that, place this card in the Battle Area.\" effect let me draw 1 card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will not draw. This card's [On Deletion] effect only places the Option card it into the Battle Area. It does not use the Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the Battle Area with this card's [On Deletion] effect, will the Option card's \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. After that, place this card in the Battle Area.\" effect let me draw 1 card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 blue/green Digimon card [dramon]\u00a0in its name and 1 [Examon], am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 blue/green Digimon card [dramon]\u00a0in its name and 1 [Examon], am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [Your Turn] effect activate when it is suspended by \uff1cEvade\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the [Your Turn] effect activate when it is suspended by \uff1cEvade\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: If both a card with [Vegetation]/[Plant]/[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits are revealed with this effect, must I add both of them to hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Fairy\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Fairy]\u00a0in one of its traits\" (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b), does it include traits other than [Fairy] (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you only reveal one or the other, you get to add the one card to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck do not include both 1 Digimon card [Rock Dragon]/[Earth Dragon]/[Bird Dragon]/[Machine Dragon]/[Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait and 1 [Hina Kurihara], am I not allowed to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you should add to your hand as much as possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal both 1 Digimon card [Rock Dragon]/[Earth Dragon]/[Bird Dragon]/[Machine Dragon]/[Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait and 1 [Hina Kurihara], am I allowed to add 1 card to hand and put the other on the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, all of them gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If multiple Digimon with the [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait are played at the same time. Does all of them gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only the Digimon with [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait will gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait and a Digimon without [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait are played by the same effect. Do both Digimon gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you choose not to play the valid Digimon card. The Digimon card will still get trashed.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I choose not to play a Digimon with the [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait using this card's [When Digivolving] effect. Does it get trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, both Digimon must be suspended otherwise they will not be able to DNA Digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my turn after my opponent's [On Play] effect of this card was activated, can an unsuspended Digimon and a suspended Digimon be used for a DNA Digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e is an effect that occurs \"when you would digivolve\", so if the Digimon you are digivolving from is unsuspended it cannot digivolve and the \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e effect cannot be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my turn after my opponent's [On Play] effect of this card was activated, can \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e be used to suspend an unsuspended Digimon and digivolve from that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. The effect of Agunimon will treat the Tamer as a \"level 3 red Digimon\", so it is considered an unsuspended Digimon and cannot digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my turn after my opponent's [On Play] effect of this card was activated, is it possible to digivolve from an unsuspended Tamer into [BT4-011 Agunimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must finish the digivolution. The effect of \"when you would digivolve into this card\" is to reveal this card from your hand and declare evolution, then return cards with the [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait to the top of the deck and reduce the evolution cost. The digivolution cannot be cancelled by a player once declared.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's \"when you would digivolve into this card\" effect, can I choose not to digivolve after returning cards with the [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait from my trash to the top of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can only trash a purple or red card with the [Free]\u00a0trait or a card with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When activating this card's [On Play] effect, after adding 1 purple or red card with the [Free]\u00a0trait or 1 card with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name to my hand, can I trash either of the remaining 2 cards? Or can I only trash a purple or red card with the [Free]\u00a0trait or a card with [Imperialdramon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Your Turn] effect will not be active.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has [BT12-001 Gigimon] in its digivolution cards when it gets deleted. Can I delete a Digimon with 4000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: If digivolving with this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect moves the memory to my opponent's side. Is it possible to use this card's inherited effect to perform a DNA Digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not have to be Red. Only the Digimon card you digivolve into has to be red.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve a Digimon into a Level 4 Red Digimon card with the [Free]\u00a0trait. Does that other Digimon have to be Red?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, once the attack is declared, the attack will continue even if it loses is digivolution cards during the attack.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this Digimon has declared an attack, its digivolution cards are all trashed by an effect. Will the attack be stopped?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you will not draw. This card's [On Deletion] effect only places the Option card it into the Battle Area. It does not use the Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: When I place [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the Battle Area with this card's [On Deletion] effect, will the Option card's \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. After that, place this card in the Battle Area.\" effect let me draw 1 card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, but it is not possible to activate both effects at the same time, so they will be activated one by one. Finish resolving the first [On Play] effect activated by this card before suspending the next one to activate it again.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this card in my battle area. After digivolving into a Digimon with the [Rock Dragon]/[Earth Dragon]/[Bird Dragon]/[Machine Dragon]/[Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait. Can I suspend both Tamers and activate the [On Play] effect of that Digimon twice?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [On Deletion] effect was triggered most recently, so it activates first before the next [Your Turn] effect of Hina Kurihara.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have two of this card, and after using this card's [Your Turn] effect to activate the effect of [EX3-012 Volcanicdramon]. Will the [On Deletion] effect happen after the [Your Turn] effect of the second Hina?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is considered to be activating a Digimon's card effect.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's effect to activate an [On Play] effect, does that count as activating a Tamer's card effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: As long as you have a level 6 Digimon with the [Machine]\u00a0trait in the battle area, you can use this Option card even if you don't have both a Red and Black Digimon and/or Tamer.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"While you have a level 6 Digimon with the [Machine]\u00a0trait in play, you may use this card without meeting its color requirements.\" effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is still the Digimon that was played by this effect. So it is deleted at the end of your opponent's turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I the Digimon played with this effect is digivolved into a new Digimon, or de-digivolved into a Digimon by a combination of effects. Is it still deleted by \"and at the end of your opponent's turn, delete that Digimon.\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot DNA Digivolve into a Level 7 Digimon using the Digimon played with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to DNA Digivolve the Digimon into a Level 7 Digimon that was played with this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if only your opponent has a Digimon in the Battle Area, suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon. If only you have a Digimon in the Battle Area, unsuspend 1 of your Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Security] effect fail to activate if either only me or my opponent has a Digimon in the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can only activate that effect when DNA Digivolving.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the effect of \"you may play 1 green or blue Digimon card with the [dramon]\u00a0trait and 12000 DP or less from your hand without paying the cost.\" when DNA Digivolving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Since [On Deletion] effect activates after moving to the trash the Digimon with this card's inherited effect is not in the Battle Area. So the effect does not meet its conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect include the Digimon that was deleted in the \"If you have a Digimon in play\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not work. Even if an effect causes the attack, it is suspended by an attack and so it is not considered to be \"suspended by a card effect\".\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when attacking with \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon.\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, deletion by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e is not considered deleted by battle.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon was deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that if the total number of your trash and your opponent's trash is 20 or more. For example, if your trash is 12 and your opponent's trash is 8. The total is 20 so the conditions are met.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"if both players have a total of 20 or more in their trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if the conditions are met when the effect activates, the effect will continue for the duration of the turn\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the total number of cards in both player's trash becoems 19 or less after being played. Does it lose \uff1cRush\uff1e gained by its [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must trash the top 2 cards of each player's deck as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect always trash the top two cards of each player's deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is a \"you may return to hand\" effect. So it's possible not to return it to your hand. However, the top two cards of each player's deck is still trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if I have [Guilmon] or a card with [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name, can I choose not to return that card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is a \"you may return to hand\" effect. So it's possible not to return it to your hand.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [On Deletion] inherited effect, if I have [Guilmon] or a card with [Growlmon]/[Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name, can I choose not to return that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates while the opponent has no Digimon, does it still activate the effect of giving -4000 DP to the opponent's Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means that the number of your trash and the number of your opponent's trash are totaled, and every 10 of that total number. For example, if you have 15 cards in your trash, and 9 cards in your opponent's trash. You'll have a total of 24 cards. So 4000 DP will be added to the maximum DP of the deletion.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For \"every 10 cards in each player's trash\" does it mean \"every 10 cards in your trash\" and \"every 10 cards in the opponent's trash\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means, if this card is in the trash at that specific timing the effect can be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [End of Your Turn] effect, what does [Trash] mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is a \"you may play this card\". So it's possible to not play this card with the effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [End of Your Turn] effect delete a Digimon with [Gallantmon]\u00a0in its name but not be played afterwards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means that the number of your trash and the number of your opponent's trash are totaled, and every 10 of that total number. For example, if you have 15 cards in your trash, and 9 cards in your opponent's trash. You'll have a total of 24 cards. So 4000 DP will be added to the maximum DP of the deletion.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For the [On Play] effect's \"every 10 cards in each player's trash\" does it mean \"every 10 cards in your trash\" and \"every 10 cards in the opponent's trash\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In that case, it will remain in the trash.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is played by its [Security] effect, and deleted during that turn. In that case, at the end of that turn, can I return this card from the trash to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to stop a suspended Digimon from unsuspending during the opponent's unsuspend phase.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [On Play][When Attacking] effect(s) fail to delete an opponent's Digimon. Can prevent a suspended Digimon from unsuspending during the opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since, [Security] effects cannot activate. The battle will be held as usual. After the battle ends, this card is placed in the trash.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if the opponent's Digimon attacks and this card is revealed while \"The opponent's [Security] effect does not activate\" is active?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate during my turn when an opponent's Digimon with [Blue Flare]/[Twilight]\u00a0trait is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they will not.If multiple Digimon that feature either the [Blue Flare]/[Twilight]\u00a0trait are played with different effects. The effect of this card will be triggered separately for each effect. According to the rules, the effect that triggered later will take precendence. In the case of this question the effect triggered by [Twilight]\u00a0trait will activate first. So a card with the DigiXros requirement is returned to your hand. Because of the [Once Per Turn], you cannot \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card with [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait is played during my turn, and the effect was triggered. Before that effect activates, if a card with [Twilight]\u00a0trait is played. Can both effects to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"return 1 card with DigiXros requirements from your trash to the hand\" both activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you play this card it will trigger its own effect.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: This card has [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait, so does this card \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e with its own effect when it is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you should do both.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with both [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait and [Twilight]\u00a0trait is played, can I do both \"gain 1 memory\" and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still add that card to your hand if you only have one or the other.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If there is only either 1 [Kiriha Aonuma] or 1 black or blue card with the DigiXros requirement among the cards revealed. Can I add only that one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a target for this effect, add it to your hand as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: FOr this card's [On Play] effect. If I have both 1 [Kiriha Aonuma] and 1 black or blue card with the DigiXros requirement among the cards revealed by the effect. Can I choose to add only 1 of them to my hand and trash the other one?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon targeted at the time of this effect will continue having \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory.\" until the end of the opponent's turn.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's [On Play] effect is activated, and the opponent's Digimon with the lowest level gains the \"[When Attacking]\" effect, that Digimon is digivolved into a higher level Digimon and another Digimon becomes the lowest level Digimion. What happens to the [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon will still be unable to attack until the end of the opponent's turn.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's inherited [When Attacking] effect. I choose 1 of my opponent's Digimon with 3 or less digivolution cards as the target of \"cannot attack until the end of the opponent's turn\" effect. What happens when the opponent's Digimon gains another digivolution card to have 4 or more digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack. This effect is \"all of your opponent's Digimon that are level 4 or lower\", so Digimon that become level 5 or higher will no longer be affected. But, Digimon that has enter the battle area afterwards as Level 4 or lower will be affected.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, all level 4 or lower Digimon was chosen to be unable to attack digivolves into a level 5 Digimon. Can it attack now?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates the opponent has 7 cards in their hand. After returning a Level 4 Digimon to the hand my opponent has 8 cards in their hand, so will the effect of \"if your opponent has 8 or more cards in their hand\" activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The card revealed from your hand will be placed on the top of your security stack face down.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is placed in security with this card's effect, is it the opponent's Digimon or the card revealed from my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can be activated, but the security will not be increased. So the revealed cannot be laced in security and will be trashed by the rules.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the effect of [BT9-103 Kongou] that prevents security from increasing is in effect. Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. [EX2-045 Calumon] does not have a level. So it is not considered as a card with the same level as [EX2-045 Calumon] and cannot be revealed by this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent plays [EX2-045 Calumon], can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to reveal another [EX2-045 Calumon] from my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's inherited effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's inherited effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Even if the targeted Digimon's DP becomes 7000 DP or more after this card's effect activated. The effect will not be lost and continue preventing it from attacking or blocking until the specified timing.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Due to the this card's [When Digivolving] effect, the opponent's 6000 DP or less Digimon cannot attack or block. What happens if that Digimon becomes a Digimon with 7000 DP or more, can it attack or block now?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: While I have a blue or yellow Tamer, or a card with [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in its the trash and use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to give -2000 DP to a Digimon with 8000 DP to 6000 DP. Can it then prevent that Digimon from attacking or blocking?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's inherited effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers, will this card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As this card is treated as including [Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name and is level 6. It can be digivolved into using [EX4-072 Digital Translator].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to digivolve [Sakuyamon] into this card with the effect of [EX4-072 Digital Translator]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] has the effect of \"when this card would be used\", and the use cost of the card has not changed, so the option card still has a memory of 5. Assuming that you have done so, the inherited effect of this card can be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] when my security is one, will this card's inherited effect be exhibited?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of \"using an option card without paying the cost\" still applies because the use cost has not changed.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"use an option card without paying cost\" effect trigger the inherited effect of this card when an option card with a use cost of 2 or more is used?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. These option cards \"change the cost to pay\" when they are used, but the card's cost itself has not changed, so they cannot be used with this card's effect. However, [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has an effect that changes the cost of the card when it is in your hand, so if you have four yellow Tamers in the Battle Area, its cost is 5 and it can be used with this Digimon's [On Play] effect.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: When I use a 5-cost Option Card for this Digimon's [On Play] effect, can I use an option card that changes its cost depending on a condition, such as [BT10-098 Plasma Deckerdra Launcher]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still add that card to your hand if you only have one or the other.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If there is only either 1 [Henry Wong]\u00a0in its name or 1 2-color green card among the cards revealed. Can I add only that one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a target for this effect, add it to your hand as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If I have both 1 [Henry Wong]\u00a0in its name and 1 2-color green card among the cards revealed by the effect. Can I choose to add only 1 of them to my hand and put the other one on the bottom of deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still add that card to your hand if you only have one or the other.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If there is only either 1 [Shu-Chong Wong]\u00a0in its name or 1 2-color green card among the cards revealed. Can I add only that one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a target for this effect, add it to your hand as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: FOr this card's [On Play] effect. If I have both 1 [Shu-Chong Wong]\u00a0in its name and 1 2-color green card among the cards revealed by the effect. Can I choose to add only 1 of them to my hand and put the other one on the bottom of deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as many times as you trigger \uff1cAlliance\uff1e (When this Digimon attacks, by suspending 1 of your other Digimon, add the suspended Digimon's DP to this Digimon and it gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e for the attack)\n",
      "question": "Q: Am i able to activate the inherited effect multiple times per turn?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card has received an Errata, please make sure to check the official page for rule changes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"[End of Attack] \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 1 card from the top of one of your opponent's Digimon. If it has no digivolution cards, or becomes a level 3 Digimon, you can't trash any more cards)\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated. You gain \uff1cPiercing\uff1e after having already deleted an opponent's Digimon in battle. So you cannot perform security checks.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When your Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card attacks the opponent's Digimon and deletes only the opponent's Digimon which causes another Digimon is suspended by another effect afterwards. Can \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card's inherited effect be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it has to be a Level 4 Digimon that is a 2-color green Digimon or a Digimon with [Gargomon]\u00a0in its name.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: This card's special digivolution requirements is \"Lv.4 w/[Gargomon] in its name or 2-color green card\". Does digivolve from a 2-color green card require it to be Level 4?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, suspending for \uff1cBlocker\uff1e doesn't count as an effect.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e suspends to block, does this card's inherited effect trigger to give my Digimon \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it has to be a Level 5 Digimon that is a 2-color green Digimon or a Digimon with [Rapidmon]\u00a0in its name.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's special digivolution requirements is \"Lv.5 w/[Rapidmon] in its name or 2-color green card\". Does digivolve from a 2-color green card require it to be Level 5?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still add that card to your hand if you only have one or the other.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If there is only either 1 [Greymon]\u00a0in its name or 1 [Gabumon]/[Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name among the cards revealed. Can I add only that one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a target for this effect, add it to your hand as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If I have both 1 [Greymon]\u00a0in its name and 1 [Gabumon]/[Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name among the cards revealed by the effect. Can I choose to add only 1 of them to my hand and put the other one on the bottom of deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still add that card to your hand if you only have one or the other.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If there is only either 1 [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name or 1 [Agumon]/[Greymon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name among the cards revealed. Can I add only that one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a target for this effect, add it to your hand as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If I have both 1 [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name and 1 [Agumon]/[Greymon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name among the cards revealed by the effect. Can I choose to add only 1 of them to my hand and put the other one on the bottom of deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is treated as [Nene Amano] by its effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect play [EX4-062 Kiriha Aonuma & Nene Amano] without paying its cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is treated as [Nene Amano] by its effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect play a [Nene Amano] while I have [EX4-062 Kiriha Aonuma & Nene Amano] in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e is lost before the second check, the second check is not performed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: The opponent attacks with a Digimon that has \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e, and the security is reduced by 1. What happens if this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect that \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e on nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 1 card from the top of one of your opponent's Digimon. If it has no digivolution cards, or becomes a level 3 Digimon, you can't trash any more cards) on the attacking Digimon causes it to lose that \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. [EX2-045 Calumon] does not have a level. So it is not considered as a card with the same level as [EX2-045 Calumon] and cannot be trashed by this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent\u2019s [EX2-045 Calumon] is deleted, can I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect to trash a [EX2-045 Calumon] from my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still add that card to your hand if you only have one or the other.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If there is only either 1 [Ravemon]\u00a0in its name, or [Bird]\u00a0in one of its traits or 1 [Keenan Crier] among the cards revealed. Can I add only that one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you have a target for this effect, add it to your hand as much as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect. If I have both 1 [Ravemon]\u00a0in its name, or [Bird]\u00a0in one of its traits and 1 [Keenan Crier] among the cards revealed by the effect. Can I choose to add only 1 of them to my hand and put the other one on the bottom of deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent will choose the card to be trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the card to be trashed from the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, deletion by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e is not considered deleted by battle.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon was deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent will choose the card to be trashed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the card to be trashed from the hand for this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Level 5 or lower Digimon gains the [On Deletion] effect. Afterwards, it digivolves into a Level 6 Digimon and gets deleted. Can the level 6 Digimon be played without paying its memory cost by the [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon will leave the battle area when it is placed as a digivolution card for another Digimon. So this card's [All Turns] effect will trigger and activate. So, it will be placed in your security face down instead of becoming a digivolution card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens with this card's [All Turns] effect if this card would be placed as a digivolution card underneath another Digimon? For example, with the effect of [BT11-109 Astral Snatcher]."
    }
  ],
  "EX4-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you out of all Digimon between you and your opponent there are 2 or more Digimon, it will activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate if there are 2 or more Digimon in the Battle Area, including my opponent's Digimon as well as my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place requirements from under my other tamers as well for this card's [All Turns] effect? Not just this tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add 1 card from trash and/or tamers for each of this card suspended.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple copies of this card, can I suspend multiple of them to place more than 1 card from my trash or tamers as a digivolution card for [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can choose to place 0, 1, or both.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: When I place cards for a DigiXros with this card's [All Turns] effect, if there's 1 valid card under my Tamers and 1 valid card in my trash, can I choose to place just 1 of those cards, or am I required to place both?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you will get both effects if it was deleted by an effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [All Turns] effect, can I perform both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"gain 1 memory\", if the Digimon was deleted by an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [Main] effect activates the opponent has 7 cards in their hand. After returning a Level 4 or lower Digimon to the hand my opponent has 8 cards in their hand, so will the effect of \"if your opponent has 8 or more cards in their hand\" activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect will activate in addition to the number of colours you have, so you can select different targets for each effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Main] effect, can different Digimon receive -6000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they will be treated as being performed at the same timing.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [Main] effect activates 2 or more times, are they are treated as activating at different times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Main] effect activate 3 times when I have 1 Digimon with 2 colours?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, duplicate colours are counted as 1 colour. So in the case of this scenario, there are 3 colours. It will be activated 4 times.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a red/blue Digimon, and a red/black Digimon. Does this card's effect activate 5 times with 4 colours?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's an effect that activates multiple times, so you can select different targets for each activation.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [Main] effect activates more than once, can I activate it once for each of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who activated this effect decides.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's effect, which players chooses the Digimon with the highest play cost?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to use this card when there are no level 3 Digimon on the opponent's Battle Area to activate only the effect of placing this card in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you the owner of the card gains 2 memory. The card to be discarded is chosen by the opponent.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent doesn't discard an Option card from their hand due to this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect, will my opponent gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is looking for a level 6 Digimon card whose name contains the selected Digimon's name.For example, if you select [WarGreymon], you can digivolve into [WarGreymon (X Antibody)]/[BlackWarGreymon (X Antibody)]/[BlackWarGreymon] and digivolve into them ignoring their digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"level 6 Digimon card with the same name as the selected Digimon but different card name\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, its effect treats it as a Digimon with [Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I select [Sakuyamon] as the target. Does the effect of [EX4-030 Kuzuhamon] allow it to be digivolved into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [EX4-030 Kuzuhamon] has [Sakuyamon]\u00a0in its name, but the [Sakuyamon] does not have \"[Kuzuhamon]\u00a0in its name\".\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If [EX4-030 Kuzuhamon] is selected as the target of this card, can it digivolve into any level 6 [Sakuyamon] with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if card A has an effect that says \"This card/Digimon is also treated as if it's [B]\", then A and B will not satisfy the \"card names are different\" condition.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If a [ChaosGallantmon] is selected as the target of this card, can it digivolve into a [Megidramon] with an effect that says \"This card/Digimon is also treated as if it's [ChaosGallantmon]\", or vice-versa (Megidramon into ChaosGallantomon)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if two cards already have the same name, a \"This card/Digimon is also treated as if it's [X]\" effect cannot satisfy the \"card names are different\" condition.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If a [Megidramon] is selected as the target of this card, can it digivolve into a [Megidramon] with an effect that says \"This card/Digimon is also treated as if it's [ChaosGallantmon]\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only the card with lowest play cost among all of your opponent's Digimon and Tamers overall will be deleted. If multiple Digimon/Tamers share the lowest play cost then this card's controller chooses 1 from among them.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect mean I choose 1 of my opponent's lowest play cost Digimon or 1 of my opponent's lowest play cost Tamers, and delete the chosen Card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, for each level 6 or higher digivolution card you trash with this effect, delete your opponent's Digimon/Tamers in ascending order of play cost.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I trash 2 Level 6 or higher digivolution cards with this card's [When Attacking] effect. If my opponent controls a 3 play cost Digimon and a 4 play cost Digimon do I delete both of them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes exactly.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I trash 3 level 6 or higher digivolution cards with this card' [When Attacking] effect, does that mean I both delete 3 of my opponent's Digimon/Tamers and trash 2 cards from my opponent's security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if it is possible you must select at least 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less with this effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [When Digivolving] effect can I choose a play cost total of 0 and not delete any of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Its [On Play] effect will trigger, but it will be deleted before it can be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has used this card's [When Digivolving][On Deletion] effect last turn, what happens when I play a Digimon with 5000 DP or less, can it activate its [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, please do as much of it as possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card's [End of Attack] effect mandatory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [End of Attack] effect even when the opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "P-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. \"Trash all of the digivolution cards of those Digimon\" is an explanation of what happens to the digivolution cards of the Digimon when it returns to their hand. It doesn't count as trashing digivolution for the purposes of this card's effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: You activate an effect that reads \"Return 1 of your opponent's Digimon to their hand. Trash all of the digivolution cards of that Digimon\" to return an opponent's Digimon to their hand. When your opponent's digivolution cards are trashed as a result, can you activate this card's effect?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. During your turn, if an effect belonging to you or your opponent causes your opponent to trash one of their Digimon's digivolution cards, this card's \"gain 1 memory\" effect activates.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: During your turn, your opponent uses an effect to trash one of their Digimon's digivolution cards. Does this card's \"gain 1 memory\" effect activate?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot activate the effect of [P-004 Gomamon].\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I use \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e while I have this Digimon as a digivolution card. Can I use the inherited effect of [P-004 Gomamon]?\n"
    }
  ],
  "P-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect only applies if a card with the exact name [Agumon] is one of its digivolution cards. Despite [Agumon Expert]/[ToyAgumon], and other Digimon cards having [Agumon] in their names, the effect doesn't apply if it isn't an exact match.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect apply if it has [Agumon Expert]/[ToyAgumon] as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect is voluntary.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I always have to use this card's effect when I attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to trash 6 cards from the top of my deck and give this card +4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card and activate its [When Attacking] effect to get +2000 DP. I then unsuspend this card using a card effect and attack again. Can I use the [When Attacking] effect again to get an additional +2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's inherited effect when I have 2 or less non-Digi-Egg cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Cards in your trash are considered public information, so please let your opponent confirm which cards you're returning to your deck before you do so.\n",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's inherited effect to return cards from my trash to the bottom of my deck, is my opponent allowed to check what cards I am returning to my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to return 3 non-Digi-Egg cards to the bottom of my deck but not activate \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can activate it at any time during your Main Phase, much like you would an Option card.\n",
      "question": "Q: At what timing does this card's [Main] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect if I have a Digimon [Veedramon]\u00a0in its name in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have two copies of this Tamer as well as one [Veedramon] in play in my battle area, can I active the effects of both Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have one [Veedramon] in play in my battle area, can I use this card's effect to make a Digimon that doesn't have [Veedramon] in its name get +1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "P-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does a [Diaboromon] Token count as 1 [Diaboromon] for this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card itself count as 1 [Diaboromon] for its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I always have to activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a [Mimi Tachikawa] in play. Is the effect of this card that I can play a [Palmon] from my hand without paying its cost?"
    }
  ],
  "P-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, uou can use it, but unless you return both a [ExVeemon] and [Stingmon] from your hand to the bottom of the deck, you cannot play [Paildramon] without paying its cost. Also, it is not possible to return only one of [ExVeemon] and [Stingmon] to the bottom of the deck.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I only have either \"XV-mon\" or \"Stingmon\" in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "P-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can use it, but you cannot put anything in your security.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I don't have [Patamon] in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it must be a card named [Tai Kamiya].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect with [P-012 Tai Kamiya (V-Tamer)] in play?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it must be a card named [Agumon].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return a card with [Agumon]\u00a0in its name such as [ToyAgumon], [Agumon Expert]/[BushiAgumon]?\n"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it must be from the battle area.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place an [Agumon] from my hand on the bottom of my deck for this card's effect?\n"
    }
  ],
  "P-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect after I digivolved this card on a suspended Digimon and the memory becomes 1 or more on the opponent's side?"
    }
  ],
  "P-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect trigger [BT3-096 Mimi Tachikawa]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: All of the effects trigger at the same time, the player activates the effects in the order they choose.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have a [BT3-091 Lilithmon] and [BT3-092 MaloMyotismon] and then I use this card's effect to \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e [BT4-077 Ghostmon], what is the order of the effects when I use [BT2-109 Heat Viper] with this card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you have exactly 3 security cards it satisfies both the conditions of \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and +1 Memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in Security do I get to use both effects to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and gain +1 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "P-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect to delete the Digimon at the end of the turn persists.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve into [AncientGreymon]. The Digimon digivolves or \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e into another Digimon. Does it still get deleted at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the \"delete this Digimon\" and \"return the Digimon to the bottom of its owner's deck\" trigger at the same time. The player chooses which effect goes first. The effect that happens after is not applied.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve into [AncientGreymon] and then using [BT5-109 Mega Digimon Fusion!] to digivolve into a level 7 Digimon. Since the deletion effect persists, what happens first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect of [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] will persist on the evolved Digimon. So the [AncientGreymon] is played.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] on this Digimon, it then digivolves into [AncientGreymon]. Which Digimon will be played by this effect [P-029 Agunimon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After the attack ends, the End of Turn Procedures will start and this Digimon will get deleted bringing the memory back 1 on your side. After the opponent resolves [ST5-04 ToyAgumon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect you continue your turn. You would end your turn twice so [End of Your Turn], [End of Opponent's Turn], and [End of All Turns] would trigger twice this turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using [BT6-104 Parabolic Junk] on this Digimon. I then uses its [When Attacking] to digivolve into [AncientGreymon] putting the memory at 1 on the opponent's side. My opponent has a Digimon with [ST5-04 ToyAgumon] in its digivolution cards. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reduce the digivolution cost of 2 with another effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I am activating this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve, can I reduce its digivolution cost of that effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect to delete the Digimon at the end of the turn persists.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGarurumon]. The Digimon digivolves or \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e into another Digimon. Does it still get deleted at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the \"delete this Digimon\" and \"return the Digimon to the bottom of its owner's deck\" trigger at the same time. The player chooses which effect goes first. The effect that happens after is not applied.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using this card's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGarurumon] and then using [BT5-109 Mega Digimon Fusion!] to digivolve into a level 7 Digimon. Since the deletion effect persists, what happens first?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect of [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] will persist on the evolved Digimon. So the [AncientGarurumon] is played.\n",
      "question": "Q: After using [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] on a Digimon, that Digimon then digivolves into [P-030 Lobomon] and then [AncientGarurumon]. Which Digimon will be played by this effect [P-030 Lobomon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Even though End of Turn Procedures have started, when your memory moves back to 0, you no longer continue ending your turn, [End of Your Turn], [End of Opponent's Turn], and [End of All Turns] would happen twice in this instance as you would end your turn twice.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve [BT1-030 Gomamon] into [P-030 Lobomon]. The memory passes over to 1 when I use the latter's effect to digivolve into [BT4-114 AncientGarurumon]. My opponent has a Digimon with [ST5-04 ToyAgumon] in its digivolution cards. As my turn is ending, AncientGarurumon is deleted and [BT1-030 Gomamon]'s effect gives me +1 memory moving my memory back to 0. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reduce the digivolution cost of 1 with another effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I am using this card's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve, can I reduce its digivolution cost of that effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon did not have \uff1cBlocker\uff1e at the [Reaction] timing. So it cannot use \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have a purple Digimon and this card in play. If my opponent uses a [When Attacking] effect to delete the purple Digimon can this Digimon still use \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "P-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when your opponent's Digimon is deleted by battle your Digimon will have \uff1cPiercing\uff1e so it can be activated. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is in play, my Black Digimon with 12000 DP attacks and uses its [When Attacking] effect to gain +1000 DP. Can that Digimon activate \uff1cPiercing\uff1e in that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when you check security it will have \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is a digivolution card of my Black Digimon with 12000 DP that attacks and uses its [When Attacking] effect to gain +1000 DP. Can that Digimon activate \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e for that attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon loses the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e and if no other effects are increasing its security attack no further checks will be performed and the attack will end.\n",
      "question": "Q: While my Black Digimon with 13000 DP is checking security with this card in its digivolution cards it is hit by a [Security] effect that \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e it to a Digimon with 12000 DP or less. What happens to the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when you activate this effect you will have 7 or more Digimon cards with [Devimon]\u00a0in their name in the trash, the [On Deletion] inherited effect be able to play a [DanDevimon] from your trash without paying its memory cost.\n",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted when I have 6 Digimon cards with [Devimon]\u00a0in its name. Can I play a [DanDevimon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "P-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card in the battle area does not meet the colour requirement for you to play Red Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can I play Red Options even though I do not have a Red Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the colour requirement for Options is only applied when using Option cards from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if there is no Red Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card in the battle area does not meet the colour requirement for you to play Blue Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can I play Blue Options even though I do not have a Blue Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the colour requirement for Options is only applied when using Option cards from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if there is no Blue Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card in the battle area does not meet the colour requirement for you to play Yellow Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can I play Yellow Options even though I do not have a Yellow Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the colour requirement for Options is only applied when using Option cards from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if there is no Yellow Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card in the battle area does not meet the colour requirement for you to play Green Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can I play Green Options even though I do not have a Green Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the colour requirement for Options is only applied when using Option cards from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if there is no Green Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card in the battle area does not meet the colour requirement for you to play Black Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can I play Black Options even though I do not have a Black Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the colour requirement for Options is only applied when using Option cards from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if there is no Black Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card in the battle area does not meet the colour requirement for you to play Purple Options.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can I play Purple Options even though I do not have a Purple Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the colour requirement for Options is only applied when using Option cards from your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if there is no Purple Digimon or Tamer in my battle area or breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the deck and the Digi-Egg deck are considered separate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a card is returned to my Digi-Egg Deck, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "P-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "P-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: [DigiXros] itself is not an effect, so, if the Digimon is played as an action in the main phase, this card's inherited effect will not activate even if it is played as a [DigiXros]. This card's inherited effect activates if a Digimon is played by an effect, regardless of whether the Digimon played by the effect [DigiXros]es.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect even if the Digimon appears as a [DigiXros]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not be deleted.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon that receives the effect of this card's [On Play] or Template:WhenDigivolving effect loses battle with a Security Digimon, will that Digimon be deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "P-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. That is possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I specify this Digimon as the Digimon to be destroyed by this card's [On Play] and Template:WhenDigivolving effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so it can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon digivolves with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect into a card in my hand, can I digivolve it regardless of the digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Special digivolution is possible, but Burst Digivolution and DNA Digivolution are not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to Special Digivolve, Burst Digivolve, or DNA Digivolve into cards in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. Since this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves from one of your Digimon, you cannot digivolve from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve from a Tamer to a Digimon card that has the effect of \"Treat your Tamer as a Digimon and digivolve\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and then not digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a [ST7-03 Guilmon] into a [Gallantmon], reducing its cost to 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "P-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so it can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon digivolves with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect into a card in my hand, can I digivolve it regardless of the digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Special digivolution is possible, but Burst Digivolution and DNA Digivolution are not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to Special Digivolve, Burst Digivolve, or DNA Digivolve into cards in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. Since this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves from one of your Digimon, you cannot digivolve from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve from a Tamer to a Digimon card that has the effect of \"Treat your Tamer as a Digimon and digivolve\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and then not digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a [ST8-04 Veemon] into an [UlforceVeedramon], reducing its cost to 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "P-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so it can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon digivolves with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect into a card in my hand, can I digivolve it regardless of the digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Special digivolution is possible, but Burst Digivolution and DNA Digivolution are not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to Special Digivolve, Burst Digivolve, or DNA Digivolve into cards in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. Since this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves from one of your Digimon, you cannot digivolve from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve from a Tamer to a Digimon card that has the effect of \"Treat your Tamer as a Digimon and digivolve\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and then not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so it can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon digivolves with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect into a card in my hand, can I digivolve it regardless of the digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Special digivolution is possible, but Burst Digivolution and DNA Digivolution are not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to Special Digivolve, Burst Digivolve, or DNA Digivolve into cards in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. Since this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves from one of your Digimon, you cannot digivolve from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve from a Tamer to a Digimon card that has the effect of \"Treat your Tamer as a Digimon and digivolve\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and then not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so it can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon digivolves with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect into a card in my hand, can I digivolve it regardless of the digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Special digivolution is possible, but Burst Digivolution and DNA Digivolution are not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to Special Digivolve, Burst Digivolve, or DNA Digivolve into cards in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. Since this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves from one of your Digimon, you cannot digivolve from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve from a Tamer to a Digimon card that has the effect of \"Treat your Tamer as a Digimon and digivolve\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and then not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect cannot ignore the digivolution conditions, so it can only digivolve into cards that meet the digivolution conditions.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon digivolves with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect into a card in my hand, can I digivolve it regardless of the digivolution conditions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Special digivolution is possible, but Burst Digivolution and DNA Digivolution are not possible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to Special Digivolve, Burst Digivolve, or DNA Digivolve into cards in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can not. Since this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves from one of your Digimon, you cannot digivolve from a Tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve from a Tamer to a Digimon card that has the effect of \"Treat your Tamer as a Digimon and digivolve\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and then not digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 10 or more cards in my trash, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to evolve my [Impmon] into [BT2-111 Beelzemon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will have +1000 DP during the battle.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards and my opponent's only unsuspended Digimon is a Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. If my opponent's Digimon blocks, does this card give my Digimon +1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is treated as the same card as [P-009 Agumon]. This is a special rule for this card, and not an effect. Also, when creating a deck the maximum number of cards that can be used along with [P-009 Agumon] is 4.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the text on this card referring to \"Card Number: It is also treated as P-009, and you can only put up to 4 cards in the deck together with P-009\", mean?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It refers to the top card only, so you cannot refer to this card's inherited effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect \"has [Gammamon]\u00a0in its text\" work if an inherited effect has [Gammamon] written in it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you reveal both you must add as much as possible.However, if you treat the [Hiro Amanokawa] as a card with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its text, it is possible to return the other card to the bottom of the deck.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if I reveal both a [Hiro Amanokawa] and a card with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its text. Can I only add one of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is treated as the same card as [P-058 Gammamon]. This is a special rule for this card, and not an effect. Also, when creating a deck the maximum number of cards that can be used along with [P-058 Gammamon] is 4.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the text on this card referring to \"Card Number: It is also treated as P-058, and you can only put up to 4 cards in the deck together with P-058\", mean?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is treated as the same card as [P-010 Greymon]. This is a special rule for this card, and not an effect. Also, when creating a deck the maximum number of cards that can be used along with [P-010 Greymon] is 4.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the text on this card referring to \"Card Number: It is also treated as P-010, and you can only put up to 4 cards in the deck together with P-010\", mean?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. However, this card can still digivolve from that Digimon using its special digivolution requirement if it is level 4.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name (e.g. [BetelGammamon]/[KausGammamon]/[WezenGammamon]/[GulusGammamon]) has a card with [Gammamon] as a digivolution card, can it evolve into this card for a digivolution cost of 3, ignoring the digivolution conditions using the effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. This card's \"gain all the effects of cards with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name will be active the moment the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effects will trigger.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After digivolving into this card, can it activate the [When Digivolving] effect gained by its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. This card's \"gain all the effects of cards with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name will be active the moment the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effects will trigger.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: After digivolving into this card, can it activate the [When Digivolving] effect gained by its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, provided memory is on the opponent's side.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-013 BetelGammamon] is in the digivolution cards, does the [All Turns] effect let me attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate an effect that digivolves one of my Digimon, can I digivolve my [Gammamon] with a digivolution card with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name into this card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the inherited effect adds DP as soon as it is placed underneath as a digivolution card, such as [Your Turn] or [All Turns] (without a Trigger Condition), then it will gain the DP before deleting the Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, I placed a Digimon card with an inherited effect that adds DP to this Digimon's digivolution cards. In that case, can \"delete 1 opponent's Digimon whose DP is equal to or less than this Digimon's\" delete the opponent's Digimon whose DP is equal to or less than the added value?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can as it is a \"you may\" effect. You can choose not to activate the effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, I have deleted 1 of my opponent's Digimon. At this point, am I allowed to not activate the [Your Turn] effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you reveal both you must add as much as possible.However, if you treat the [Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] as a card with [Jellymon]\u00a0in its text, it is possible to return the other card to the bottom of the deck.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if I reveal both a [Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] and a card with [Jellymon]\u00a0in its text. Can I only add one of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, If I discard multiple blue cards from my hand, does this card's effect choose different Digimon or Tamers to trash the cards underneath of?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: For Digimon it means \"Digimon without digivolution cards\", and for Tamer it refers to a Tamer where there have been no cards placed underneath the tamer.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"without cards underneath\" mean?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. This card's \"gain all the effects of cards with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name will be active the moment the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effects will trigger.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After digivolving into this card, can it activate the [When Digivolving] effect gained by its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, provided memory is on the opponent's side.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-013 BetelGammamon] is in the digivolution cards, does the [All Turns] effect let me attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect, when I trash multiple blue cards from my hand, can I choose different Digimon and Tamers to trash the cards underneath?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who activates this effect selects and trashes any card of their choice among the cards below.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect, do I trash any card that is underneath the Digimon and/or Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who activated this effect decides the order.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When multiple level 3 Digimon are placed into security by this card's [When Digivolving] effect, which player decides the order of the cards placed in security?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you reveal both you must add as much as possible.However, if you treat the [Ruli Tsukiyono] as a card with [Angoramon]\u00a0in its text, it is possible to return the other card to the bottom of the deck.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if I reveal both a [Ruli Tsukiyono] and a card with [Angoramon]\u00a0in its text. Can I only add one of them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. This card's \"gain all the effects of cards with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name will be active the moment the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effects will trigger.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After digivolving into this card, can it activate the [When Digivolving] effect gained by its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, provided memory is on the opponent's side.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-013 BetelGammamon] is in the digivolution cards, does the [All Turns] effect let me attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot.At the end of your turn, all of your Digimon's [End of Your Turn] effect will be triggered at the same time. After the first effect has finished activating, the 2nd one that was waiting to activate will be unable to attack as an attack is still currently undergoing.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple of this Digimon, can this card's [End of Your Turn] effect allow me to attack multiple times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Both [End of Your Turn] effects are triggered at the same time so you choose which card to activate first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With the [End of Your Turn] effect of this card, can I activate it after the [End of Your Turn] effect of [RB1-034 Ruli Tsukiyono] to unsuspend this card and then attack?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated the effect of this card will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When returning a card revealed from the opponent's security attack for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, which player decides whether the card goes to the top or bottom of security?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated the effect will.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player determines whether the card goes to the top or bottom of the deck for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. This card's \"gain all the effects of cards with [Gammamon]\u00a0in its name will be active the moment the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effects will trigger.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: After digivolving into this card, can it activate the [When Digivolving] effect gained by its [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, provided memory is on the opponent's side.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If [BT8-013 BetelGammamon] is in the digivolution cards, does the [All Turns] effect let me attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect, delete 1 of my own Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Both [End of Your Turn] effects are triggered at the same time so you choose which card to activate first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With the [End of Your Turn] effect of this card, can I activate it before the [End of Your Turn] effect of [RB1-025 Diarbbitmon] to unsuspend this card and then attack?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, since the Digimon does not have a level none of the effects of \"If the Digimon is level 4 or higher\" or \"if the Digimon is level 3\" will work.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon without a level is played, can I suspend this Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since both conditions were met, both effects will be performed.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I suspend this Tamer when my opponent has both a level 3 Digimon and a level 4 or higher Digimon at the same time?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Even if multiple level 3 Digimon were played at the same time, you will only \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. If multiple level 4 or higher Digimon were played, only 1 memory is gained.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has 2 level 3 played at the same time, if I suspend this tamer. Do I \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e twice?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the inherited effect adds DP as soon as it is placed underneath as a digivolution card, such as [Your Turn] or [All Turns] (without a Trigger Condition), then it will gain the DP before deleting the Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [End of Your Turn] effect, I placed a Digimon card with an inherited effect that adds DP to this Digimon's digivolution cards. In that case, can \"delete 1 opponent's Digimon whose DP is equal to or less than this Digimon's\" delete the opponent's Digimon whose DP is equal to or less than the added value?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q:  This card has the inherited effect, \"While this Digimon has 4 or more digivolution cards, it gets +1000 DP.\" Is this card counted as part of that total?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  You can attack with it. But when you do, even if the memory counter moves to 1 or higher on your opponent's side, you don't switch turns until the attack is finished.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this Digimon if I don't have 2 or more memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A:  Yes, it can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon target itself for its own effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only activates if your opponent declares they're blocking the attack with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when I attack my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Only multiples of 2 count for this effect, so even if you have 3 digivolution cards, it only gains \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: How does this Digimon's effect work when it has 3 digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does..\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this Tamer stack if there are multiple copies in play in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: During my next turn after this card's [Security] effect was activated, does it apply to newly played Digimon and Digimon moved from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They are sent to their owner's trash. \n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the digivolution cards of a Digimon deleted by this card's main effect? "
    }
  ],
  "ST1-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They are sent to their owner's trash. \n",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the digivolution cards of a Digimon deleted by this card's main effect? "
    }
  ],
  "ST10-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards is yellow.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards is a yellow Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card, and 1 of your other Digimon, can DNA digivolve into a Digimon in your hand that can <DNA Digivolve>, before the turn is passed to your opponent.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that cannot <DNA Digivolve>.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that cannot <DNA Digivolve>?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve your Digimon that is not the correct colour or level specified by the card that can <DNA Digivolve>.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve my Digimon in play that is not the colour and level specified by the card that can <DNA Digivolve> in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon from DNA Digivolve is treated as a new Digimon so the old DIgimon is no longer in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's [End of Your Turn] effect has triggered, and the Digimon it is underneath is used as part of a DNA Digivolve. Can I still activate this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it says to \"Reveal\", you must reveal the top 3 cards from your deck if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I reveal the top 3 cards of my deck for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \"Add to your hand\", you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if both a yellow and a purple card were revealed, must I add both of them to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card, and 1 of your other Digimon, can DNA digivolve into a Digimon in your hand that can <DNA Digivolve>, before the turn is passed to your opponent.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that cannot <DNA Digivolve>.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that cannot <DNA Digivolve>?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve your Digimon that is not the correct colour or level specified by the card that can <DNA Digivolve>.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve my Digimon in play that is not the colour and level specified by the card that can <DNA Digivolve> in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card is purple.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card is a purple Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The first part \"Place 1 yellow or purple Digimon card from your trash to the top of your security stack face-down\" activates even if you don't DNA Digivolve. The latter part \u201cYou may look at all of your security cards and play a level 5 or below Digimon card from among them without paying its cost\" can only activate if you DNA Digivolved. \u201cThen, shuffle your Security Stack\u201d activates for both digivolutions.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, does it not activate if I don't DNA Digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate if my Security Digimon is played as a Digimon by its [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. As moving a Digimon from Breeding Area is not treated as playing a Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate if I move a Digimon from my Breeding Area to my Battle Area using the effect of [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You choose 1 of those Digimon, and delete a Digimon whose level is equal to or lower than that Digimon's level.\n",
      "question": "Q: When an effect plays multiple Digimon with different levels at the same time, what happens for its [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it says to \u201cReveal\u201d, you must reveal the top 3 cards from your deck if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I reveal the top 3 cards of my deck for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \"Add to your hand\", you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if a Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Fallen Angel]\u00a0trait was revealed, must I add it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is played at the end of battle regardless of the outcome of that battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Security] effect, if it lost the battle against the attacking Digimon, can I still play it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect activate even if it is played by the effects of this card's [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As this Digimon is to be played at the end of the battle with the attacking Digimon, it is played before the next check happens. Its [On Play] effect also activates before the next check.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Security] effect, if at the end of the battle which this card was checked, the attacking Digimon still has remaining checks not done, does this card's [Security] effect activate first or does the next check happens first?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it says \"You may trash 1 card from your hand to\", if you choose not to trash a card, the effects that follow  do not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I reveal the top 3 cards of my deck for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \"Add to your hand\", you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving]\n"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, exactly. If you choose to put it on top of the security stack, it will become the actual target of trashing.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I choose to place my opponent's Digimon at the top of their security stack with this card's effect, does that mean the card that was just placed is then trashed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as the Digimon was not deleted, those effects do not activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the Digimon that was placed in the security stack by this card's effect activate its [On Deletion] effects? Or if there are other Digimon or Tamers with effects that trigger \"When Digimon are deleted\", do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper]'s [All Turns] effect will prevent it from being placed in security and because no cards were placed in security by this card's effect a card is not trashed from security.\n",
      "question": "Q: if I target [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] with this card's effect, what happens?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect can return a yellow or purple Digimon card that was trashed from top of the deck by this card's effect to your hand.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect return to my hand a yellow or purple Digimon card that was trashed from top of the deck by this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is counted.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also count the Digimon on top of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. It will only have +1000 DP from this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Will the Digimon with this card's inherited effect get +2000 DP if I have 4 Digimon in play?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is an effect that nullifies \"reduce play cost by x\". You and your opponent will be unable to activate effects that reduce play costs, and must pay the play cost written on the cards in order to play them.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's \"can't reduce play costs.\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"play without paying its memory cost\" is not an effect that reduces play costs, so it can activate.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is in play, can \"play without paying its memory cost\" effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the play cost cannot be reduced. Since this card's effect does not target Digimon, it cannot be blocked even if the opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] is in the Breeding Area, so the effect that reduces play cost cannot be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is in play, can the [Your Turn] effect of an opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] reduce the play cost of Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the cost cannot be reduced. Because of this card's effect, effects that reduce the play cost of Tamers cannot be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is present, can an opponent's [BT14-046 Togemon]'s [Your Turn] effect reduce the play cost of a green Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will only gain 1 memory when 2 or more Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in their name are played at the same time.\n",
      "question": "Q: If an effect plays 2 or more Digimon with [Sistermon]\u00a0in their name, will this Digimon gain 1 memory for each Digimon that is played?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon plays a Digimon card with [Sistermon]\u00a0in its name with its [When Attacking] effect, will this Digimon have +3000 DP and \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e during the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is played at the same time as another Digimon. Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is an optional effect so you can choose not to trash 1 card in your hand. In which case, you will not \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible not to activate this card's [On Play]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is treated as \"[Sistermon Ciel] and [Data] Attribute\" because it is a special rule and not an effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in the hand or breeding area. Is this card still treated as \"[Sistermon Ciel] and [Data] Attribute\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card is treated as both [Virus] and [Data], but it is treated as one card number, and it is treated as having three traits in total including [Champion] and [Puppet].\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have four traits, [Champion]/[Puppet]/[Virus], and [Data]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can target different Digimon for each effect, and it can also be the same Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to give the +2000 DP effect and \uff1cPiercing\uff1e effect to different Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the cards that were revealed, this card will be placed in the battle area after trashing the revealed cards.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card does not reveal any cards with [Huckmon]/[Sistermon]\u00a0in its name, or the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait, does this card still place itself in the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: After activating this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect, can I reduce the cost of a digivolution caused by an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if two or more Digimon with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait are played at the same time with one effect, this card's inherited effect will only gain 1 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If 2 or more of my Digimon with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait are played at the same time, does this card's inherited effect gain 1 memory for each Digimon that was played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, in that case, the total memory from both effects will be 2 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If there are Digimon with this card in their digivolution cards. If a Digimon with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait is played. Will each inherited effect be activated and gain a total of 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon that's black or has the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait as its bottom digivolution card\" is a cost, so you can choose not to place it as a digivolution card. If you do, you will not proceed the rest of the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to not activate the [On Play] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is optional to play the Digimon. If you do not play it, add it to your hand liek any other card.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after revealing a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait from the top of the deck. Is it possible to not play the Digimon card with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it cannot be played due to the effect of [BT9-047 Pomumon]'s [All Turns] effect, the card is add it to your hand in the same way as other revealed cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has has [BT9-047 Pomumon] in play, what happens to a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait that was revealed from the deck due to this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon\" is a cost, so you can choose not to place it as a digivolution card. If you do, you will not delete a Digimon with this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to not activate the [On Play] effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, the Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card and another Digimon, can be used to [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   into a Digimon card that has [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   in your hand before it becomes the opponent's turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's [End of Your Turn] effect work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't ignore digivolution conditions, so you can't DNA Digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn't have [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost  .\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn't have [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   in your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't ignore digivolution conditions, so it is not possible to evolve DNA DIgivolve with a Digimon of a colour or level not specified in the [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   conditions.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to evolve DNA Digivolve with a Digimon of a colour or level that is not specified in the [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   conditions of the card in hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is \"you may\", so you can choose not to play the Digimon card. If you do, put it on the bottom of your deck like any other card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to not play a revealed Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait from the deck with the [When Attacking] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it cannot be played due to the effect of [BT9-047 Pomumon]'s [All Turns] effect, the card is returned to the bottom of the deck in the same way as other revealed cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has has [BT9-047 Pomumon] in play, what happens to a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait that was revealed from the deck due to this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works as long as the memory is 1 or more on the opponent's side.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card perform \uff1cBlitz\uff1e when performing a DNA Digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has 8 digivolution cards, does this card's [When Digivolving] effect after DNA Digivolving, delete 2 of my opponent's Digimon both with a play cost of 20 or less, and trash 2 cards from the top of my opponent's security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and \"for every 4 cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards, delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 20 or less and trash the top card of your opponent's security stack.\" are on effect. So if it was DNA Digivolved, you must finish activating the above effects, after declaring an attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, the effects will continue activating. Afterwards, you can activate [When Attacking] effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: When DNA Digivolving into this card and the memory was 1 or more on the other side, and it activates \uff1cBlitz\uff1e. If this Digimon has a [When Attacking] effect. Is it possible to activate the [When Attacking] effect before applying the rest of this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is an effect that nullifies \"reduce play cost by x\". You and your opponent will be unable to activate effects that reduce play costs, and must pay the play cost written on the cards in order to play them.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's \"can't reduce play costs.\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"play without paying its memory cost\" is not an effect that reduces play costs, so it can activate.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is in play, can \"play without paying its memory cost\" effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the play cost cannot be reduced. Since this card's effect does not target Digimon, it cannot be blocked even if the opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] is in the Breeding Area, so the effect that reduces play cost cannot be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is in play, can the [Your Turn] effect of an opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] reduce the play cost of Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the cost cannot be reduced. Because of this card's effect, effects that reduce the play cost of Tamers cannot be activated.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is present, can an opponent's [BT14-046 Togemon]'s [Your Turn] effect reduce the play cost of a green Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon that's black or has the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait as its bottom digivolution card\" is a cost, so you can choose not to place it as a digivolution card. If you do, you will not proceed the rest of the effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to not activate the [On Play] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is optional to play the Digimon. If you do not play it, add it to your hand liek any other card.\n",
      "question": "Q: If after revealing a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait from the top of the deck. Is it possible to not play the Digimon card with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it cannot be played due to the effect of [BT9-047 Pomumon]'s [All Turns] effect, the card is add it to your hand in the same way as other revealed cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has has [BT9-047 Pomumon] in play, what happens to a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait that was revealed from the deck due to this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon\" is a cost, so you can choose not to place it as a digivolution card. If you do, your Digimon will not gain \uff1cReboot\uff1e.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to not activate the [On Play] effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, the Digimon that has this card as a digivolution card and another Digimon, can be used to [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   into a Digimon card that has [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   in your hand before it becomes the opponent's turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's [End of Your Turn] effect work?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't ignore digivolution conditions, so you can't DNA Digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn't have [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost  .\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn't have [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   in your hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't ignore digivolution conditions, so it is not possible to evolve DNA DIgivolve with a Digimon of a colour or level not specified in the [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   conditions.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to evolve DNA Digivolve with a Digimon of a colour or level that is not specified in the [DNA Digivolve] \u00a0: Cost   conditions of the card in hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Card text that specifically specify \"delete,\" such as \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon,\" can't be used to delete this Digimon. They can still be deleted by losing a battle or being reduced to 0 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: What does \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" on this card's [All Turns] effect refer to, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is \"you may\", so you can choose not to play the Digimon card. If you do, put it on the bottom of your deck like any other card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to not play a revealed Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait from the deck with the [When Digivolving] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it cannot be played due to the effect of [BT9-047 Pomumon]'s [All Turns] effect, the card is returned to the bottom of your deck in the same way as other revealed cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has has [BT9-047 Pomumon] in play, what happens to a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait that was revealed from the deck due to this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the timing of this card's inherited effect is [Opponent's Turn], and since the turn has not changed yet at the end of the turn, the inherited  effect of this card is not applied, and the effect of the opponent's [BT9-112 DeathXmon] will not be prevented.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the opponent has [BT9-112 DeathXmon], and it activates its [End of Opponent's Turn] effect. Will the Digimon with this card's inherited [Opponent's Turn] effect be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though the Digimon is unaffected by the effects they have been applied and during your unsuspend phase it is no longer unaffected by your opponent's Digimon effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is underneath a suspended [RagnaLoardmon] and is targeted for the effect of [BT3-057 MegaGargomon], does this card unsuspend during the next unsuspend Phase?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only one Digimon can be deleted with this card. If there are multiple opponents with the highest DP, the player of this card selects the target to be deleted.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Main] effect delete all of the opponent's Digimon with the highest DP?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Main] effect be used when you don't have a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or less and [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait in your hand, so that only the effect of placing this card in the battle area is applied?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must choose whether to return all revealed cards to the top of the deck in any order or all revealed cards to the bottom of the deck in any order.\n",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to separately return the revealed cards to the top and bottom of the deck for this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 4 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card can only digivolve into a Digimon card with the exact name [Beelzemon].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve into [Beelzemon: Blast Mode] with its [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [When Attacking] effect, it digivolves into [Beelzemon]. Can the effect of [EX2-065 Ai & Mako] then digivolve it into [Beelzemon: Blast Mode]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect include this card for the number of cards in trash??"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If there is a target that can be attacked, such as the opponent's suspended Digimon, it will attack that target. If it cannot attack anyone other than the player, it will not be able to attack due to its \"This Digimon cannot attack the player\" effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's \"This Digimon cannot attack the player\" is chosen by \"your opponent attacks with 1 of their Digimon\". What will happen?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. It can only play cards named [Beelzemon].\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect play [Beelzemon: Blast Mode]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 9 or less cards in my trash, and this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates, and i discard 4 cards from my deck. If I now have 10 or more cards in my trash, can I gain 1 memory."
    }
  ],
  "ST14-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this effect of \"when this card is trashed from the deck... For every 10 cards in your trash, add 1 to the maximum level of the Digimon you chose with this effect\" include this card for the number of cards in the trash?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect is \"By suspending this Tamer, return 1 card from your hand to the top of your deck and gain 1 memory.\". However, if you have one or more cards in your hand you must return it to your deck.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] efect activate and gain 1 memory even when I have 0 cards in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since a turn has passed it can be activated.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is trashed from the deck and placed in the Battle Area during my opponent's turn. Can I activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e during my next turn?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack is changed by the block, it will activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card as a digivolution source attacks an opponent player and the opponent blocks, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the attack target of another Digimon (without this card as a digivolution source) is changed?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect does not refer to Digimon in the breeding area.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect work even if there are only Digimon in the opponent's breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack is changed by the block, it will activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card as a digivolution source attacks an opponent player and the opponent blocks, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the attack target of another Digimon (without this card as a digivolution source) is changed?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's effect activates before the opponent blocks, so even if it is blocked after it activates, the effect will not be canceled.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks the opponent player and is blocked by the opponent's Digimon. In this case, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Only Digimon cards with the exact name [Agumon] are eligible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to use this card's effect to play a Digimon with [Agumon]\u00a0in its name, such as [Agumon Expert] or [BushiAgumon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack is changed by the block, it will activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon that has this card as a digivolution source attacks an opponent player and the opponent blocks, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the attack target of a Digimon without this card in its digivolution sources is changed?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate when a different Digimon reduces your Security or the opponent's Security?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since the target of the attack is changed by the block, it will be effective.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon attacks an opponent player and the opponent blocks, will this card's effect be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be blocked. \uff1cBlocker\uff1e is an effect that allows a Digimon to block, and since it's an effect on the opponent's Digimon, it is not affected by your Digimon's \"Not affected by opponent's Digimon effects\" effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon with [Greymon]\u00a0in its name is no longer affected by the effects of my opponent's Digimon due to this card's [Main] effect, can it be blocked by my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It is possible. However, in that case, the attack will not be performed due to the \"This Digimon cannot attack\" effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [Main] effect, can I select an opponent's Digimon with a \"This Digimon cannot attack\" effect as the target for the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] This Digimon attacks.\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the start of your opponent's main phase, the two effects given by this card's effect will be triggered simultaneously, and your opponent will decide which one to activate first. After [When Attacking] and such effects are activated, the second pending [Start of Your Main Phase] effect will be activated before [Reaction]/[Counter] timing, but since the first Digimon is already attacking, the second Digimon cannot attack and the effect will end immediately. As a result, only the opponent's Digimon that activated its effect first will attack. (See more in Attack Resolution and Attack Resolution/Old.)\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if you use this card twice to give two opponent's Digimon the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, when it becomes your opponent's turn, the opponent's Digimon's \"This Digimon is unaffected by opponent's effects\" effect will be lost, so at the start of the main phase it must attack due to the effect given by this card.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [Main] effect, can I target an opponent's Digimon with the effect \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon is unaffected by opponent's effects\" to give it \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\"?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect does not refer to Digimon in the breeding area.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect work even if there are only Digimon in the opponent's breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't work. This card's effect only activates when it declares an attack targeting an opponent's Digimon.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks the opponent player and is blocked by an opponent's Digimon. In this case, does this Digimon's effect work?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Only Digimon cards with the exact name [Gabumon] are eligible.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to use this card's effect to play a Digimon with [Gabumon]\u00a0in its name, such as [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] or [Gabumon (X Antibody)]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the conditions are met when this card is activated, the effect will continue until the end of the opponent's turn, even if the Digimon name does not include \"Garurumon\".\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [Main] effect, I give one of my Digimon with [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name the effect of \"[On Deletion] Play this card without paying its cost.\" After that, if the target Digimon digivolves or \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1es into a Digimon that doesn't have [Garurumon]\u00a0in its name, what will happen to the given effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It only exists when comparing the DP between two Digimon for a battle. It is not applied during the resolution \"End of battle\" or \"On Deletion\" effects that activated from that same battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: How long does the DP effect [ST2-01 Tsunomon] last?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The 1000 DP only exists when comparing the DP between Digimon for a battle. It is not applied during \"when X attacks\" effects.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack with [BT5-111 Omnimon X-Anti-body] that has this card as a digivolution card against a 16000 DP Digimon with no sources. Can I use its effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect does nothing to your opponent's Digimon if they have no digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect be used to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect does nothing to your opponent's Digimon if they have no digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect be used to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply even if my opponent only has 1 Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Once that Digimon has no digivolution cards left, this card's inherited effect activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon has this card as a digivolution card and attacks one of my opponent's Digimon that has 1 digivolution card. If this Digimon has another [When Attacking] effect that activates and trashes that digivolution card, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Your opponent has to have a Digimon in their battle area for it to activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect does nothing to your opponent's Digimon if they have no digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect be used to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. In that case, it would only trash that 1 digivolution card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect be used on an opponent's Digimon that has only 1 digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only unsuspends itself once per turn. In other words, it only unsuspends the first time it attacks each turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon unsuspend itself each time it attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can use the effect again during your next turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon's effect only activate once per game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After you declare your attack, suspend the Digimon, then declare your attack target. When performing your security check or resolving a battle with your opponent's Digimon, this Digimon will already be unsuspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: At what timing does this Digimon unsuspend itself?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You only gain 1 memory no matter how many Digimon your opponent has without digivolution cards.\n",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 1 memory for each Digimon my opponent has without digivolution cards? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this Tamer's effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Your opponent has to have a Digimon in their battle area for it to activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this Tamer's effect apply when my opponent has no Digimon in their battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect of each copy activates, causing you to gain 2 memory.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have two of this Tamer in play and my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards, do I gain 2 memory from this Tamer's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. However, this only happens after any attacks resolve. If there are any  effects or attacks that have not resolved, those must resolve before it becomes your turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the security effect of this card causes the memory counter to move to 1 or higher on my side, does my opponent's turn end?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: If one of my opponent's Digimon has this card's effect used on it and is suspended, can I attack that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can only be used to target cards that meet its requirements upon activation. So the effect would still apply, and even though the target Digimon has gained digivolution cards, it still can't attack or block.\n",
      "question": "Q: If one of my opponent's Digimon has this card's effect used on it and it digivolves and now has 1 or more digivolution cards, how does this card's effect resolve?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Level 2 Digimon can't be in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the effect of this Option card to play a level 2 Digimon that is currently a digivolution card of one of my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it is played as another Digimon, it is played unsuspended.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I use this Option card's effect to play a digivolution card of one of my suspended Digimon, does it come into play suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it is played as another Digimon, it is not affected by any effects of the original Digimon it was under.\n",
      "question": "Q: If one of my Digimon has an effect applied to it that lasts a turn, then I use the effect of this Option card to play one of its digivolution cards as a Digimon, does that Digimon come into play with the same effect applied to it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since it would count as the turn they were played.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can Digimon played by this card's effect attack the turn they were played?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Since it meets the activation conditions, they all activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the DP of an opponent's Digimon is reduced to 0 and deleted, if I have multiple Digimon with this Digimon as digivolution cards, do all of their effects activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Since it meets the activation conditions, they all activate.\n",
      "question": "Q: If the DP of an opponent's Digimon is reduced to 0 and deleted, if I have multiple Digimon with this Digimon as digivolution cards, do all of their effects activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have 4 or more cards in your security stack, you gain 1 memory. But you can only gain 1 memory from this effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: On attack, if I have 8 cards in my security stack, does this card's inherited effect cause me to gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 1000 DP or less and delete it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You do not enter battle, then once any other [When Attacking] and [Reaction] effects resolve, the attack ends. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as a digivolution card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then that Digimon's DP is reduced to 0 and deleted by this card's inherited effect. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When Attacking effects resolve before block declaration, so you can't activate the inherited effect after a blocker has been declared.\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as a digivolution card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then the opponent blocks with a Digimon that has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's inherited effect to reduce the DP of the blocking Digimon to 0 and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. This effect behaves the same way as an effect that reads \"If you have 3 or fewer security cards\", so the condition is checked when the effect would be activated.\n",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve into this card while I have 4 or more security cards. While this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect is pending activation, one of my other effects reduces my security cards to 3 or fewer. Do I?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less, reduce its DP to 0, and delete it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You do not enter battle, then once any other [When Attacking] and [Reaction]/[Counter] effects resolve, the attack ends.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then that Digimon's DP is reduced to 0 and deleted by this card's effect. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [When Attacking] effects resolve before block declaration, so you can't activate the [When Attacking] effect after a blocker has been declared.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then my opponent blocks with a Digimon that has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the DP of the blocking Digimon to 0 and delete it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Rosemon's condition of \"If this Digimon is at rest\" is no longer fulfilled, so Rosemon cannot rest your other Digimon.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: I play [ST3-16 Seven Heavens] to give -10,000 DP to the opponent's rested Rosemon. Then my [ST3-11 Seraphimon] attacks player. Both Seraphimon and Rosemon skills trigger at the same time [When Attacking] Seraphimon -4000 DP to Rosemon, killing it. Can Rosemon still rest an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this Tamer stack if there are multiple copies in play in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It doesn't affect normal Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this Tamer's effect only affect Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do.\n",
      "question": "Q: If there are two copies of this card in my security stack, and both copies are activated in the same turn, do their effects stack?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 2000 DP or less, reduce its DP to 0, and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: That Digimon can't perform security checks, so the battle ends. Even if your opponent has no cards in their security stack, you would not win the game by attacking with that Digimon.\n",
      "question": "Q: What happens when a Digimon has a security check number of 0 because of this card's effect and it attacks a player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It would still check 0 cards. In order to check 1 or more security cards, that Digimon would need to gain \uff1cSecurity Attack +3\uff1e or higher.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect causes a Digimon to gain \uff1cSecurity Attack -3\uff1e, giving them a security check number of 0. How many security cards could that Digimon check if it gained edned \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 10000 DP or less, reduce its DP to 0, and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared an attack against your opponent, this card's effect doesn't activate, even if they use another Digimon to block it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you declared an attack against an opponent's Digimon, this effect activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and use another effect to delete an opponent's Digimon card. Does this card's effect activate? "
    }
  ],
  "ST4-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared an attack against your opponent, this card's effect doesn't activate, even if they use another Digimon to block it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you declared an attack against an opponent's Digimon, this effect activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and use another effect to delete an opponent's Digimon card. Does this card's effect activate? "
    }
  ],
  "ST4-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if your memory counter moves to 1 on your opponent's side due to this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, your turn doesn't end until the attack does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack if I have less than 2 memory? "
    }
  ],
  "ST4-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Security] effects only activate when flipped over from the security stack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's inherited effect to trash an opponent's Security Card. Does the security effect on that card activate? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only trashes the top card of your opponent's security stack. It doesn't win you the game if it's empty.\n",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has an empty security stack. If I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and I use it to attack and delete an opponent's Digimon and survive, do I win the game? "
    }
  ],
  "ST4-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect simply prevents the Digimon from attacking or blocking. You can still attack it.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon. Can I attack that Digimon if it's suspended? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect persists, even if they digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, can it attack and block again? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect preventing it from attacking takes priority. Your opponent's Digimon still can't attack.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon. If that Digimon activates an effect that allows it to attack other Digimon or players, what happens? "
    }
  ],
  "ST4-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when my opponent uses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend one of their Digimon? "
    }
  ],
  "ST5-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if your opponent didn't have a Digimon in play for their entire turn? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if you activate effects to prevent all of your opponent's Digimon from attacking? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not because your opponent still declared an attack this turn.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activates if you ended an attack with [BT5-111 Omnimon X-Anti-body]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if your opponent didn't have a Digimon in play for their entire turn? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if you use effects to prevent your opponent's Digimon from attacking? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. They attacked this turn, so the effect doesn't apply.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if your opponent's Digimon were all deleted in battle after attacking? "
    }
  ],
  "ST5-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if your memory counter moves to 1 on your opponent's side due to this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, your turn doesn't end until the attack does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack if I have less than 2 memory? "
    }
  ],
  "ST5-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give this Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon retain effects when digivolving or dedigivolving, so \uff1cBlocker\uff1e remains.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to give a Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, what happens to \uff1cBlocker\uff1e? "
    }
  ],
  "ST5-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give this Digimon \uff1cReboot\uff1e? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon retain effects when digivolving or dedigivolving, so \uff1cReboot\uff1e remains.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to give a Digimon \uff1cReboot\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, what happens to \uff1cReboot\uff1e? "
    }
  ],
  "ST5-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to unsuspend a Digimon that didn't suspend itself by activating \uff1cBlocker\uff1e? "
    }
  ],
  "ST6-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't lose the game when your deck is empty. You will lose the game if your deck has 0 cards in it at your next draw phase, however.\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card's effect reduces the number of cards in my deck to 0, do I lose the game? "
    }
  ],
  "ST6-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if your memory counter moves to 1 on your opponent's side due to this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, your turn doesn't end until the attack does.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack if I have less than 2 memory? "
    }
  ],
  "ST6-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q:  Can I use this card's effect to give this Digimon \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon retain effects when digivolving or dedigivolving, so \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e remains.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to give a Digimon \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, what happens to \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e? "
    }
  ],
  "ST6-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e to trash a purple level 3 Digimon card in the Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e's digivolution cards. Can I immediately use the \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect to play that Digimon without paying its memory cost? "
    }
  ],
  "ST6-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must fully activate this card's effect, then activate the [On Deletion] effect.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to delete one of my Digimon with a [On Deletion] effect. Can I activate the [On Deletion] effect before this card's \"delete 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon\" effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They trigger at the same time, which means the turn player resolves their effect first.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to delete one of my own Digimon, and an opponent's Digimon. If they both have [On Deletion] effects, which\neffect resolves first?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you only have a level 3 or level 4 purple Digimon card in your trash, you can play it.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect if I only have either a level 3 or level 4 purple Digimon card in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have both a level 3 and a level 4 in the trash, you must play both of them or none at all. If you have only one of them, you can play just that one.\n",
      "question": "Q: If I have both a level 3 and a level 4 in the trash, can I choose to play only one of them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you only trigger that effect once.\n",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [Main] effect to play 2 Digimon. Do I get to trigger \"When you play a Digimon\" twice?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect was activated before your opponent blocked it. (See more in Attack Resolution)\n",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Your Digimon is placed in your trash before the effect can activate. It\u2019s no longer in your battle area, so it doesn\u2019t activate.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and an opponent\u2019s Digimon are deleted simultaneously. Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon, can I activate [P-103 Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve this Digimon into a [Gallantmon] in hand, reducing its cost to 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[3]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon and I activate an effect that evolves one of my Digimon, can I evolve this Digimon into [Gallantmon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Before you can activate the effect this card is moved to the trash and is no longer in the battle area, so you cannot activate the effect\n",
      "question": "Q: If your Digimon with this card as a source and an opponent\u2019s Digimon are deleted at the same time, can you activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. At the point this Digimon is played via this effect it is considered to be a standard Digimon\n",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is played due to its [Security] effect is it counted as a Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The outcome of the battle doesn\u2019t matter, at the end of the battle the Digimon is Played\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is Security Checked and deleted in battle does is it still Played via its [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is Played prior to the next Security Check. The [On Play] ability also activates as soon as the Digimon is Played, prior to the next Security Check\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is Security checked and battled, if the attacking Digimon has further security checks to make, does this Digimon get Played or do those Checks occur first? Furthermore, what is the timing for the activation of this card\u2019s [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You may delete the attacking Digimon\n",
      "question": "Q: This card is played via its [Security] effect. The attacking Digimon has DP4000 or less but has <Jamming>. Can you use this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect to delete the attacking Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It does\n",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as a source and the \uff1cPiercing\uff1e effect attacks an opposing Digimon and only the opposing Digimon is deleted. Does the inherited effect of this card grant the attacking Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e for the ensuing Security Checks granted by \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This refers to a situation in which there are no opposing Digimon that can be deleted by this Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, such as if your opponent does not have a Digimon with DP 4000 or less or if they only have Digimon that cannot be deleted by effect\n",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [When Attacking] ability reads, \u2018Delete an opponent\u2019s Digimon with DP4000 or less. If an opponent\u2019s Digimon is not deleted by this effect,\u2019 What does this mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect is activated and there is an opposing Digimon with DP 4000 or less you must target that Digimon. If there is an appropriate target for the effect you may not choose to not target it.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with DP 4000 or less, can I choose not to delete that Digimon to give this Digimon DP +3000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You may choose any opposing Digimon with DP 4000 or less. You may deliberately choose a Digimon that cannot be deleted by opponent\u2019s effects to force the deletion to fail.\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has two Digimon with DP 4000 or less, one which cannot be deleted by opponent\u2019s effects and one that can, can I target the Digimon that cannot be deleted by opponent\u2019s effects, fail to delete it, and then give this Digimon DP +3000?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. So long as your number of Security Cards remaining is equal or fewer than your opponent\u2019s at the time of Use, you don\u2019t lose the effect even if your opponent\u2019s Security decreases later\n",
      "question": "Q: Upon using this card you and your opponent have the same number of Security Cards remaining, but then later in the turn your opponent\u2019s number of Security Cards decrease, leaving you with more. Does the \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e granted by this card disappear at that time?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Choose any number of your opponent\u2019s Digimon so that the total DP of those Digimon adds up to 8000 or less, such as a DP 3000 Digimon and a DP 5000 Digimon, or two DP 2000 Digimon and a DP 3000 Digimon, and then activate the effect on those Digimon\n",
      "question": "Q: The card reads, 'Choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 8000 or less'. What does that actually mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You are free to choose so long as the total DP is 8000 or less. However, you must choose at least 1 Digimon if your opponent has any Digimon with DP 8000 or less\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I deliberately choose fewer targets so that the total DP is less than 8000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Your opponent\u2019s Digimon\u2019s DP will only be reduced after Golemon is Deleted when this card\u2019s effect has finished activating. You may not choose an additional target at that point\n",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT4-066 Golemon] and I include Golemon as one of the targeted Digimon my opponent\u2019s other Digimon\u2019s DP will be reduced by 1000 when Golemon is Deleted. Can I include that loss of DP in my calculations when selecting Digimon to target?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s [Main] effect be stacked with \"Add 1000 to the maximum DP you can choose with DP-based deletion effects\" to make it able to delete a Digimon with 11000 DP or lower?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The inherited effect activates the moment you have 8 cards in hand, even mid Attack, giving the attacking Digimon DP +1000\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in hand and attack with a Digimon that has this card as a source, activating that Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] ability to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Now that I have 8 cards in hand does the inherited effect from this card give the attacking Digimon DP +1000 for the ensuing Check or Battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30c1\u30d3\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Vee\" (\u30d6\u30a4) in its name.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Vee]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The inherited effect becomes active the moment you have 8 cards in hand, even mid-atttack. Giving the attacking Digimon +1000 DP.\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in hand and attack with a Digimon that has this card as a source, activating that Digimon's [When Attacking] ability to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Now that I have 8 cards in hand does the inherited effect from this card give the attacking Digimon DP+1000 for the ensuing check or battle?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon, can I activate [P-104 Mental Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve this Digimon into an [UlforceVeedramon] in hand, reducing its cost to 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon and I activate an effect that evolves one of my Digimon, can I evolve this Digimon into [UlforceVeedramon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. So long as you choose to Activate this card\u2019s inherited effect after the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e you will have 8 cards in hand when this effect is activated allowing you to return an opponent\u2019s Digimon to their hand\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in hand and attack with a Digimon that has this card as a source, activating that Digimon\u2019s other [When Attacking] ability to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Now that I have 8 cards in hand can I use this card\u2019s inherited ability to return one of my opponent\u2019s Lv. 3 Digimon to their hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The outcome of the battle doesn\u2019t matter, at the end of the battle the Digimon is Played\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is Security Checked and deleted in battle does is it still Played via its [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect activates\n",
      "question": "Q: If this card is Played via its [Security] does its [On Play] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is Played prior to the next Security Check. The [On Play] ability also activates as soon as the Digimon is Played, prior to the next Security Check\n",
      "question": "Q: When this card is Security checked and battled, if the attacking Digimon has further security checks to make, does this Digimon get Played or do those Checks occur first? Furthermore, what is the timing for the activation of this card\u2019s [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The inherited effect activates the moment you have 8 cards in hand, even mid Attack, giving the attacking Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in hand and attack with a Digimon that has this card as a source, activating that Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] ability to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Now that I have 8 cards in hand does the inherited effect from this card give the attacking Digimon \uff1cSecurity Attack +1\uff1e for the ensuing Check?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: In response to this Digimon attack, an opponent\u2019s Digimon cannot redirect this Digimon's attack when activating the \uff1cBlocker\uff1e effect.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card reads, \u2018This Digimon is unblockable.\u2019 What exactly does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon can still be suspended but the attack will not be redirected.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent still suspend their Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. So long as you choose to Activate this card\u2019s inherited effect after the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e you will have 8 cards in hand when this effect is activated allowing you to Unsuspend this Digimon\n",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in hand and attack this Digimon, activating this Digimon\u2019s other [When Attacking] ability to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Now that I have 8 cards in hand can I use this card\u2019s [When Attacking] ability to Unsuspend this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards is blue.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards is a blue Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it says to \"Reveal\", you must reveal the top 3 cards from your deck if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: Must I reveal the top 3 cards of my deck for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, at it says to \u201cAdd to your hand\u201d, you must add a revealed card that fulfils the condition to your hand if you are able to.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Play] effect, if I revealed a digimon card with the [Free]\u00a0trait, must I add it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card is Green.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card is a Green Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is an effect that can only activate if you DNA Digivolve.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, does it not activate if I don't DNA digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you have both digivolution cards, you must play both of them, or not play any of them. If you do not have both, you may play as much as you can.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if I have both a level 4 or lower blue Digimon card and a green Digimon card in its digivolution cards, must I play both Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to play the Blue-Green Digimon as the Blue Digimon so that no other Green Digimon can be played.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if the only level 4 or lower digivolution cards this Digimon has are a Blue-Green level 3 Digimon and a Blue level 3 Digimon, can I choose to only play 1 of them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to play the Blue-Green Digimon as the Green Digimon so that no other Blue Digimon can be played.\n[2]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if the only level 4 or lower digivolution cards this Digimon has are a Blue-Green level 3 Digimon and a Green level 3 Digimon, can I choose to only play 1 of them?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [When Attacking] effects activate before \uff1cBlocker\uff1e is activated/performed in [Reaction]/[Counter] timing, so it loses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e before it is able to block.\n[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon attacks and deletes my blue Digimon with its [When Attacking] effect, leaving me with no other blue Digimon in play, can I still use this card's effect to block?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card, and 1 of your other Digimon, can DNA digivolve into a Digimon in your hand that can <DNA Digivolve>, before the turn is passed to your opponent.\n",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that cannot <DNA Digivolve>.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that cannot <DNA Digivolve>?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as digivolution requirements cannot be ignored. You cannot DNA digivolve your Digimon that is not the correct colour or level specified by the card that can <DNA Digivolve>.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve my Digimon in play that is not the colour and level specified by the card that can <DNA Digivolve> in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon from DNA Digivolve is treated as a new Digimon so the old DIgimon is no longer in the battle area.\n",
      "question": "Q: This card's [End of Your Turn] effect has triggered, and the Digimon it is underneath is used as part of a DNA Digivolve. Can I still activate this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card is blue.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution card is a blue Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is played at the end of battle regardless of the outcome of that battle.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Security] effect, if it lost the battle against the attacking Digimon, can I still play it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect activate even if it is played by the effects of this card's [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As this Digimon is to be played at the end of the battle with the attacking Digimon, it is played before the next check happens. Its [On Play] effect also activates befeore the next check.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [Security] effect, if at the end of the battle which this card was checked, the attacking Digimon still has remaining checks not done, does this card's [Security] effect activate first or does the next check happens first?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The first part \"suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon\" activates even if you don't DNA Digivolve. The latter part \"That Digimon is not unsuspended in your opponent's next unsuspend phase\" can only activate if you DNA Digivolved.\n",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, does it not activate if I don't DNA Digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this inherited effect only counts the colour of the topmost card. If it is a single-coloured card, it is counted as 1 colour even if there are cards of other colours in the digivolution card.\n",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also count the colours of cards in digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend a Digimon, but return a different Digimon that was already suspended to my opponent's hand with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.\n",
      "question": "Q: Can I give +2000 DP to a Digimon, but give \uff1cPiercing\uff1e to a different Digimon with this card's effect?"
    }
  ]
}